[
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nAfter the Corp installs a card for the first time in a turn, who decides first?\n\n* (A) Does the Runner decide to use the ability, forcing the Corp to pay 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> or expose the card, or\n* (B) Does the Corp decide whether or not to pay 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>, allowing the Runner to choose whether or not the card should be exposed?",
    "answer": "A. The Runner chooses to use the ability, then the Corp chooses whether or not to pay the 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "419_amoral_scammer",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Aaron Marrón when they have no tags? How about if the stack is empty?",
    "answer": "As long as either a tag would be removed or a card would be drawn, the ability has the potential to change the game state and thus can be used. If both the stack is empty and the Runner has no tags, then Aaron Marrón cannot possibly change the game state and thus cannot be used.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aaron_marron",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner prevent Acacia from being trashed and still gain the credits?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "acacia",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Looking at the top 3 cards of R&D does not remove the cards\nfrom R&D. The cards are still in R&D and able to be affected by\noperations played with Accelerated Diagnostics. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "accelerated_diagnostics",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Each operation the Corp looks at can be played in any order. The\nCorp does not have to play the topmost operation first. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "accelerated_diagnostics",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "When the Corp plays an operation, they fully resolve it before\nplaying another one or trashing the rest of the cards. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "accelerated_diagnostics",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If any of the 3 cards looked at are no longer in the top 3 positions\nof R&D (as determined when Accelerated Diagnostics was played),\nthen those cards cannot be played. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "accelerated_diagnostics",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp can only play and look at the top 3 cards (as determined\nwhen Accelerated Diagnostic was played). Even if other cards are\nmoved into the top 3, those cards are not eligible to be played/\nlooked at by the Accelerated Diagnostics. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "accelerated_diagnostics",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If one of the operations played shuffles R&D, the remainder of\nAccelerated Diagnostics’ effect is ignored. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "accelerated_diagnostics",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can choose to not use the ability on Account Siphon\nwhen accessing cards, and if so does not take any tags. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "account_siphon",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner ends up running successfully on another server\nthan HQ, the “If successful...” effect on Account Siphon cannot be\ntriggered. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "account_siphon",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the additional tag from Acme Consulting be removed?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner is considered to have an additional tag during encounters with outermost ice, even when they have none, but it does not exist for the purposes of being manipulated (such as removing it).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "acme_consulting_the_truth_you_need",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp must both install and rez any advertisements chosen by\nAd Blitz. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "ad_blitz",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen does the Runner need to decide which 3 directives Adam starts the game with?",
    "answer": "The Runner chooses which 3 directives Adam uses after IDs are revealed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "adam_compulsive_hacker",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen can the Runner use the ability gained by Adjusted Matrix?",
    "answer": "The Runner can use this ability if the host icebreaker meets the strength of the encountered ice. Treat the card as if it said “Host icebreaker gains **AI** and \"You may spend <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> to break any subroutine on a piece of ice currently being encountered.\"",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "adjusted_matrix",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 19](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Sovereign_Sight_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\n**Updated** If the Runner uses [Salsette Slums](/en/card/10059) to remove an accessed card from the game, does Aeneas Informant trigger?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner accessed a card and did not trash it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aeneas_informant",
    "update_date": "2018-02-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 15](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Earth's_Scion_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Aeneas Informant when accessing a rezzed card?",
    "answer": "Yes. Revealing the card is part of the effect and not a condition for using the ability.\n\nIf the Runner has both [Maw](/en/card/12002) and Aeneas Informant installed, what happens if the first card accessed is not trashed or stolen? What if the card trashed by Maw is that already accessed card?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aeneas_informant",
    "update_date": "2018-02-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can [Aesop’s Pawnshop](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31035) be used multiple times in a turn to trash multiple cards?",
    "answer": "No, there is only one opportunity for ‘when your turn begins’ effects to meet their trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aesops_pawnshop",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if Afshar is protecting HQ and gains additional subroutines?",
    "answer": "The additional subroutines can be broken normally. Afshar’s ability only affects its printed subroutines.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "afshar",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Pelangi to make a piece of ice a sentry and then bypass it with Afterimage?",
    "answer": "No. Pelangi can only add subtypes to ice during the paid ability window of an encounter, and Afterimage meets its trigger condition when an encounter begins. There is no opportunity to use Pelangi in time to trigger Afterimage's bypass ability for that same encounter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "afterimage",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Aggressive Negotiation can be played if the Corp scores an agenda\nduring step 1.1 of their draw phase. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "aggressive_negotiation",
    "update_date": "2017-04-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The programs are trashed at the same time. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "aggressive_secretary",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corporation cannot choose to trash the same program more\nthan once. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "aggressive_secretary",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes [Reina Roja's](/en/card/04041) ability allow a newly rezzed piece of ice with a printed rez cost of 4 to be broken by Aghora?",
    "answer": "No. Reina's ability only lasts for the duration in which the Corp is paying to rez the ice.\n\nCan the Runner use Aghora to swap in another copy of Aghora from the grip?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aghora",
    "update_date": "2022-01-04",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp uses [AgInfusion](/en/card/12052) to redirect the Runner to a different server, what happens if the outermost ice protecting the new server is unrezzed?",
    "answer": "If the outermost piece of ice is unrezzed, the Runner passes it and proceeds as normal for a run on the new server. There is no opportunity to rez the ice because the approach phase is skipped.\n \nIf the Corp uses [AgInfusion](/en/card/12052) to redirect the Runner to a different server with a rezzed piece of ice, can the Runner jack out before encountering that ice?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aginfusion_new_miracles_for_a_new_world",
    "update_date": "2022-12-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Corp uses [AgInfusion](/en/card/12052)'s ability, does it close the paid ability window? Can the runner use paid abilities before encountering the outermost ice on the server they are redirected to?",
    "answer": "[AgInfusion](/en/card/12052)'s ability does close the paid ability window. The Runner does not have the opportunity to use paid abilities before the encounter with the outermost ice protecting the new server begins.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aginfusion_new_miracles_for_a_new_world",
    "update_date": "2022-12-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses [AgInfusion](/en/card/12052) to redirect the Runner to a different server, what happens if there is no ice protecting the new server? Can the Runner jack out?",
    "answer": "The runner moves to the Movement Phase, 6.9.4. The runner can jack out before approaching the server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aginfusion_new_miracles_for_a_new_world",
    "update_date": "2022-12-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if Akhet has 3 or more hosted advancement tokens and gains additional subroutines?",
    "answer": "The additional subroutines can be broken normally. Akhet's ability only affects its printed subroutines.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "akhet",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses Algernon to gain <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span>, but then uses [Dr. Lovegood](/en/card/09042) to blank Algernon, is it still trashed at the end of the turn if the Runner doesn't make a successful run?",
    "answer": "Yes. Once triggered, Algernon's ability exists independently of the source card, so the second part of its ability will still trigger when the turn ends.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.05).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "algernon",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Algo Trading start getting 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> from the bank on the second or third turn after it is installed?",
    "answer": "Algo Trading’s second ability can start putting 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> on it the second turn after it is installed. Both abilities meet their trigger condition at the same time each turn, so the Runner can choose the order in which they trigger. The second ability does not check how many credits are on Algo Trading until it resolves, so if the Runner chooses to trigger the first ability before the second ability and this brings the number of credits on it up to 6, then the second ability will be able to resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "algo_trading",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen Alice Merchant makes a successful run on Archives, does the Corp trash a card from HQ before or after the Runner accesses cards?",
    "answer": "Before.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "alice_merchant_clan_agitator",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Allele Repression can add itself to HQ as part of the resolution of its\neffect. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "allele_repression",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Programs that make a run, such as Sneakdoor Beta, Keyhole, etc., **do\nnot** fulfill the requirement to make a run on Always Be Running. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "always_be_running",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the last ice you encountered during the first run of Always Have a Backup Plan is swapped to a different server, uninstalled, or derezzed, what happens during the second run?",
    "answer": "In either case, the Runner does not encounter that piece of ice, and thus no ice is bypassed.\n\nIf the first run with Always Have a Backup Plan is deflected to a new server, which server does the Runner run the second time?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "always_have_a_backup_plan",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp scores Medical Breakthrough, what is the base trace strength for Amani Senai?",
    "answer": "Medical Breakthrough’s ability is active before Amani Senai’s ability resolves, so if it’s the first copy of Medical Breakthrough to be scored or stolen, the base trace strength will be 3. Each additional copy in a player’s score area would lower the base trace strength by another 1.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "amani_senai",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Political Operative](/en/card/10043) to trash [AMAZE Amusements](/en/card/30058), does its ability remain active?",
    "answer": "No. The ability only persists if the Runner trashes [AMAZE Amusements](/en/card/30058) while accessing it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "amaze_amusements",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner accesses and trashes an unrezzed [AMAZE Amusements](/en/card/30058), does its ability apply?",
    "answer": "No. The persistent flag only indicates that an active ability can remain active beyond its source card. The ability must be active to begin with in order for it to persist.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "amaze_amusements",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner bypasses Anansi with an encounter bypass ability (e.g. [Inside Job](/en/card/20023)), does Anansi still do 3 net damage?",
    "answer": "Yes. Bypassing causes the encounter to end immediately, which is the trigger condition for Anansi's ability.\n\nCan the Runner use [Hunting Grounds](/en/card/09035) to prevent Anansi's ability?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "anansi",
    "update_date": "2020-01-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "When the Runner mulligans with Andromeda, they draw\nanother starting hand of 9 cards. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "andromeda_dispossessed_ristie",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses a card ability to rez [Anemone](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33043) at a time other than while the Runner is approaching it, will they be able to use its ability?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as there is a run in progress and [Anemone](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33043) is protecting the attacked server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "anemone",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan Aniccam cause the Runner to draw a card after playing an event?",
    "answer": "Yes, unless the event removes itself from the game or otherwise does not follow normal procedure. Normally, events are trashed after resolving.\n\nCan Aniccam cause the Runner to draw a card after an event is hit by damage?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aniccam",
    "update_date": "2020-03-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If you play [Networking](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31020) and choose to add it to your grip, do you draw 1 card with [Aniccam](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/26084)?",
    "answer": "No, [Networking](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31020) adding itself to HQ prevents the default trashing of a resolved event.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aniccam",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf Ankusa breaks all the subroutines on [Paper Wall](/en/card/04059), what happens?",
    "answer": "If it is the Runner's turn, then Paper Wall is returned to HQ and is not trashed. If it is the Corp's turn, then Paper Wall is trashed and is not returned to HQ.\n\nIf Ankusa breaks all subroutines on a piece of ice during a [Knifed](/en/card/07038) run, what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ankusa",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the Corp’s last chance to rez [Anoetic Void](/en/card/30050) for its ability to apply to a run?",
    "answer": "The Runner has an opportunity to jack out after passing the last piece of ice protecting the server. The “last chance” you are looking for is the paid ability window just after this (step 4e).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "anoetic_void",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Anoetic Void](/en/card/30050) is installed in the root of HQ, can it be one of the cards trashed from HQ for its ability?",
    "answer": "No. “Cards from HQ” only refers to cards in the Corp’s hand. Upgrades installed in the root of a central server are not “in” that server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "anoetic_void",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp installs a piece of ice with the second subroutine on [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) and trashes [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) as part of the installation process, what happens?",
    "answer": "If the Corp trashes [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) this way, they finish resolving the install instruction, then the encounter ends and the Runner passes [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038)’s former position. The third subroutine on [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) will not have the opportunity to resolve, because it is no longer active.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ansel_1_0",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp installs a piece of ice with the second subroutine on [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038), can they force the Runner to approach the new ice by trashing [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) and/or other ice protecting the attacked server as part of that install?",
    "answer": "No. The new ice must be installed in the outermost position protecting the server. Since the Runner already has a position relative to the other ice protecting the server, the new ice will necessarily have a position outward from the Runner. Trashing multiple ice does not allow new ice to “leapfrog” the Runner’s position, but just moves the Runner 1 position toward the server for each trashed piece of ice that was inward from their earlier position.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ansel_1_0",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Carnivore](/en/card/30003) if the last subroutine on [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) resolved earlier in the run?",
    "answer": "No. That subroutine prohibits the Runner from trashing cards they access in any way, not just by using the basic trash ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ansel_1_0",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "When encountering an Archangel during access, the Runner follows\ntiming step 3 of a run, ignoring the portions about approaching ice/\nthe server. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "archangel",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Archangel is encountered while accessed and it is moved from\nits position as determined when accessed (e.g., from R&D being\nshuffled during the encounter or from Archangel being trashed from\nHQ by [Utopia Shard](/en/card/06100) during the encounter), then the encounter\nimmediately ends and any currently open paid ability windows\nclose. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "archangel",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Archangel is not considered to be rezzed during its encounter, and\ncards that interact with rezzed cards, e.g., [Datasucker](/en/card/01008), cannot affect\nit. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "archangel",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Send a Message](/en/card/30069)’s ability to rez an [Archer](/en/card/31075) without forfeiting an agenda?",
    "answer": "Yes. “Ignoring all costs” in [Send a Message](/en/card/30069)’s ability refers to both the rez cost of the ice and any additional costs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "archer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Corp has a scored [Braintrust](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/20094) with 1 agenda counter, and forfeits it to rez [Archer](), how much does the Corp pay for rezzing [Archer](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31075)?",
    "answer": "It costs 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> plus the forfeit of [Braintrust](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/20094). The decision of what you use to pay is made upfront and then the cost is paid simultaneously. The [Braintrust](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/20094) ability applies while deciding what to pay for the cost.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "archer",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "architect",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens to the cards the Corp looked at but did not install when resolving Architect Deployment Test’s ability?",
    "answer": "They remain in R&D in the same order they were found.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "architect_deployment_test",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp name a card that is not in the heap when playing Ark Lockdown?",
    "answer": "Yes. Abilities are only checked for their potential to change the game state to determine whether those abilities can be triggered. Once an ability begins resolving, it does not have to change the game state.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ark_lockdown",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Corp scores Armed Intimidation, can the Runner choose either of the options then prevent/avoid the damage/tags?",
    "answer": "Yes. The ability forces the Runner to choose one of the options, but once an option has been chosen, the resolution can still be modified or prevented.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "armed_intimidation",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use more than one Armored Servers during a run?",
    "answer": "Yes. Both add an additional cost to jacking out or breaking subroutines, so the Runner would have to trash 2 cards from their grip whenever they wish to do one of those two things.\n\nIf the Runner wants use an ability that breaks multiple subroutines, must they trash a card from their grip for each subroutine that ability would break?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "armored_servers",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Corp scores [Artificial Cryptocrash](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33049) when the Runner has fewer than 7<span class=\"icon icon-credit\">?",
    "answer": "The Runner loses all of their credits.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "artificial_cryptocrash",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Runner use Artist Colony to search for a card they are unable to install (either because it’s an Event or because they can’t afford the install cost)?",
    "answer": "Yes because Artist Colony does not restrict which card can be searched for. If the Runner cannot install the card, though, it will just get shuffled back into the stack.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "artist_colony",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner has 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when the trace on [Virgo](/en/card/06109) is successful, can the Runner avoid the tag with [New Angeles City Hall](/en/card/02109) before losing 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> to Aryabhata Tech?",
    "answer": "Yes. The “if successful” effects of a trace are constant effects, so they always resolve before any abilities triggered by the successful trace.\n\nIf the Runner has 4<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when the trace on Virgo is successful and boosted to at least trace strength 5, can the Runner avoid both tags with New Angeles City Hall before losing 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> to Aryabhata Tech?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aryabhata_tech",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan [Apex: Invasive Predator](/en/card/09029) use Assimilator to obtain non-virtual resources?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nWhat happens if the Runner uses Assimilator to flip up a console while a console is already installed?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "assimilator",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If an [Asteroid Belt](07012) has 4 hosted advancement counters, how much does it cost to rez it during a run made with [Tread Lightly](30012)?",
    "answer": "It would cost 0[c]. To determine what a cost is when effects are modifying its value, start with the default value for that cost ([Asteroid Belt](07012)’s printed rez cost is 9[c]), apply each effect that increases the cost ([Tread Lightly](30012) adds 3[c]), and then apply each effect that lowers the cost ([Asteroid Belt](07012)’s ability subtracts 3[c] for each hosted advancement counter).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "asteroid_belt",
    "update_date": "2021-10-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Audacity count itself toward the required number of cards in HQ?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "audacity",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf there are cards installed in the root of a central server, how many times does Aumakua trigger?",
    "answer": "Aumakua triggers once after the whole access step.\n\nDoes Aumakua trigger after the Runner accesses Archives?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "aumakua",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner avoid the tag from Authenticator and still bypass it?",
    "answer": "If the Runner avoids the tag, then they have not paid the cost to bypass Authenticator and therefore do not bypass it.\n \nIf [Jesminder Sareen](/en/card/10006) has not previously avoided a tag this run and encounters Authenticator, can she bypass it?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "authenticator",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner gain a credit when they sabotage and have [Demolisher](/en/card/26002) installed?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp is trashing the cards when resolving a sabotage effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "avgustina_ivanovskaya",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Ice hosted on Awakening Center can be rezzed through other card\neffects, but a rezzed piece of ice cannot be encountered unless it was\nrezzed by Awakening Center. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "awakening_center",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Only one piece of hosted ice on Awakening Center can be\nencountered per run. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "awakening_center",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Ice on Awakening Center are in the server and do not count as ice\nprotecting the server. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "awakening_center",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Tāo Salonga](/en/card/30019) to swap a piece of ice protecting a server with ice hosted on ​[Awakening Center​](/en/card/03021)?",
    "answer": "Yes, but only if that piece of ice is a rezzed ​**bioroid​**, because [Awakening Center​](/en/card/03021) is only a legal location for ​**bioroid​** ice. If the ice is unrezzed, the Runner cannot demonstrate that the swap is legal. It does not matter if the ice was exposed earlier in the game or is otherwise known by the Runner; it only matters whether the Runner is allowed to see the ​**bioroid​** subtype at the time Tāo’s ability resolves. If a rezzed **bioroid​** is swapped this way, the Corp will not be able to pay the cost to force the Runner to encounter it with [Awakening Center​](/en/card/03021)​’s second ability unless another effect derezzes the ​**bioroid​**.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "awakening_center",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When exactly does the Runner set aside cards with [Ayla “Bios” Rahim](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31025), and how does the ability interact with taking a mulligan?",
    "answer": "The Runner should set aside the cards after revealing IDs and shuffling their deck, before drawing any cards. After setting aside cards and shuffling again, the Runner draws a starting hand. If the Runner chooses to take a mulligan, the set aside cards are not affected in any way, as those cards are no longer in the deck.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ayla_bios_rahim_simulant_specialist",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner trash cards set aside with [Ayla “Bios” Rahim](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31025) to use [Endless Hunger](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/09033)?",
    "answer": "No, set aside cards are not installed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ayla_bios_rahim_simulant_specialist",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes a card with a printed rez cost of 2 to pay the additional cost to score [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), can they use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066) into the root of the same server as the [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058)? Can they then resolve [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066)’s ability?",
    "answer": "Yes and yes. When the Corp pays the additional cost to score [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), a checkpoint occurs before the score effect itself is resolved.  [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) triggers at this checkpoint and resolves in time for [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066) to be active when its trigger condition is met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "azef_protocol",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) while resolving the additional cost on [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) to install an asset in the root of the same server as [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058)?",
    "answer": "It is not possible to do this and still score the [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058). When the Corp pays the additional cost to score [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), a checkpoint occurs before the score effect itself is resolved.  [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) triggers at this checkpoint and resolves fully before the game continues attempting to resolve scoring. If the Corp chooses to install an asset in the root of the server that currently contains [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), they must trash [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) as part of installing the asset. This is legal, but when the reaction window closes and the game proceeds, the score effect won't be able to find [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) because it is no longer installed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "azef_protocol",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp has [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) with 2 advancement counters in the root of a server with a rezzed [SanSan City Grid](/en/card/31069), can they trash the [SanSan City Grid](/en/card/31069) to score the [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058)?",
    "answer": "No, trashing the [SanSan City Grid](/en/card/31069) would result in no longer meeting the requirement for scoring the [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "azef_protocol",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp names \"event\" for the card type for Azmari EdTech, does the Corp still gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> if the Runner plays [Employee Strike](/en/card/09053)?",
    "answer": "No. Following the rules for playing events, \"when played\" abilities do not meet their trigger condition until the even in question is active in the play area. Employee Strike blanks Azmari EdTech as soon as it becomes active, so its ability is no longer active and cannot trigger.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "azmari_edtech_shaping_the_future",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner’s mark stay if all mark cards leave play, or does it leave and return when a new mark card comes into play?",
    "answer": "When you identify your mark, that server becomes your mark for the turn, even if the card that instructed you to identify your mark leaves play. If an event instructs you to identify your mark, that server continues to be your mark for the remainder of the turn after that event resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "backstitching",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner does not have a mark, and they install a card that says “When your turn begins, identify your mark.”, do they get a mark for the current turn?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner only identifies a mark when an ability instructs them to.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "backstitching",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has multiple “mark” cards, how do they identify their mark?",
    "answer": "The first time each turn the Runner resolves an instruction to identify their mark, they will randomly choose a central server. That server becomes their mark for the entire turn. Resolving another instruction to identify their mark will have no effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "backstitching",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner encounters [Konjin](/en/card/26109) protecting their mark, and they are forced to encounter ice protecting a different server, can they trash [Backstitching](/en/card/33019) to bypass the ice that [Konjin](/en/card/26109) forced them to encounter?",
    "answer": "Yes. The attacked server is still the Runner’s mark, so the forced encounter from [Konjin](/en/card/26109) still meets [Backstitching](/en/card/33019)’s trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "backstitching",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner steals Bacterial Programming from **R&D** with accesses remaining, what happens if the Corp uses the ability on Bacterial Programming?",
    "answer": "The Runner continues accessing cards from R&D as normal, starting with whatever card is now on top of R&D, and proceeding down through as many cards as they have accesses remaining.\n\nIf the Runner steals Bacterial Programming from **HQ** with accesses remaining, what happens if the Corp uses the ability on Bacterial Programming to add any cards to HQ?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bacterial_programming",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can choose which memory to lose (e.g., memory from\n[Deep Red](/en/card/04042)). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "bad_times",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Corp uses [Sub Boost](/en/card/07025) or [Sensei](/en/card/02034) to give Bailiff an additional subroutine, and the Runner uses [Breach](/en/card/05042) to break both subroutines at once, does the Corp gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> or 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "The Corp gains 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>. Even though the Runner only triggered one ability, both subroutines were broken.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bailiff",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use “Baklan” Bochkin to take a tag, even if they are not encountering a piece of ice?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nCan the Corp re-rez a piece of ice immediately after “Baklan” Bochkin derezzes it?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "baklan_bochkin",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Who chooses whether to trash a program or end the run?",
    "answer": "The Corp makes any choices in resolving subroutines unless the ability specifically directs the Runner to perform its effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ballista",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can take credits from Bank Job if they made a\nsuccessful run on an empty server. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "bank_job",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner has both Bazaar and [Replicator](/en/card/02088) installed, can they install all copies of a piece of hardware from Grip and Stack by installing the first copy?",
    "answer": "Yes. Bazaar and Replicator meet their trigger condition simultaneously, so the Runner can choose to trigger Replicator first and then trigger Bazaar. The Runner may choose to repeat this process until there are no more copies of that hardware available to install.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bazaar",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the additional cost from Bellona meet GameNET's trigger condition?",
    "answer": "Yes. There is not normally a cost to steal an agenda, so the Runner is paying a cost because of a Corp card ability.\n\nIf the Runner steals Bellona with 2 advancement counters on it while NAPD Cordon is active, how many different costs do they pay? How many times can the Corp trigger GameNET?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bellona",
    "update_date": "2020-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner still steal an agenda if they prevent some or all of the net damage incurred by Ben Musashi?",
    "answer": "If the Runner prevents even a single point of the net damage incurred by Ben Musashi, then they have not paid the additional cost to steal the agenda and therefore do not steal it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ben_musashi",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nHow long does the strength boost on Berserker last?",
    "answer": "Like with typical strength boosts from icebreakers, Berserker resets at the end of each encounter.\n\nIf the Runner encounters a [Galahad](/en/card/06011), how much strength does Berserker gain?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "berserker",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan Best Defense trash facedown Runner cards?",
    "answer": "No. Facedown Runner cards do not have install costs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "best_defense",
    "update_date": "2018-02-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 10](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Intervention_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan Best Defense trash a Corp card?",
    "answer": "No.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "best_defense",
    "update_date": "2018-02-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhat does it mean for the Corp to “have” a certain number of credits?",
    "answer": "This means that the player has that number of credits in their credit pool. Recurring credits and other credits hosted on cards do not count unless they say otherwise.\n\nWith Beth Kilrain-Chang installed, if the Corp has 9<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> and a scored [Corporate Sales Team](/en/card/10037) when the Runner's turn begins, does the Runner gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>, draw 1 card, or both?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "beth_kilrain_chang",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Runner trashes cards during Biased Reporting, which player gains the credits?",
    "answer": "The Runner.\n\nDoes the Corp gain credits before or after the Runner trashes cards to Biased Reporting?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "biased_reporting",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “You may score that card, if able.” mean?",
    "answer": "Normally, resolving a **terminal** operation would skip all remaining paid ability windows this turn where the Corp can score an agenda. This effect provides an opportunity to score outside of a paid ability window, but the Corp still needs to meet the advancement requirement of the agenda and any other requirements in effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "big_deal",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "####MWL [update v1.2]\nNAPD Most Wanted List - **Level 1**: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction.",
    "card_codename": "bio_ethics_association",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the only piece of ice protecting Bio-Ethics Association  is returned to hand by [Blue Sun](/en/card/06068) at the start of the Corp's turn, does the ability of the political asset still trigger?",
    "answer": "Yes. If the Corp chooses to trigger Blue Sun before triggering the ability on Bio-Ethics Association, then when that ability resolves the \"if\" clause will be true and allow resolution.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bio_ethics_association",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner prevent all of the first instance of net damage in a turn using both [Net Shield](/en/card/01045) and Bio-Modeled Network?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner can trash Bio-Modeled Network, preventing all but the first damage, then pay 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> using Net Shield to prevent that damage.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bio_modeled_network",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Biometric Spoofing to prevent 1 damage?",
    "answer": "Yes. Because the ability does not say \"if able\", it will resolve as much as possible when used.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "biometric_spoofing",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhat does “immediately after playing an operation” on Bioroid Work Crew mean? Does the Corp trigger this ability in the next paid ability window after resolving an operation, or does it have special timing?",
    "answer": "Treat Bioroid Work Crew as if it read “Use this ability only during the next paid ability window after playing and resolving an operation.”",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bioroid_work_crew",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Bishop only moves from a piece of ice protecting a central server to\na piece of ice protecting a remote server, and vice versa. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "bishop",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Bishop can be hosted on any piece of ice if it is already hosted on\nanother non-ice card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "bishop",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the Corp gain the bonuses from Black Level Clearance if the Runner jacks out before Black Level Clearance allows the Runner to?",
    "answer": "No. The latter part of the ability is conditional on the first part.\n\nIf the Runner jacks out with Black Level Clearance, does the Runner take a tag from [John Masanori](/en/card/04009)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "black_level_clearance",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 3: Each copy of this card costs 3 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "blackmail",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When does [Bladderwort](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33041) check the Corp’s credits?",
    "answer": "[Bladderwort](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33041) checks the Corp’s credits when its second instruction resolves, after the Corp gains 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> from its first instruction.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bladderwort",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "How do multiple rezzed copies of [Bladderwort](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33041) interact with each other?",
    "answer": "The Corp resolves 1 copy of the ability at a time in full before moving on to the next copy. If a chain reaction or other “when your turn begins” ability resolves in the middle of this process and causes the Corp to lose or spend credits, it is possible that a copy resolved later could do net damage even though the Corp had too many credits to meet the requirement on a previously-resolved copy.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bladderwort",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner trash a card with [Aesop's Pawnshop](/en/card/01047) and then remove that same card from the heap with Bloo Moose?",
    "answer": "Yes. Both Aesop's Pawnshop and Bloo Moose meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner can choose the order in which the abilities trigger.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bloo_moose",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the base trace strength for [Amani Senai](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21076)’s ability if Blood in the Water is scored or stolen?",
    "answer": "[Amani Senai](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21076)’s base trace strength will be equal to the number of cards in the Runner’s grip.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "blood_in_the_water",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What choice does the Runner need to make with [RNG Key](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21029) to gain credits or draw cards if the next card they access is [Blood in the Water](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33039)?",
    "answer": "The chosen number must be equal to the number of cards in the Runner’s grip at the time [RNG Key](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21029)’s last sentence resolves during the access of [Blood in the Water](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33039). This is not necessarily the same as the number of cards in the Runner’s grip when the choice is made. For example, if the Runner has 4 cards in their grip when the run is declared successful, but suffers 1 net damage from [Hokusai Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31059) before breaching the server, they will need to have chosen the number 3 in order to draw cards or gain credits with [RNG Key](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21029).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "blood_in_the_water",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhere does the Corp install the ice for Bloom's second subroutine?",
    "answer": "The ice is installed in the position closer to the server than Bloom where the Runner would approach it after passing Bloom.\n\nIf the Corp uses [Wormhole](/en/card/07013) to resolve Bloom's first subroutine, where can the Corp install the ice?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bloom",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the ice chosen for Boomerang is derezzed or moved, can Boomerang still be used?",
    "answer": "Yes. Boomerang can keep track of which piece of ice was chosen as long as both Boomerang and the ice remain installed.\n\nIf the ice chosen for Boomerang is uninstalled and then reinstalled, can Boomerang still be used?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "boomerang",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is [Botulus](/en/card/30004)’s strength?",
    "answer": "[Botulus](/en/card/30004) is not an **icebreaker**, so it does not have a strength value. Its ability can be used to break subroutines on ice of any strength.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "botulus",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens to [Botulus](/en/card/30004) if the ice hosting it is trashed or derezzed?",
    "answer": "If the host ice is trashed or otherwise uninstalled, any cards and counters hosted on it, including [Botulus](/en/card/30004), are trashed. If the host ice is merely derezzed, it keeps all of its hosted cards and counters, including [Botulus](/en/card/30004).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "botulus",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner uses both Brahman and [Faerie](/en/card/02104) to break subroutines on a piece of ice, can the Runner choose to add Faerie to the top of their stack instead of trashing Faerie?",
    "answer": "Yes. Faerie and Brahman meet their trigger condition simultaneously, so the Runner chooses the order in which their conditional abilities resolve. If the Runner chooses to resolve Brahman’s ability first, then Faerie is no longer active, so its conditional ability fails to resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "brahman",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner has negative agenda points, Brain Chip does not lower\nhis or her hand size or MU: these cannot be increased by a negative\nnumber. [Official FAQ] [Negative agenda points can be gained from [News Team](/en/card/09009) or [Shi.Kyū](/en/card/05011).]",
    "card_codename": "brain_chip",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhat is randomized by Brain Rewiring? Which cards are selected from the grip, or the order they are put on the bottom of the stack?",
    "answer": "Both.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "brain_rewiring",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Corp has a scored [Braintrust](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/20094) with 1 agenda counter, and forfeits it to rez [Archer](), how much does the Corp pay for rezzing [Archer](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31075)?",
    "answer": "It costs 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> plus the forfeit of [Braintrust](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/20094). The decision of what you use to pay is made upfront and then the cost is paid simultaneously. The [Braintrust](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/20094) ability applies while deciding what to pay for the cost.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "braintrust",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Corp installs ice with the first subroutine on [Brân 1.0](/en/card/30039), can they trash other ice? Can they trash [Brân 1.0](/en/card/30039) itself? What happens if they do?",
    "answer": "Yes, the procedure for installing ice is followed normally, except for the destination position being behind [Brân 1.0](/en/card/30039) instead of the outermost position. However, the relative position of each piece of ice protecting the server is established before any cards are trashed. If [Brân 1.0](/en/card/30039) is trashed, the encounter will end as soon as the install effect is complete, no more of its subroutines will resolve, and the Runner’s next position will correspond to the newly-installed ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bran_1_0",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Corp have to pay to rez ice installed with [Brân 1.0](/en/card/30039)?",
    "answer": "Yes. The “ignoring all costs” clause only applies while the ice is being installed, not when it is later approached and rezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bran_1_0",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the run need to be successful for the Runner to gain credits?",
    "answer": "No. Bravado's conditional ability meets its trigger condition when the run ends, regardless of how it ended.\n\nIf the Runner passes an unrezzed piece of ice, does it count toward how many credits Bravado lets them gain?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bravado",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "breaking_news",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp plays [Paywall Implementation](/en/card/06028) with Bryan Stinson, does it get removed from the game? If so, when? What if the Runner trashes Bryan Stinson before an agenda is stolen or another current is played?",
    "answer": "Paywall Implementation will be removed from the game instead of trashed whenever it would normally get trashed: once an agenda is stolen or another current is played. Once Bryan Stinson’s ability is triggered, it exists independently of Bryan Stinson, so Paywall Implementation will still be removed from game instead of being trashed even if Bryan Stinson is trashed before that happens.\n\nIf the Corp plays a terminal transaction with Bryan Stinson, such as [Violet Level Clearance](/en/card/11111), does it still get removed from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bryan_stinson",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Buffer Drive to put an event at the bottom of the stack after playing it?",
    "answer": "No. Events resolve in and are then trashed from from the play area, not the grip. Nice try!\n\nIf a card is trashed from the grip or stack, can Buffer Drive move it to the bottom of the stack before Skorpios Defense Systems removes it from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "buffer_drive",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner installs Bug Out Bag with [Career Fair](/en/card/08023), how many power counters are placed on it?",
    "answer": "Lowering the install cost of Bug Out Bag has no effect on the value of X. The number of counters placed on Bug Out Bag is always equal to the number of credits actually paid to install it.\n\nHow many tags must the Runner have for the Corp to use [Best Defense](/en/card/11079) to trash a Bug Out Bag with 5 power counters on it?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bug_out_bag",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the first time the Corp installs a card in a turn is with Building Blocks, does [419](/en/card/21063) trigger?",
    "answer": "Yes, but the barrier is both installed and rezzed simultaneously, thus rendering the ice ineligible to be exposed. Because the barrier cannot be exposed, the Corp can decline to pay 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> and 419's ability will simply do nothing.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "building_blocks",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the Runner still gain credits from Bukhgalter if another card is used during the encounter where all subroutines are broken by Bukhgalter (i..e Datasucker to reduce strength)?",
    "answer": "Yes, what matters is that all subroutines were broken using Bukhgalter.\n\nWhat happens if the encountered ice gains additional subroutines after the Runner uses Bukhgalter to break all of the other subroutines?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "bukhgalter",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner plays By Any Means and then accesses an [Archangel](/en/card/09013), can the Runner trash the Archangel before encountering it?",
    "answer": "Yes. Whenever more than one ability meet their trigger conditions, first the active player's abilities resolve, then the inactive player's abilities resolve. If one of those abilities moves the card being accessed to a different zone, no further \"when accessed\" abilities can resolve.\n\nIf the Runner plays By Any Means and then accesses an advanced [Project Junebug](/en/card/01069), can the Corp deal net damage?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "by_any_means",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp moves Calibration Testing to HQ, can they use it to place advancement tokens on an agenda in HQ?",
    "answer": "No. Only installed cards can host advancement tokens.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "calibration_testing",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes Calvin B4L3Y’s last ability trigger when it’s unrezzed or not installed?",
    "answer": "No.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "calvin_b4l3y",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Caprice Nisei’s ability triggers at step 4 of a run. [Official FAQ] \n\n[This means that in order for Caprice's ability to trigger on a current run, the latest the Corp can rez Caprice is at run step 2.3 of the approach to the innermost ice, when the runner has decided to continue towards this ice. This is the same window that this ice can be rezzed. \n\nRezzing Caprice after the runner passes the innermost ice is too late to have her ability trigger this run, because the next non-ice rez window after passing the innermost ice is 4.3, which is after Caprice's ability would trigger.]",
    "card_codename": "caprice_nisei",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If there is no ice protecting the server, Caprice Nisei’s ability still\ntriggers if she was rezzed before the run was initiated. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "caprice_nisei",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a player charge cards that have 2 or more power counters?",
    "answer": "Yes, a card that has 2 power counters qualifies as having at least 1 power counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "captain_padma_isbister_intrepid_explorer",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner chooses to use [Carnivore](/en/card/30003), can they draw with [René “Loup” Arcemont](/en/card/30001) before trashing cards from their grip?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner must fully resolve [Carnivore](/en/card/30003)’s ability before the trigger condition on *Loup*’s ability is met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carnivore",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Carnivore](/en/card/30003) to trash an operation or piece of ice?",
    "answer": "Yes. [Carnivore](/en/card/30003) does not care whether a card you access has a trash cost.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carnivore",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Carnivore](/en/card/30003) to trash an agenda they don’t want to steal?",
    "answer": "Yes. Once the agenda is trashed, the access ends. The Runner will not steal it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carnivore",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Carnivore](/en/card/30003) if the last subroutine on [Ansel 1.0](/en/card/30038) resolved earlier in the run?",
    "answer": "No. That subroutine prohibits the Runner from trashing cards they access in any way, not just by using the basic trash ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carnivore",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner’s mark stay if all mark cards leave play, or does it leave and return when a new mark card comes into play?",
    "answer": "When you identify your mark, that server becomes your mark for the turn, even if the card that instructed you to identify your mark leaves play. If an event instructs you to identify your mark, that server continues to be your mark for the remainder of the turn after that event resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carpe_diem",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has multiple “mark” cards, how do they identify their mark?",
    "answer": "The first time each turn the Runner resolves an instruction to identify their mark, they will randomly choose a central server. That server becomes their mark for the entire turn. Resolving another instruction to identify their mark will have no effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carpe_diem",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner makes a successful run on a server that later becomes their mark with [Carpe Diem](/en/card/33012), will “the first time each turn you make a successful run on your mark” abilities resolve?",
    "answer": "No. To meet these abilities’ trigger conditions, the Runner must make a successful run on a server while that server is their mark. A previous successful run made before the attacked server became the Runner’s mark will not retroactively become a run on their mark. The Runner can still trigger these abilities by running the server again after it becomes their mark.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "carpe_diem",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Agendas installed faceup with Casting Call are not active (unless\nthose agendas can be installed faceup through their own abilities). [Official FAQ] [Example agendas that can be installed faceup: [Oaktown Renovation](/en/card/08058),\n [Underway Renovation](/en/card/08077), [Hollywood Renovation](/en/card/08098).]",
    "card_codename": "casting_call",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the agenda hosting Casting Call is uninstalled, Casting Call is\ntrashed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "casting_call",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Corp use Cayambe Grid to place advancement tokens on Border Control?",
    "answer": "Yes. Cayambe Grid's first ability does not require you to choose a piece of ice you can advance.\n\nWhat is an \"advanced piece of ice?\"",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cayambe_grid",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "cerberus_lady_h1",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nThis card is a reprint. Has anything changed about how Cerebral Overwriter works?",
    "answer": "Only in the most technical sense. The newly updated wording and the rules for nested costs in CR 1.4 indicate that the 3[c] in Cerebral Overwriter's second ability is a cost, which was not clear before. But the ability functions essentially as it always did.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cerebral_overwriter",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use credits on [Cezve]([Cezve](/en/card/33017)) to pay for installing cards with [Masterwork (v37)](/en/card/26015)?",
    "answer": "Yes. The run is already in progress when abilities with “run begins” trigger conditions resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cezve",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use credits hosted on [Cezve](/en/card/33017) to install [MKUltra](/en/card/11081), [Black Orchestra](/en/card/11042) or [Paperclip](/en/card/11024) if they intend to trash [Cezve](/en/card/33017) to install that program?",
    "answer": "No. When installing a card, players trash cards before paying for install costs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cezve",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Charlatan to bypass a piece of ice after the Corp rezzes it?",
    "answer": "No. “When approached” abilities meet their trigger condition at step 2 of a run when the approach begins, but the Corp does not rez approached ice until step 2.3 of the run. Charlatan’s ability creates a conditional ability that only meets its trigger condition the first time the runner approaches an already rezzed piece of ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "charlatan",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp look at the cards that are being trashed while resolving sabotage?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp must choose which cards to trash first, and then all cards are trashed simultaneously. The Corp can look at the trashed cards from R&D in Archives after all trashes from sabotage have been resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chastushka",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp has only 1 card in HQ and must sabotage 2, can they choose to “trash 2 cards from HQ” in order to only trash the 1 card in HQ?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp must trash 2 cards if possible. The Corp must trash the remaining card from R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chastushka",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp has only 1 card in R&D and must sabotage 2, can they choose to “trash 2 cards from R&D” in order to only trash the 1 card in R&D?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp must trash 2 cards if possible. The Corp must trash the remaining card from HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chastushka",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What if the Corp has only 1 card total in HQ and R&D and must sabotage 2?",
    "answer": "The Corp trashes all cards from HQ and R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chastushka",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner gain a credit when they sabotage and have [Demolisher](/en/card/26002) installed?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp is trashing the cards when resolving a sabotage effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chastushka",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes the counter spent to install a program with Chatterjee University count toward reducing the program's cost?",
    "answer": "Yes. The text of the ability resolves in order, so the counter is only removed after the program is installed. Therefore the counter is still on Chatterjee University when the install cost must be paid, and reduces the cost.\n\nCan the Runner use Chatterjee University's ability to install a program when there are no counters on it?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chatterjee_university",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf an encountered piece of ice is trashed, does Chief Slee gain power counters?",
    "answer": "Yes. If an encountered piece of ice is uninstalled, then the encounter immediately ends.\n\nIf the Runner trashes [Hive](/en/card/04117) during the encounter while the Corp has 2 agenda points in their score area, how many power counters are placed on Chief Slee? What if the Runner encounters and trashes an ice that gains subroutines, like [Komainu](/en/card/05017)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chief_slee",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Datasucker to help trash ice faster with Chisel? What about cards like Null: Whistleblower?",
    "answer": "No, Datasucker can only reduce the strength of ice during the paid ability window of an encounter, which is after Chisel’s ability will already have resolved and either trashed the ice or added a virus counter to itself. Null, on the other hand, has a conditional ability with the same trigger condition as Chisel, so the Runner can choose the order to trigger and resolve those abilities. Chisel looks at the strength of the ice at the time its ability resolves, which will include Null’s effect if that was resolved first.\n\nIf the Runner encounters a Tollbooth hosting a Chisel with 5 virus counters, do they still have to pay 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chisel",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Ice Carver](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31009) apply its -1 strength before or after [Chisel](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/26003)’s ability resolves?",
    "answer": "Before. [Ice Carver](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31009) has a static ability, which means it applies as soon as the encounter begins. The Runner doesn’t have to trigger the ability explicitly or wait for conditional abilities to resolve before it takes effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chisel",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Runner use [Political Operative](/en/card/10043) to trash a rezzed Chrysalis?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "chrysalis",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner jacks out immediately after encountering a Chum and\nnot breaking its subroutine, the Runner does not take any damage. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "chum",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Chum deals its net damage the first time either of the following\noccur during an encounter with the next piece of ice:\n\n1) step 3.1 of a run closes and there is an unbroken subroutine on\nthe piece of ice.\n\n2) step 3.1 of a run was skipped or did not resolve because the\nencounter/run ends (if 3.1 does not happen, no subroutines can be\nbroken). This applies even if the piece of ice has 0 subroutines. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "chum",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses [Joshua B.](/en/card/02042) to gain an extra click while untagged, can [Citadel Sanctuary](/en/card/11070) remove the tag gained from Joshua B.’s ability at the end of the turn?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner must be tagged when the end of the turn occurs in order for Citadel Sanctuary to meet its trigger condition. If the Runner takes a tag after the end of the turn has already occurred, such as through Joshua B.’s ability, then Citadel Sanctuary cannot retroactively meet its trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "citadel_sanctuary",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp advance [Clearinghouse](/en/card/30061) if it’s unrezzed?",
    "answer": "Yes. Abilities that allow the Corp to advance a card are active even if the card is unrezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "clearinghouse",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp does not trash a card for Climactic Showdown, does the Runner access 2 additional cards from the chosen server or from the server they are accessing?",
    "answer": "If the Runner accesses HQ before R&D that turn, they access 2 additional cards from HQ. If the Runner accesses R&D before HQ that turn, they access 2 additional cards from R&D.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp does not have any installed ice when Climactic Showdown resolves?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "climactic_showdown",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "clone_chip",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the operation returned to HQ with Clone Suffrage Movement is facedown in Archives, must the Corp reveal it to the Runner?",
    "answer": "Yes, just like when returning a copy of [Subliminal Messaging](/en/card/04100) from Archives to HQ, the Corp must reveal this information as the ability resolves.\n\nIf the only piece of ice protecting Clone Suffrage Movement  is returned to hand by [Blue Sun](/en/card/06068) at the start of the Corp's turn, does the ability of the political asset still trigger?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "clone_suffrage_movement",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIs \"Clones are not People\" trashed while in the score area if another current is played or an agenda is stolen?",
    "answer": "No. \"Clones are not People\" is added to the Corp's score area as a blank agenda.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "clones_are_not_people",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the Runner’s last chance to use an ability like [Simulchip](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/26085) to install [Clot](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31005) before the Corp can score an agenda?",
    "answer": "When the Corp places the last required advancement counter on an agenda during their turn, they will be the next player to receive priority, so they can score the agenda immediately. If the Runner wants to use [Clot](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31005) to prohibit the Corp from scoring, they must install it before the final advancement counter is placed on it. Note that sometimes more than one advancement counter can be placed at a time, such as with [Trick of Light](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31058), so the Runner may have to install [Clot](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31005) when they think the Corp still needs two more advancement counters to account for such effects.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "clot",
    "update_date": "2022-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp uses Code Replicator to force the Runner to approach the outermost piece of ice a second time, is the Runner still prohibited from jacking out?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner is only disallowed from jacking out the first time they approach a piece of ice in a run. This rule is not tied to any specific piece of ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "code_replicator",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner trash a [Cloak](/en/card/03041) if they spend the credit from Cloak during the run initiated by Cold Read?",
    "answer": "Yes. Spending recurring credits from a card is considered using that card, so trashing Cloak for Cold Read is allowed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cold_read",
    "update_date": "2017-04-18",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nThis card is a reprint. Has anything changed about how Colossus works?",
    "answer": "Yes. The wording of Colossus's subroutines has been updated to remove the parentheses. Each subroutine now uses a conditional replacement effect, which in most cases achieves the same result. But effects such as Loki that refer to subroutines on Colossus now interact with it differently. If Loki gains a subroutine from Colossus, it will now check the number of advancement tokens on itself (Loki) to determine the effect the subroutine should have. Previously, it was unclear how to interpret the two different instructions in the subroutine without the linked ability explaining the parenthetical text.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "colossus",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the only piece of ice protecting Commercial Bankers Group  is returned to hand by [Blue Sun](/en/card/06068) at the start of the Corp's turn, does the ability of the political asset still trigger?",
    "answer": "Yes. If the Corp chooses to trigger Blue Sun before triggering the ability on Commercial Bankers Group, then when that ability resolves the \"if\" clause will be true and allow resolution.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "commercial_bankers_group",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the Runner have to shuffle the stack after searching it with Compile?",
    "answer": "Per the rules on searching a deck for cards, after a search is performed, the deck must be shuffled immediately before proceeding with any remaining effects initiated by the search.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "compile",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp names I’ve Had Worse and trashes one with Complete Image, does the Runner draw right away or later?",
    "answer": "The Runner draws from the ability on I’ve Had Worse before the next iteration of Complete Image. The Corp names the next target card after the draw is complete.\n\nIf Complete Image doesn’t trash the named card but Potential Unleashed does, does Complete Image repeat?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "complete_image",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Conduit](/en/card/30024)'s paid ability and makes a successful run on R&D, do they put a virus counter on [Conduit](/en/card/30024) before or after they breach R&D?",
    "answer": "After. A run is still in progress while the attacked server is being breached, and [Conduit](/en/card/30024)’s first ability waits for the run to end.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "conduit",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Conduit](/en/card/30024)’s action ability to run R&D, but [Conduit](/en/card/30024) is trashed before R&D is breached, how many additional cards does the Runner access?",
    "answer": "[Conduit](/en/card/30024)’s action ability checks the number of hosted counters at the time its nested “when you breach R&D” ability resolves. If [Conduit](/en/card/30024) is trashed before this, there are no longer any hosted counters, so the Runner will not access any additional cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "conduit",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The Runner uses [Conduit](/en/card/30024)'s action ability while there are 2 virus counters on [Conduit](/en/card/30024). The second card the Runner accesses is Cyberdex Virus Suite and the Corp purges virus counters. Does the Runner access a third card in R&D?",
    "answer": "Yes. The limit to how many cards the Runner can access from R&D is determined at the beginning of breaching R&D. Once accessing cards begins, changing the number of virus counters on [Conduit](/en/card/30024) will have no effect on the breach already in progress.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "conduit",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Corp triggers [Mumbad City Hall](/en/card/10055) three times with [Jeeves Model Bioroids](/en/card/10067) rezzed, can they reveal Consulting Visit for the third usage of Mumbad City Hall and use the click from Jeeves to pay the additional cost?",
    "answer": "Yes. Jeeves Model Bioroids triggers off of the Corp paying the clicks, and due to the chain reaction rule it must resolve before Mumbad City Hall continues on to play the Consulting Visit.\n\nIf the Corp plays [Accelerated Diagnostics](/en/card/04052) and finds Consulting Visit and two other operations, can they play Consulting Visit followed by the other operations seen with Accelerated Diagnostics?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "consulting_visit",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has both Consume and [Hivemind](/en/card/07042) installed, each with 2 virus counters hosted on them, what happens when the Runner uses Consume?",
    "answer": "The Runner gains 8<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> and removes all four virus counters from both Consume and Hivemind.\n\nIf the Runner plays [Apocalypse](/en/card/09030) while Consume is installed, does Consume gain virus counters before being flipped facedown?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "consume",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner play Contaminate if the only installed Runner cards are virus programs and a [Hivemind](/en/card/07042) with a virus counter on it?",
    "answer": "No.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "contaminate",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose the Runner has [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) and [Hivemind](/en/card/07042) installed, with 1 virus counter on [Hivemind](/en/card/07042). If they then install [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017), is the host ice derezzed immediately? Or does it wait for the next check at the beginning of the Runner's next turn?",
    "answer": "By managing their abilities carefully, the Runner can choose whether to derez the ice right away or not. [Hivemind](/en/card/07042)’s second ability is a static ability, so it always applies as soon as [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) is installed. But the conditional abilities on [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) and [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner can choose the order to resolve them. If they resolve [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) first, it will only have 2 hosted virus counters (including the one shared from [Hivemind](/en/card/07042)) at the time that the number of counters is checked. If they resolve [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) first, then by the time [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) resolves, it will have 3 hosted virus counters and will derez the ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cookbook",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If a piece of ice is bypassed, Copycat still triggers since the ice is also\npassed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "copycat",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Cordyceps to swap a piece of ice protecting the attacked server with ice hosted on Awakening Center?",
    "answer": "Yes, but only if that piece of ice is a rezzed bioroid, because Awakening Center is only a legal location for bioroid ice. If the ice is unrezzed, the Runner cannot demonstrate that the swap is legal. It does not matter if the ice was exposed earlier in the game or is otherwise known by the Runner; it only matters whether the Runner is allowed to see the bioroid subtype at the time Cordyceps's ability resolves. If a rezzed bioroid is swapped this way, the Corp will not be able to pay the cost to force the Runner to encounter it with Awakening Center's second ability unless another effect derezzes the bioroid.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cordyceps",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the additional bad publicity from Corporate Scandal be removed?",
    "answer": "No. The Corp is considered to have an additional bad publicity, even when they have none, but it does not exist for the purposes of being manipulated (such as removing it).\n\nThe Corp has 0 bad publicity when the Runner plays Corporate Scandal. The Corp plays [The All-Seeing I](/en/card/09022). Can the Runner remove the additional bad publicity from Corporate Scandal to prevent all resources from being trashed?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "corporate_scandal",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIs the rez cost in Councilman's ability affected by constant abilities on cards such as [Breaker Bay Grid](/en/card/08040)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Whenever an ability queries a value from the game, modifiers are taken into account unless otherwise noted.\n\nIs the rez cost in Councilman's ability affected by modifiers at the time of rez, such as from [Worlds Plaza](/en/card/08116)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "councilman",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses Counter Surveillance to run on R&D, but they have fewer credits than tags by the time the run is successful, what happens?",
    "answer": "The Runner cannot pay the full cost, so the Runner’s access step is replaced with accessing no cards.\n\nIf the Runner uses [Eater](/en/card/07040) during a run initiated by Counter Surveillance, what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "counter_surveillance",
    "update_date": "2021-11-03",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan Cradle have negative strength if the Runner has 6 or more cards in their grip? If so, what ice can Cradle break if its strength is negative?",
    "answer": "Yes, strength on both ice and icebreakers can be negative. An icebreaker's strength being negative does not affect its basic functionality; it can still only break subroutines on ice with strength less than or equal to the icebreaker's strength.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.05).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cradle",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [Creative Commission](/en/card/30020) if they only have 1 click left?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner only needs to spend the 1 click required for the basic action to play an event. The second sentence on [Creative Commission](/en/card/30020) is part of its effect, not a cost to play the card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "creative_commission",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDuring a run initiated by Credit Crash, is the Runner required to reveal the accessed card to the Corp if it is accessed from R&D?",
    "answer": "The card must be revealed. This effect requires the Corp to act on an element of the card, so it is satisfied by the Corp examining that card.\n\nIf the Corp prevents the trashing of the first card accessed with Credit Crash, can the Runner still trash that card normally?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "credit_crash",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner avoid the tag from Credit Kiting and still install a card?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "credit_kiting",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028) to run a server with a rezzed [Crisium Grid](/en/card/31079), will they access an additional card?",
    "answer": "No. [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028)’s ability that gives an additional access is a delayed conditional ability created by its “If successful” ability. Since [Crisium Grid](/en/card/31079) stops the run from being declared successful, that ability is never resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "crisium_grid",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [Emergency Shutdown](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31016) on their second click after they ran HQ with an active [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) that was trashed during the breach?",
    "answer": "No, the Runner did not make a successful run on HQ due to [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079)’s ability. Trashing [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) does not retroactively make the run successful.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "crisium_grid",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner breaches a server that has a rezzed [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079), do they access cards as normal?",
    "answer": "Yes. Preventing the run from being declared successful only affects abilities that require a successful run, such as the restriction on playing [Emergency Shutdown](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31016).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "crisium_grid",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) is active in the root of HQ and the Runner uses [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023), is the run successful on either Archives or HQ?",
    "answer": "No, [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023) changes the attacked server while step 6.9.5a of the run is imminent, because the expected effects of that step include the trigger condition of [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023)’s delayed conditional ability, which is that the run on Archives would be declared successful. However, once the attacked server is changed to HQ, the imminent step cannot declare the run successful after all because of [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079)’s ability. The Runner will still breach HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "crisium_grid",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) is active in the root of Archives and the Runner uses [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023), what server does the Runner breach and is the run successful?",
    "answer": "The Runner breaches Archives and the run is not declared successful. Since [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079)’s ability is a static ability and applies immediately, declaring the run successful is never part of the expected effects of step 6.9.5a of the run, so the trigger condition of [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023)’s delayed conditional ability is never met and the ability never resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "crisium_grid",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Runner installs a program from Customized Secretary, does it remain hosted?",
    "answer": "No, the program moves off of Customized Secretary and is installed in the rig as usual.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "customized_secretary",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner encounters [Troll](/en/card/06108) with Cyberdelia installed, do they gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "As long as the run reaches step 3.1, then the Runner is considered to have broken all 0 subroutines on Troll.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cyberdelia",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Corp purge virus counters even if there are none in play?",
    "answer": "Yes. Per rule 10.1.1a, the Corp can always use an effect that purges virus counters, even if that effect would not normally be determined to have the potential to change the game state.\n\nWhen the Corp scores Cyberdex Sandbox, does its second ability allow them to trigger its first ability and gain 4[c]?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cyberdex_sandbox",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Cyberdex Virus Suite](/en/card/07027) in the middle of the Runner using [Fermenter](/en/card/30007) to stop them from gaining credits?",
    "answer": "No. Paid abilities can only be used when a player has priority in a paid ability window, not in the middle of resolving another ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cyberdex_virus_suite",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you use the credits hosted on [Cyberfeeder](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/25008) to pay for [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022)’s bypass ability?",
    "answer": "Yes. Since the bypass ability is an optional ability, you are considered to be using the ability. The credits from [Cyberfeeder](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/25008) can be spent to pay for the use of that ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cyberfeeder",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner installs a non-AI icebreaker and then hosts Adjusted Matrix on it, does that icebreaker lose the strength bonus from Cybertrooper Talut?",
    "answer": "No. Cybertrooper Talut only cares whether the program is an AI or not at the time it is installed. Once the strength bonus is applied, the ability does not continue checking the program's subtypes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "cybertrooper_talut",
    "update_date": "2020-03-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "d4v1d",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has both Dadiana Chacon and [Order of Sol](/en/card/06058) installed, can the Runner keep Dadiana Chacon from trashing herself by triggering Order of Sol first?",
    "answer": "No. Although the Runner can trigger Order of Sol first, Dadiana Chacon will still be trashed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dadiana_chacon",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Do the abilities of multiple rezzed [Daily Business Show](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31063) assets stack?",
    "answer": "Yes, each of the interrupt abilities will increase the number of draws for the first draw by 1 each. The ‘when you draw those’ abilities will then also each separately cause you to add 1 card to the bottom of R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "daily_business_show",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nThis card is a reprint. Has anything changed about how Daily Casts works?",
    "answer": "No. The wording was updated to our current style, including using the new \"load\" and \"empty\" keywords, but there are no functional changes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "daily_casts",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use a Daruma that is installed in the root of a central server?",
    "answer": "No. Daruma swaps out a card installed in the same server from which it was trashed. There are no cards installed in central servers, only the inactive cards in the Corp’s hand/deck/discard and the cards installed in the root.\n\nWhat about using Daruma in a remote server to swap something into the root of a central server?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "daruma",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf a Runner with [Doppelgänger](/en/card/02064) uses Data Breach, can he or she choose in which order their effects trigger?",
    "answer": "Both Doppelgänger and Data Breach meet their trigger condition at the same time, so the Runner chooses the order the effects trigger. Once the additional run from either effect has completed, then the other ability triggers and the Runner may initiate another run. Either (a) the Runner chooses to trigger Data Breach first, makes a run on R&D, and then makes an additional run with Doppelgänger’s ability; or (b) the Runner makes an additional run with Doppelgänger’s ability, and then makes an additional run on R&D after that run completes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "data_breach",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner only has 1 card in their grip when they encounter Data Loop, do they have to put that card on top of the stack?",
    "answer": "Yes. As the effect does not stipulate \"if able\", as much of the effect as can be resolved must be resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "data_loop",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Is [Leech](/en/card/30008) a functional reprint of [Datasucker](/en/card/01008)?",
    "answer": "Not quite. Because [Datasucker](/en/card/01008) says that the ice you are encountering must be rezzed, there are some rare encounters where it cannot be used, such as an encounter with an [Archangel](/en/card/09013) being accessed from the Corp’s hand or deck. [Leech](/en/card/30008) can be used even during these encounters.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "datasucker",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 3: Each copy of this card costs 3 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "ddos",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen does the ability from Dean Lister expire if activated outside of a run?",
    "answer": "It expires immediately just like an icebreaker boosting its own strength.\n\nIs the strength increase from Dean Lister locked in at the moment the ability resolves, or does it track the number of cards in the Runner’s grip?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dean_lister",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Death and Taxes trigger when the Runner trashes one of their own cards?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "death_and_taxes",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner plays [Legwork](/en/card/05035) while Dedicated Neural Net is scored and loses the Psi game, does the Corp choose the cards the Runner will access one at a time, or does the Corp choose a set of cards and the Runner accesses them in any order?",
    "answer": "The Corp chooses a set of cards for the runner to access of size equal to the number of cards the Runner will access from HQ, then the Runner accesses them one at a time in the order of the Runner’s choosing.\n\nIf the Corp has scored Dedicated Neural Net and wins the Psi game, what happens when an [Information Sifting](/en/card/10079) run is successful?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dedicated_neural_net",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf Dedicated Processor is hosted on an icebreaker that is hosted on [Baba Yaga](/en/card/11088), does Baba Yaga gain \"2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>: +4 strength.\"?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dedicated_processor",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan Dedication Ceremony be used to place advancement tokens on a rezzed [Haas Arcology AI](/en/card/03011)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Dedicated Ceremony does not specify to put the tokens on a card that can be advanced, and rezzed cards are faceup.\n\nDoes Dedication Ceremony trigger the abilities on public agendas like [Oaktown Renovation](/en/card/08058)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dedication_ceremony",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has 4 unused MU when they play Deep Data Mining, do they access 4 cards or 5 cards from R&D?",
    "answer": "The Runner accesses 5 cards. “Up to” limits the number of additional accesses the Runner can get, not the total number of accesses.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "deep_data_mining",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has more than 2<span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> remaining when they play [Deep Dive](/en/card/33022), can they pay multiple additional <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> to access more than 2 cards?",
    "answer": "No. [Deep Dive](/en/card/33022) grants a single opportunity to pay 1<span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> to access 1 additional card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "deep_dive",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can trash an agenda accessed with Demolition Run, instead of stealing it. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "demolition_run",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen does the Runner choose and resolve the second option for Deuces Wild?",
    "answer": "The Runner does not have to choose which mode to resolve next until the first has finished resolving.\n\nCan the Runner choose the same option on Deuces Wild twice?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "deuces_wild",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Devil Charm to lower the strength of a piece of ice to 0 or less before using Chisel to trash it?",
    "answer": "Yes. Devil Charm and Chisel meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner can choose the order to trigger and resolve the two abilities. Chisel does not check the ice's strength until its ability resolves.\n\nIf the Runner uses Devil Charm to lower the strength of a piece of ice to a negative value during a run made with Prey, can the Runner trash that ice when they pass it? How many cards do they need to trash?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "devil_charm",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDhegdheer's middle ability is worded like a conditional ability that triggers *after* the install action. Does Dhegdheer actually reduce the cost to install programs on it?",
    "answer": "Yes. Interpret the text as if it read \"Lower the install cost of programs you install on Dhegdheer by 1.\"",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dhegdheer",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses Diana's Hunt to install a [Femme Fatale](/en/card/01026) targeting the encountered ice, can they then use Femme Fatale to bypass that ice?",
    "answer": "No. The Femme Fatale was not installed at the time that its trigger condition would have been met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dianas_hunt",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Corp play Digital Rights Management on the first turn of the game?",
    "answer": "No. The \"Play only if…\" restriction is not satisfied, because there is no \"Runner's last turn\" to check as to whether there were any successful runs on HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "digital_rights_management",
    "update_date": "2020-04-15",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If there is an icebreaker already installed on Dinosaurus, the Runner\ncan install a different icebreaker onto Dinosaurus, trashing the\npreviously installed icebreaker. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "dinosaurus",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner has no free MU but a Dinosaurus that is not currently\nhosting an icebreaker, he can install an icebreaker on Dinosaurus\nwithout trashing a program. Declaring where a program is hosted is part of the install action, and so the memory cost of the program\ndoes not need to be taken into account. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "dinosaurus",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nPlaying against Replicating Perfection, can the Runner use Direct Access to run on a remote server if they have not run on any central servers yet that turn?",
    "answer": "Yes. The identities lose their abilities as soon as Direct Access becomes active, before the run begins and the attacked server is declared.\n\nPlaying as Apex, can the Runner use DaVinci to install a non-virtual resource during a Direct Access run?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "direct_access",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses Direct Access to run a remote server against Replicating Perfection, do they have to run a central server to run another remote server?",
    "answer": "Yes. Replicating Perfection must register a central server run when they regain their ability, before a remote server can be attacked.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "direct_access",
    "update_date": "2019-12-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIn what order are the cards added to the bottom of R&D with Disposable HQ?",
    "answer": "In the order of the Corp’s choice. Disposable HQ implicitly gives the choice to the Corp due to being a Corp card effect. ([CBI Raid](/en/card/10022), for example, specifies the choice because it is a Runner card effect.)\n\nDoes Disposable HQ trigger from Archives?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "disposable_hq",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Disrupter cannot be used once the Corp has bid during a trace\nattempt. It must be used when the trace is being initiated, and it\nprevents the entire trace before re-initiating it with a base trace\nstrength of 0. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "disrupter",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf damage is the first time in a turn that a program or hardware is put into the heap, does District 99 gain a power counter?",
    "answer": "Yes. Damage causes cards to be trashed.\n\nIf discarding at the end of the Runner's turn is the first time that turn a program or hardware is put into the heap, does District 99 gain a power counter?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "district_99",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp play Divert Power but choose not to derez or rez any cards?",
    "answer": "Yes. To play Divert Power, it must have the potential to change the game state (via at least one rezzed card that can be derezzed and/or at least one unrezzed card that can be rezzed), but when the operation actually resolves, the Corp does not have to do anything since all of Divert Power's effects are adjustable.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.07).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "divert_power",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Corp use Divested Trust to stop the Runner from winning after stealing their 7th agenda point?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner wins the game while Divested Trust’s ability is still pending.\n\nIf the Corp uses Divested Trust to snatch a 3-point agenda from the Runner, but the Runner steals that agenda again, how much damage does Punitive Counterstrike do?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "divested_trust",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner access upgrades installed in the root of R&D or HQ with Divide and Conquer?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nWhat happens if the Runner uses [The Turning Wheel](/en/card/10085) during a run made with Divide and Conquer?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "divide_and_conquer",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [NISEI Rules Team Update]\nIf the Runner plays Divide and Conquer with an [Aumakua](/en/card/12104) installed, how many times does Aumakua trigger?",
    "answer": "Aumakua will trigger up to three times, once for each server breached with no cards trashed or stolen.\n\nUpdated (2022.05).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "divide_and_conquer",
    "update_date": "2022-06-09",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if [Diviner](/en/card/30046) trashes a card with a play or install cost of 0?",
    "answer": "[Diviner](/en/card/30046) will not end the run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "diviner",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if [Diviner](/en/card/30046) trashes a card with play or install cost of X?",
    "answer": "[Diviner](/en/card/30046) will not end the run. A play or install cost of X is considered to be 0 until the card is played or installed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "diviner",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Diviner](/en/card/30046)’s subroutine require you to trash cards from HQ like [Anoetic Void](/en/card/30050)?",
    "answer": "No. [Diviner](/en/card/30046)’s subroutine is checking the install/play cost of the card that was trashed from the Runner’s grip by the net damage.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "diviner",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan Diwan increase the install cost of an upgrade installed in the root of a central server?",
    "answer": "No. Cards installed in the root of a central server are not in that central server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "diwan",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens if DJ Fenris is flipped facedown by [Apocalypse](/en/card/09030)?",
    "answer": "The identity remains hosted on DJ Fenris but has no effect on the game as it is not active. If DJ Fenris is turned back faceup, it will have the text of the hosted identity again.\n\nWhat happens if DJ Fenris is blanked by [Dr. Lovegood](/en/card/09042)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dj_fenris",
    "update_date": "2022-05-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner cannot move other installed programs to Djinn when it is installed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "djinn",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "When the Runner installs a program, they have the choice of installing it directly into their rig or on Djinn. Thy cannot move programs onto Djinn at a later point. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "djinn",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If breaching HQ is replaced with another effect, such as gaining 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> with [Security Testing](/en/card/31024), will the Runner get the additional access with [Docklands Pass](/en/card/30013) if they make a successful run on HQ again later in the turn?",
    "answer": "Yes. “The first time you breach HQ” refers to a breach actually taking place, not just reaching the “Breach the attacked server.” step of the run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "docklands_pass",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Door to Door give the Runner 1 tag if the trace is unsuccessful or if the runner is not tagged?",
    "answer": "Door to Door does not give the tag if the trace is unsuccessful, but rather only if the trace is successful and the Runner is not tagged.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "door_to_door",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp installs a piece of ice with Drafter's second subroutine, can they force the Runner to approach the new ice by trashing Drafter and/or other ice protecting the attacked server as part of that install?",
    "answer": "No. The new ice must be installed in the outermost position protecting the server. Since the Runner already has a position relative to the other ice protecting the server, the new ice will necessarily have a position outward from the Runner. Trashing multiple ice does not allow new ice to \"leapfrog\" the Runner's position, but just moves the Runner 1 position toward the server for each trashed piece of ice that was inward from their earlier position.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "drafter",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner is resolving DreamNet's ability, but they are unable to draw a card because their stack is empty or the Corp resolved the subroutine on Lockdown, do they still gain a credit?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as they meet one of the specified conditions of having a digital identity or at least 2[link]. The second sentence of the ability is not in any way dependent on the effects of the first sentence. The word \"also\" is used only to make clear that both sentences are part of the same ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dreamnet",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp trashes a [NetChip](/en/card/10024) hosting a program, can the Runner trash a program from grip to use Dummy Box to save the hosted program?",
    "answer": "No. The program hosted on NetChip is trashed by the hosting rules and not by the Corp. Trashing hosted cards when the host is uninstalled cannot be prevented.\n\nIf the first subroutine on [Conundrum](/en/card/12120) resolves, can the Runner use Dummy Box to save the chosen program?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dummy_box",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If I have multiple [DZMZ Optimizer](/en/card/30022)s installed, do their discounts stack?",
    "answer": "Yes. If you have 2 [DZMZ Optimizer](/en/card/30022)s installed, you will pay 2[c] less to install your first program each turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "dzmz_optimizer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "e3 Feedback Implants triggers itself, so the Runner can break all\nsubroutines on a **bioroid** ice by paying credits after spending a\nsingle click. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "e3_feedback_implants",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If multiple subroutines are broken at the same time, e3 Feedback\nImplants triggers once for each subroutine. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "e3_feedback_implants",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if there is more than one remote server when an effect disabling Earth Station's \"Limit 1 remote server.\" ability (such as Employee Strike or Direct Access) ends?",
    "answer": "The game state is now illegal, so in the next checkpoint after Earth Station's ability becomes active again, the Corp must choose exactly 1 remote server they will keep. The game trashes all cards in and protecting all other remote servers. This trashing cannot be prevented.\n\nWhat happens if the previous situation occurs while Architect is rezzed protecting a remote server?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "earth_station_sea_headquarters",
    "update_date": "2020-04-16",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner access Archives after using Eater, all cards are turned\nfaceup but no individual cards are accessed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "eater",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner prevent the Eavesdrop trace with [Hunting Grounds](/en/card/09035)?",
    "answer": "No. Hunting Grounds prevents \"when encountered\" abilities on ice, and the trace ability from Eavesdrop is on a condition counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "eavesdrop",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Echo](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33035) get a power counter from itself?",
    "answer": "Yes. When [Echo](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33035) is rezzed, it becomes active before the checkpoint in which its own ability’s trigger condition is met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "echo",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the first operation Edward Kim accesses is in Archives, then he\ncannot trash another operation with his ability that turn. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "edward_kim_humanitys_hammer",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If an ice with a hosted [Egret](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31032) is derezzed, does the ice still gain the subtypes from [Egret](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31032)?",
    "answer": "Yes, facedown corp cards still have subtypes as normal and [Egret](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31032) still grants the subtypes <b>sentry</b>, <b>code gate</b> and <b>barrier</b> to the ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "egret",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The memory limit from Ekomind is modified by other card abilities\n(e.g. a Runner with 5 cards in his or her grip and an [Akamatsu Mem Chip](/en/card/01038) installed has 6<span class=\"icon icon-mu\"></span>). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "ekomind",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhat does the parenthetical \"(minimum of 1)\" mean on Election Day?",
    "answer": "The text \"(minimum of 1)\" prohibits the Corp from playing Election Day unless at least one card is trashed by its effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "election_day",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [Emergency Shutdown](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31016) on their second click after they ran HQ with an active [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) that was trashed during the breach?",
    "answer": "No, the Runner did not make a successful run on HQ due to [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079)’s ability. Trashing [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) does not retroactively make the run successful.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "emergency_shutdown",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner trash a mix of programs and hardware to Emergent Creativity?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "emergent_creativity",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp rez any pieces of ice after the Runner uses EMP Device if the Corp has already rezzed ice during the run?",
    "answer": "Yes, EMP Device only restricts how much ice the Corp can rez from the time it is used until the end of the run.\n\nAfter the Runner uses EMP Device, the Corp rezzes [Howler](/en/card/03016). Can Howler’s subroutine still install a bioroid behind itself? Is the Howler still trashed?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "emp_device",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner starts their turn with [Out of the Ashes](/en/card/10080) in their heap and Emptied Mind installed, does the Runner still gain <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> if during the run from Out of the Ashes they discard all the cards in grip to using Faust?",
    "answer": "Yes, Emptied Mind checks the number of cards in grip when its ability resolves. If other simultaneous effects are triggered before Emptied Mind, then the check will wait until those effects are fully resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "emptied_mind",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [En Passant](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31003) to trash a piece of ice that was passed while rezzed and then subsequently derezzed, such as by playing [Emergency Shutdown](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31016)?",
    "answer": "Yes. [En Passant](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31003) only cares about the current rezzed or unrezzed status of its target and whether it was passed during the Runner’s last run, not whether it happened to be rezzed at any point during that run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "en_passant",
    "update_date": "2022-04-22",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner play two Encores on the same turn?",
    "answer": "If the Runner has enough clicks in a single turn to run successfully on R&D, HQ, and Archives then play two Encores, then the Runner takes two additional turns after that one.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "encore",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Endless Hunger can only break subroutines that read exactly “<span class=\"icon icon-subroutine\"></span> End\nthe run.” It cannot break subroutines that use the words “end the\nrun” as only part of its effect, e.g. on [Tsurugi](/en/card/04074) or [Pop-up Window](/en/card/02056). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "endless_hunger",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How big is *[Endurance](/en/card/33025)* compared to the ships depicted on [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057)?",
    "answer": "There are two tanker ships in the foreground of [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) with large white cylindrical tanks. *[Endurance](/en/card/33025)* is about one-twelfth the length of those ships, smaller than the radius of one of the tanks.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "endurance",
    "update_date": "2022-09-21",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan Enforcing Loyalty be used to trash installed Corp cards?",
    "answer": "Yes. There are no Corp cards that have factions that match the factions of Runner identities.\n\nDo neutral cards match the faction of any Runner's identity?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "enforcing_loyalty",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp uses Marcus Batty to resolve a subroutine with Engram Flush, can they trash a card from the grip?",
    "answer": "If an encounter with Engram Flush is in progress and its conditional ability has resolved, the Corp can trash a card of the chosen type, regardless of whether the subroutine is resolving due to the normal progression of a run or because of a card ability. If a subroutine on Engram Flush resolves outside of an encounter with it, or during an encounter in which no card type was chosen (perhaps due to Hunting Grounds's first ability), the Corp only reveals the grip and cannot trash anything.\n\nIf the Corp is playing Harishchandra Ent. and the Runner is tagged, can the Corp reveal the grip and trash a card with Engram Flush?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "engram_flush",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The revealed card is no longer revealed during the access phase; it\nimmediately returns to its unrevealed state after the Corp shows the\ncard to the Runner. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "enhanced_vision",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes a piece of ice (such as [Envelopment](/en/card/33060)) while the Runner is encountering it, then installs a new piece of ice protecting the same server with [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057), where is the Runner’s position relative to the newly installed ice?",
    "answer": "The Runner is inward from the new ice, so they will not approach it. When ice is uninstalled during a run, the Runner and all ice protecting the server immediately “collapse” their positions toward the root of the server. Ice cannot “jump in front of ” the Runner by trashing and installing midrun.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "envelopment",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp look at the cards that are being trashed while resolving sabotage?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp must choose which cards to trash first, and then all cards are trashed simultaneously. The Corp can look at the trashed cards from R&D in Archives after all trashes from sabotage have been resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "esa_afontov_eco_insurrectionist",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp has only 1 card in HQ and must sabotage 2, can they choose to “trash 2 cards from HQ” in order to only trash the 1 card in HQ?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp must trash 2 cards if possible. The Corp must trash the remaining card from R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "esa_afontov_eco_insurrectionist",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp has only 1 card in R&D and must sabotage 2, can they choose to “trash 2 cards from R&D” in order to only trash the 1 card in R&D?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp must trash 2 cards if possible. The Corp must trash the remaining card from HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "esa_afontov_eco_insurrectionist",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What if the Corp has only 1 card total in HQ and R&D and must sabotage 2?",
    "answer": "The Corp trashes all cards from HQ and R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "esa_afontov_eco_insurrectionist",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner gain a credit when they sabotage and have [Demolisher](/en/card/26002) installed?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp is trashing the cards when resolving a sabotage effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "esa_afontov_eco_insurrectionist",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf Estelle Moon has 3 power counters, does the Corp draw 1 card and gain 6<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> or draw 3 cards and gain 6<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "The latter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "estelle_moon",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can install the card even if they cannot lower\nthe install cost by 10 credits (the “if able” only refers to the install\naction). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "eureka",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes the Runner gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for the played copy of Exclusive Party?",
    "answer": "No. Events are not trashed until they finish resolving.\n\nDoes \"Limit 6 per deck.\" apply during a draft?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "exclusive_party",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the trace for the subroutine on Executive Functioning need to be successful to do the brain damage?",
    "answer": "Yes. Interpret the text as if it said \"If successful\".",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "executive_functioning",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "answer": "No. It is assumed that the Corp's deck is legal, and the influence value on the card is irrelevant for the purposes of gameplay.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp no longer has enough cards in their deck to satisfy the Alliance requirement for a card due to cards being removed from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "executive_search_firm",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner steals an agenda with their first R&D access and uses [Pantograph](/en/card/30023) to install [eXer](/en/card/21041), can they access another card?",
    "answer": "No. The limit to how many cards the Runner can access from R&D is determined at the beginning of breaching R&D. If an ability that would modify a breach, such as [eXer](/en/card/21041)’s ability, becomes active after the Runner has accessed a card, then it is too late to affect that breach.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "exer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhat happens if the Runner has no installed cards or no credits when encountering Fairchild 1.0?",
    "answer": "When one of Fairchild 1.0's subroutines resolves, the Runner must follow the instructions to the extent that they are able. So if they have no credits, they will need to trash an installed card. If they have no installed cards, they will be forced to pay a credit. If they have neither credits nor installed cards, they will not be able to fulfill the instruction at all, so the subroutine does nothing.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fairchild_1_0",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has exactly 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when Fairchild 2.0’s first subroutine resolves, what happens? What if the Runner has no installed cards?",
    "answer": "The Runner must choose an option they are able to fulfill if possible. If they don’t have 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>, they must trash an installed card. If the Runner doesn’t have any installed cards, they can’t fulfill either option, so they get to keep their 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fairchild_2_0",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "False Lead cannot be forfeited unless the Runner can lose 2 clicks. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "false_lead",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp can forfeit 2 copies of False Lead at 1.1 to force the Runner\nto lose 4 clicks. The turn advances to the Runner’s discard phase\nafter 1.2 resolves and the Runner has no clicks. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "false_lead",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nThis card is a reprint. Has anything changed about how False Lead works?",
    "answer": "No. The original wording of False Lead used an “if able” clause to accomplish the same thing as the condition in the new wording, but we feel that the new wording is much clearer.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "false_lead",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Corp plays Fast Break, do they draw cards until either they have drawn X cards or they wish to stop? What about for the installs?",
    "answer": "The Corp must decide how many cards they will draw (any number from 0 to X), then draw that many cards. They cannot see the cards as they draw them, then use this information to decide when to stop drawing. The same is true for the installs; first the Corp decides how many cards they will install, then they install that many cards one at a time.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.07).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fast_break",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 3: Each copy of this card costs 3 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "faust",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen does the Runner reveal extra copies of Fear the Masses to force the Corp to trash additional cards?",
    "answer": "The Runner reveals the other copies during the access cards step (4.5) before any cards have been trashed from Fear the Masses' effect.\n\nDoes \"Limit 6 per deck.\" apply during a draft?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fear_the_masses",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022) need to match strength to use its bypass ability?",
    "answer": "No, the bypass ability does not have an interface flag, so there is no prerequisite of matching the strength of the encountered ice in order to use that ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "femme_fatale",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you use the credits hosted on [Cyberfeeder](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/25008) to pay for [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022)’s bypass ability?",
    "answer": "Yes. Since the bypass ability is an optional ability, you are considered to be using the ability. The credits from [Cyberfeeder](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/25008) can be spent to pay for the use of that ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "femme_fatale",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022) is reinstalled, can the ice chosen when [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022) was first installed be bypassed with [Femme Fatale](31022)’s ability?",
    "answer": "No, the choice of ice is only retained for as long as [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022) is installed. When it is uninstalled, the choice is forgotten. When you reinstall [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022), it can only bypass the ice chosen during its most recent installation.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "femme_fatale",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When an ice chosen for [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022)'s ability is uninstalled, can it be bypassed with [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022)'s ability after it has been reinstalled later in the game?",
    "answer": "No. The newly installed ice is a different game object than the originally installed ice. The chosen ice in [Femme Fatale](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31022)’s ability only applies to the original object, which doesn’t exist anymore.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "femme_fatale",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat are the applicable uses for credits on Fencer Fueno other than trashing accessed cards? Can the Runner use the credits to break the subroutine when accessing Archangel?",
    "answer": "Once a run becomes successful, the credits on Fencer Fueno become available for the Runner to spend for any purpose until that run ends. The Runner can feel free to spend the credits on anything as if they were in their credit pool, including but not limited to the trace from Ash 2X3ZB9CY, the psi game from The Future Perfect, or even using a Self-Modifying Code during an access encounter with Archangel.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fencer_fueno",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Cyberdex Virus Suite](/en/card/07027) in the middle of the Runner using [Fermenter](/en/card/30007) to stop them from gaining credits?",
    "answer": "No. Paid abilities can only be used when a player has priority in a paid ability window, not in the middle of resolving another ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fermenter",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner must pay the 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> to steal Fetal AI from Archives. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "fetal_ai",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "After Film Critic’s ‘when accessed’ ability resolves, any remaining\n‘when accessed’ abilities are non-resolvable. [Official FAQ] [So for example, [Fetal AI](/en/card/02032)'s 2 net damage does not trigger.]",
    "card_codename": "film_critic",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "An agenda hosted on Film Critic is not considered to be stolen. An\nagenda added to the score area from Film Critic is not considered to\nbe stolen. [Official FAQ] [At neither step does the Runner have to pay the credit cost for [Fetal AI](/en/card/02032) or [NAPD Contract](/en/card/04119), or 'play the psi game' on [The Future Perfect](/en/card/05007). Also, neither step satisfies the requirement to play [Midseason Replacements](/en/card/02116) or [Punitive Counterstrike](/en/card/04079).]",
    "card_codename": "film_critic",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner cannot voluntarily trash an agenda hosted on Film\nCritic, even if the Runner accesses another agenda. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "film_critic",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Film Critic can only host an agenda through its ‘when accessed’\nability. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "film_critic",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp play Financial Collapse while there are no installed resources?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nThe Runner is playing [Armand \"Geist\" Walker](/en/card/08063), and [Fall Guy](/en/card/04106) and [Tech Trader](/en/card/10023) are the only installed resources. If the Corp plays Financial Collapse, can Geist attempt to trash Tech Trader for Financial Collapse, then prevent the trash with Fall Guy? What happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "financial_collapse",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf Adam starts the game with Find the Truth in play, does the Runner reveal his or her starting hand to the Corp?",
    "answer": "No. The directives start the game installed, but during set up they are not active.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "find_the_truth",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner choose to look at the top card of R&D with [Find the Truth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/11047) before using [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Both abilities meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner chooses the order to resolve them.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "find_the_truth",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use credits hosted on Flame-out to pay the install cost from using Self-Modifying Code?",
    "answer": "No. Paying a program's install cost is not using that program, and Self-Modifying Code is no longer hosted on Flame-out when the program is being installed, so neither card can meet the requirements to use credits from Flame-out.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "flame_out",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Flashbang have to match the strength of a sentry in order to derez it?",
    "answer": "Yes. Derezzing is a form of interacting with a piece of ice, and icebreakers must match strength to interact with ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "flashbang",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the Runner still have to pay the additional cost from Port Anson Grid if they use Flip Switch to jack out from a run on its server?",
    "answer": "Yes. When the ability on Flip Switch resolves, the Runner must trash a program to jack out. If they do not trash a program, they do not jack out.\n\nDoes the third ability on Flip Switch trigger Armand “Geist” Walker?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "flip_switch",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nHow does Flower Sermon interact with Daily Business Show?",
    "answer": "If Flower Sermon's ability is the first time the Corp would draw cards in a turn, and no other relevant effects apply, then the Corp reveals the top card of R&D, then looks at the top 3 cards of R&D. They put one of those 3 cards on the bottom of R&D and draw the other 2. Finally, they put a card from HQ (which could be one of the drawn cards or another card) on top of R&D.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp uses Jinja City Grid to reveal and install all the cards they would draw while resolving Flower Sermon's ability?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "flower_sermon",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Corp have to pay the rez cost of ice rezzed due to [Forged Activation Orders](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31017)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Install, rez, and play costs must always be paid, as well as any additional costs that apply, unless the ability that allows a player to install, rez, or play a card specifically says otherwise.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "forged_activation_orders",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp rez [Akitaro Watanabe](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/01079) in response to Forged Activation Orders?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp cannot rez [Akitaro Watanabe](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/01079) in response to a [Forged Activation Orders](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31017) being played. The effect of [Forged Activation Orders](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31017) is immediately resolved unless prevented or avoided.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "forged_activation_orders",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp rez and move more than one Formicary per run?",
    "answer": "Yes. Although forcing the Runner into a Formicary negates the trigger for any additional Formicaries, the next thing the Runner does after passing the first Formicary is approach the server a second time. At that point the Corp could use a second Formicary, and even a third afterward in similar fashion.\n\nHow does Formicary interact with [Mti Mwekundu](/en/card/21114)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "formicary",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner encounters a [Troll](/en/card/06108) protecting a server with Fractal Threat Matrix, do they trash the top 2 cards of their stack?",
    "answer": "If Troll's \"when encountered\" ability ends the run, then the Runner will not have reached step 3.1 of the run and thus will not have had the chance to break any subroutines. If Troll does not end the run, the Runner is considered to have broken all 0 subroutines on Troll, thus triggering Fractal Threat Matrix.\n\nThe Runner encounters an [Ashigaru](/en/card/06064) protecting HQ, and the Corp has [Panic Button](/en/card/04072) and Fractal Threat Matrix installed. Each time the Runner breaks all the remaining subroutines on Ashigaru, the Corp uses Panic Button to add another subroutine to Ashigaru. Does Fractal Threat Matrix trigger each tim eht Runner breaks the added subroutines?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fractal_threat_matrix",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses [Paige Piper](/en/card/08002) to find and trash the other copies of the card installed by Frantic Coding, are the rest of the cards looked at still trashed?",
    "answer": "No. Paige Piper interrupts the resolution of Frantic Coding, and as a search effect it shuffles the stack. After this, the cards that were looked at can no longer be confirmed and referenced, so the rest of Frantic Coding’s ability fails to resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "frantic_coding",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan Freedom Khumalo trash accessed agendas?",
    "answer": "No. Agendas do not have rez or play costs.\n\nIf the Runner wishes to trash a card with a rez or play cost of 0 with Freedom Khumalo, can they still do so if they have no virus counters or no installed cards at all?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "freedom_khumalo_crypto_anarchist",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIs \"Freedom Through Equality\" trashed while in the score area if another current is played or an agenda is scored?",
    "answer": "No. \"Freedom Through Equality\" is added to the Runner's score area as a blank agenda worth 1 agenda point. Additionally, agendas in the Runner's score area are not active.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "freedom_through_equality",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like Friends in High Places work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays Friends in High Places as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "friends_in_high_places",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp has one remote server with ice protecting it and a card installed in it, how many times does the ability resolve?",
    "answer": "Twice. The ability resolves once, then it is repeated for the one matching remote server.\n\nHow many times does NASX trigger while resolving Fully Operational?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fully_operational",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner loses the psi game from [Caprice Nisei](/en/card/04114) while Fumiko Yamamori is rezzed, does the Runner take meat damage before or after the run ends?",
    "answer": "After. The run ending is a constant effect from the result of the secretly spent credits being revealed, so it must be immediately resolved before any abilities triggered from the secretly spent credits being revealed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "fumiko_yamamori",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner stop [Funhouse](/en/card/30054) from ending the run by choosing to take the tag and then preventing it?",
    "answer": "No. The “unless” in [Funhouse](/en/card/30054)’s ability indicates a nested cost. If the Runner does not take a tag, the cost is not paid and [Funhouse](/en/card/30054) will end the run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "funhouse",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Runner has a mandatory ability that would prevent the tag from [Funhouse](/en/card/30054), such as the ability on [Jesminder Sareen: Girl Behind the Curtain](/en/card/10006)?",
    "answer": "Players cannot attempt to pay a cost that would be prevented. If *Jesminder*’s ability is applicable, the Runner must choose to end the run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "funhouse",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Inside Job](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31018) and bypasses [Funhouse](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30054) or [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066), do the non-subroutine abilities on those cards resolve?",
    "answer": "No. An ability that meets its trigger condition due to an encounter beginning can only resolve if the encounter is still taking place. [Inside Job](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31018)’s bypass ability meets its trigger condition at the same time as [Funhouse](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30054) or [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066)’s ability, and as it’s the Runner’s turn, they will resolve the ability they control first. Bypassing a piece of ice immediately ends the encounter, stopping the Corp from resolving their ability before they can tag the Runner or charge a toll.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "funhouse",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nAre cards set aside with Gachapon still on top of the stack? What happens if another effect moves or shuffles cards within the stack while Gachapon is resolving?",
    "answer": "Cards that are set aside are in their own zone and are no longer in their previous location. See the notes on the set-aside zone, above. Other effects that manipulate the stack cannot affect the cards from Gachapon while they are set aside.\n\nHow do set-aside cards interact with Paige Piper?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "gachapon",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can decline to pay the 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> to access a card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "gagarin_deep_space_expanding_the_horizon",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan an ability meet GameNET's trigger condition if it tries to make the Runner spend or lose credits, but the Runner doesn't have any credits to spend or lose?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner must actually lose or spend at least 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for the Corp to be able to trigger GameNET. For simplicity, we'll assume the Runner is able to spend at least 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for the rest of these GameNET questions.\n\nDoes the \"pay credits\" option on abilities like one of Fairchild 1.0's subroutines meet GameNET's trigger condition?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "gamenet_where_dreams_are_real",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp uses Ganked! to make the Runner to encounter a piece of ice, does the Runner's position move back to that ice?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner is still accessing cards while they are being forced to encounter the ice. However, they are no longer accessing Ganked! itself, because Ganked! is trashed as part of resolving its ability. When the forced encounter ends, resolving Ganked!'s ability is complete, and the game proceeds with the remaining accesses from the set of cards being accessed.\n\nWhat happens if an \"end the run\" effect resolves during an encounter created by Ganked!?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ganked",
    "update_date": "2020-04-15",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Karunā](30047)’s first subroutine resolves while the Runner is already breaching the attacked server (perhaps because of [Ganked!](26119)), can the Runner still jack out? Does that stop them from accessing any more cards?",
    "answer": "Yes and yes. Nothing stops the Runner from jacking out at unusual times if given the opportunity by a card ability. Jacking out ends the run, which ends any breach in progress as well.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ganked",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner is able to uninstall and reinstall the same Gauss in a single turn, will it have +6 strength that turn?",
    "answer": "No. Whenever a card becomes uninstalled, it becomes a new copy of itself without any memory of its previous state.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "gauss",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nHow exactly does Gebrselassie's ability affect the host icebreaker?",
    "answer": "Gebrselassie replaces any instance of an icebreaker resetting to base strength at the end of an encounter with resetting at the end of the turn. This includes the basic rule applied to any strength boost that does not specify a duration, as well as any strength boost that specifies the end of an encounter explicitly (such as [Takobi](/en/card/21026)). Gebrselassie does not have any effect on abilities that continuously modify strength (like [Na'Not'K](/en/card/12088)) or abilities that modify the strength of the host icebreaker for a different specified duration.\n\nSo how does Gebrselassie interact with a card like [Dean Lister](/en/card/13025)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "gebrselassie",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Corp’s trace strength is 5 or greater, Gemini does 1 net damage even if the trace was unsuccessful. [Official FAQ, listed under Taurus' ruling]",
    "card_codename": "gemini",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp move Georgia Emelyov to a new remote server?",
    "answer": "No. Georgia Emelyov must be moved to another server that already exists. New remote servers can only be made during installations.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "georgia_emelyov",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf Giordano Memorial Field ends the run, is the run considered successful or unsuccessful?",
    "answer": "After a run has been declared successful, it cannot be made unsuccessful.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.07).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "giordano_memorial_field",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Glenn Station is forfeited, any card hosted on it is trashed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "glenn_station",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Glenn Station can only host a card through its click ability. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "glenn_station",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens when a run initiated by Glut Cipher is successful and there are fewer than 5 cards in Archives?",
    "answer": "The Runner does not access any cards. The Corp does not add any cards from Archives to HQ nor trash any cards from HQ.\n\nWhich player trashes the random cards from HQ? Does this trashing trigger effects like [Hostile Infrastructure](/en/card/06083)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "glut_cipher",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner avoid the tag from God of War and still get the virus counters?",
    "answer": "No, taking the tag is a cost to placing the virus counters on God of War. If the tag is avoided, the cost hasn't been paid and the counters do not get placed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "god_of_war",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner breaks both subroutines on Gold Farmer with a single ability, such as Paperclip's ability, how many credits do they lose?",
    "answer": "The Runner will lose 2[c]. Gold Farmer's trigger condition is met for each subroutine that is broken, regardless of which or how many abilities are used to break them.\n\nIf the Runner breaks both subroutines on Gold Farmer by using Corroder's ability twice, and then trashes Gold Farmer with Hippo, do they still lose 2[c]?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "gold_farmer",
    "update_date": "2020-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Golden to derez [Troll](/en/card/06108)?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner cannot use Golden to break any subroutines on Troll, so the usage requirement for Golden has no way of being satisfied.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "golden",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the expose effect is prevented, can the Runner still trash GPI Net Tap to jack out?",
    "answer": "Yes. Each effect is separate from the other. \"Then\" does not imply any conditionality to the expose effect, it only indicates the order of resolution.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "gpi_net_tap",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner play Guinea Pig when it is the only card left in the grip?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nIf the Runner plays Guinea Pig with [Dadiana Chacon](/en/card/12049) installed and exactly 4<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> in their credit pool, does the Runner flatline?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "guinea_pig",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Runner has Guru Davinder and [Net Shield](/en/card/01045) installed when they suffer 1 net damage. Can they choose to use Net Shield, or are they forced to use Guru Davinder because his ability is constant versus Net Shield's paid ability? What if the Runner suffers 1 meat damage while Guru Davinder and [Muresh Bodysuit](/en/card/02044) are both installed (as they are both constant)?",
    "answer": "Guru Davinder prevents all net or meat damage, leaving nothing left for the Runner to use Net Shield on. In the case of Guru Davinder and Muresh Bodysuit, simultaneous triggers on cards are resolved in the order of their owner's choosing.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "guru_davinder",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Haas-Bioroid: Architects of Tomorrow](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/11072) meet its trigger condition if the Runner trashes an encountered bioroid?",
    "answer": "No. [Haas-Bioroid: Architects of Tomorrow](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/11072) requires the Runner to pass a rezzed piece of ice in order to meet its trigger condition, and the trashed ice is neither rezzed nor unrezzed. Consequently, the ability is still available to meet its trigger condition later in the same turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "haas_bioroid_architects_of_tomorrow",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses a card ability to rez [Hákarl 1.0](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33036) at a time other than while the Runner is approaching it, will they be able to use its ability?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Corp can use the ability as long as there is a run in progress and [Hákarl 1.0](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33036) is protecting the attacked server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hakarl_1_0",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp choose an installed piece of ice for Hangeki?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nSo if the Corp chooses an installed [Archangel](/en/card/09013) for Hangeki, the Runner could encounter it if they do not take the -1 agenda point?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hangeki",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Is [Hansei Review](/en/card/30048) a card in HQ while its own ability is resolving?",
    "answer": "No. Operations and events are placed into the play area before they begin to resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hansei_review",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like Hard-Hitting News work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays Hard-Hitting News as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hard_hitting_news",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf a tagged Runner is damaged while playing against Harischandra Ent., how is the damage resolved?",
    "answer": "Damage is still random. In practice, the Runner should hide and shuffle their grip, suffer damage as normal, then reveal their grip again.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "harishchandra_ent_where_you_re_the_star",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner play Harmony AR Therapy if there are no cards in their stack?",
    "answer": "Yes. Harmony AR Therapy removes itself from the game, so it always has the potential to change the game state. In this case, the Runner will shuffle the cards found by the search to form their new stack.\n\nCan the Runner play Harmony AR Therapy if there are no cards in their heap?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "harmony_ar_therapy",
    "update_date": "2020-03-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes the Runner have to discard before or after drawing 3 cards from Harvester?",
    "answer": "Resolve the text of each subroutine in the order it appears. First the Runner draws 3 cards, then they must discard to their maximum hand size.\n\nIf the Runner does not draw 3 cards due to Harvester’s subroutine effect, must they still discard cards?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "harvester",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan Hatchet Job add a Corp card to the Runner's grip?",
    "answer": "No, cards can only be added to hands and decks belonging to their owner.\n\nCan Hatchet Job add a facedown virtual card to the Runner's grip?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hatchet_job",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use a Helheim Servers installed in the root of HQ if there is no ice protecting HQ?",
    "answer": "No. The effect does not have the potential to cause a change in the game state, so it cannot be used.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "helheim_servers",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner accesses a card and then later trashes it outside of an access (e.g. with [Political Operative](/en/card/10043)), can the Corp play Hellion Beta Test on the next turn?",
    "answer": "No, Hellion Beta Test’s condition requires a card to have been trashed while it was being accessed.\n\nIf the Runner trashed only one Corp card on their last turn and subsequently used [Salsette Slums](/en/card/10059) to remove that card from the game, can the Corp still play Hellion Beta Test?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hellion_beta_test",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner is tagged and breaks more than one subroutine with a single ability (e.g. with [Berserker](/en/card/12041)), how many credits does the Corp gain?",
    "answer": "The Corp gains 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for each subroutine broken.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "henry_phillips",
    "update_date": "2017-05-26",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "answer": "No. It is assumed that the Corp's deck is legal, and the influence value on the card is irrelevant for the purposes of gameplay.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp no longer has enough cards in their deck to satisfy the Alliance requirement for a card due to cards being removed from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "heritage_committee",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf a piece of ice will gain a subroutine from an effect like [Sensei](/en/card/02034) or [Komainu](/en/card/05017), does that subroutine factor into the additional cost for Hernando Cortez as well?",
    "answer": "No. Those effects cause the next piece of ice encountered to gain a subroutine, but ice is rezzed during the approach.\n\nHow many credits is the additional cost incurred for rezzing a piece of ice with flexible subroutines while Hernando Cortez's ability is active (such as [NEXT Silver](/en/card/06002), [Ashigaru](/en/card/06064), [Tour Guide](/en/card/08118), etc.)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hernando_cortez",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "#### UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen does High-Stakes Job trigger?",
    "answer": "High-Stakes Job triggers as soon as a successful run ends, similar to [Dirty Laundry](/en/card/03052) or [Doppelgänger](/en/card/02064)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "high_stakes_job",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner trash [Mirāju](/en/card/12071) with Hippo? If they do, are they moved to Archives?",
    "answer": "Yes, Hippo can be used after breaking the subroutine on Mirāju, and the Runner will not be moved to Archives. Mirāju's ability checks whether the Runner broke its printed subroutine at the time they would pass it (Step 4 of the run). Since Hippo's ability triggers as soon as all subroutines are broken (in step 3.1), Mirāju is no longer active in order to replace passing with moving to Archives.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hippo",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose the Runner has [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) and [Hivemind](/en/card/07042) installed, with 1 virus counter on [Hivemind](/en/card/07042). If they then install [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017), is the host ice derezzed immediately? Or does it wait for the next check at the beginning of the Runner's next turn?",
    "answer": "By managing their abilities carefully, the Runner can choose whether to derez the ice right away or not. [Hivemind](/en/card/07042)’s second ability is a static ability, so it always applies as soon as [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) is installed. But the conditional abilities on [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) and [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner can choose the order to resolve them. If they resolve [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) first, it will only have 2 hosted virus counters (including the one shared from [Hivemind](/en/card/07042)) at the time that the number of counters is checked. If they resolve [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) first, then by the time [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) resolves, it will have 3 hosted virus counters and will derez the ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hivemind",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the trace for the subroutine on Holmegaard need to be successful to stop the Runner from accessing cards?",
    "answer": "Yes. Interpret the text as if it said \"If successful\".",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "holmegaard",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if the Runner plays Rebirth to switch their identity with Hoshiko Shiro?",
    "answer": "Hoshiko enters play with her Untold Protagonist side faceup.\n\nIf the Runner runs a server with no cards in it, does Hoshiko Shiro: Untold Protagonist flip at the end of the turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hoshiko_shiro_untold_protagonist",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Hostile Infrastructure does not resolve when the Corp trashes his or\nher cards, even as a result of a Runner ability (e.g. [Noise](/en/card/01001) forcing the Corp to trash the top card of R&D). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "hostile_infrastructure",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Hostile Infrastructure and any other Corp cards are trashed\nsimultaneously, Hostile Infrastructure will trigger for each\ncard trashed and do 1 net damage that many times. [Official FAQ/Updated for clarity Oct. 2019] [Relevant if playing [Apocalypse](/en/card/09030).]",
    "card_codename": "hostile_infrastructure",
    "update_date": "2019-10-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner has 1 card in his or her grip and installs it,\nHousekeeping has no effect and does not prevent the install. (Only\nforced trashing through damage can result in a flatline.) [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "housekeeping",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The prevent ability on Hunting Grounds is optional; because it can\nonly be triggered “once per turn” it is the Runner’s choice as to when\nto trigger it. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "hunting_grounds",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf Hyoubu Precog Manifold ends the run, is the run still successful?",
    "answer": "Yes. Once the run is declared successful, it can't stop being successful. The Runner just won't access cards if the run ends before they have the chance.\n\nIf the Runner makes a run using Sneakdoor Beta while Hyoubu Precog Manifold is active, and the chosen server is HQ, can Hyoubu Precog Manifold's ability resolve?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hyoubu_precog_manifold",
    "update_date": "2020-04-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Rigging Up](/en/card/33024) to put an extra counter on [Hyperbaric](/en/card/33026)?",
    "answer": "Yes. [Hyperbaric](/en/card/33026)’s “when you install” ability resolves in between the instruction from [Rigging Up](/en/card/33024) that installs it and the instruction that gives the option to charge it. By the time the latter instruction resolves, [Hyperbaric](/en/card/33026) has a hosted power counter and is legal to charge.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hyperbaric",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan Hyperloop Extension's ability be resolved by cards like [Bifrost Array](/en/card/06081) and [24/7 News Cycle](/en/card/09019)?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.07).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "hyperloop_extension",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner trashes all cards from the damage before drawing for\nI’ve Had Worse. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "i_ve_had_worse",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "I’ve Had Worse cannot prevent the Runner from being flatlined if\nthe Runner takes more damage than the number of cards in their grip. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "i_ve_had_worse",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Iain Stirling has a negative agenda point total, then he has fewer\nagenda points than a Corp with 0 or more agenda points. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "iain_stirling_retired_spook",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "answer": "No. It is assumed that the Corp's deck is legal, and the influence value on the card is irrelevant for the purposes of gameplay.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp no longer has enough cards in their deck to satisfy the Alliance requirement for a card due to cards being removed from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ibrahim_salem",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Ice Carver](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31009) apply its -1 strength before or after [Chisel](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/26003)’s ability resolves?",
    "answer": "Before. [Ice Carver](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31009) has a static ability, which means it applies as soon as the encounter begins. The Runner doesn’t have to trigger the ability explicitly or wait for conditional abilities to resolve before it takes effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ice_carver",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses credits from [Flame-out](/en/card/21109) to use Ika, and then moves Ika off of Flame-out, is Ika still trashed at the end of the turn?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.06).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ika",
    "update_date": "2022-06-21",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the Corp take a bad publicity if the Runner trashes an unrezzed Illegal Arms Factory?",
    "answer": "No. The ability is not active if Illegal Arms Factory is not active. The phrase \"while it is installed\" is just a reminder and does not functionally change the ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "illegal_arms_factory",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is [Imp](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31007)’s ability written differently than in previous printings?",
    "answer": "The previous wording for [Imp](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31007) and similar cards did not fit into any of the modern ability types that the CR supports, and it was not clear exactly when it could be used. The new “Access →“ flag lets this type of ability be written as a paid ability and gives it clear timing and structure.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "imp",
    "update_date": "2022-04-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner avoids a tag from Increased Drop rate, can the Corp still remove bad publicity?",
    "answer": "Since “unless” designates taking a tag as a nested cost (rule 1.15.10b) and costs cannot be avoided (rule 1.15.1a), the tag cannot be avoided.\n\nIf the Corp does not have any bad publicity when the Runner accesses Increased Drop Rates, is the Runner forced to take a tag?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "increased_drop_rates",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes “out-of-faction” refer to cards not belonging to the Corp’s identity faction or to cards not belonging to Weyland?",
    "answer": "Out-of-faction refers to cards that do not belong to the faction of the Corp’s identity.\n\nIf the Corp is playing a Weyland identity, does the parenthetical text on Indian Union Stock Exchange allow it to still trigger off of itself?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "indian_union_stock_exchange",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen Information Sifting resolves, can the Corp choose for one of the piles to contain 0 cards?",
    "answer": "The Corp cannot make a facedown pile of 0 cards. At least 1 card must be in each pile in order for it to be a pile and for it to be facedown.\n\nIf HQ does not contain enough cards to make 2 piles when an Information Sifting run is successful, what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "information_sifting",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Inside Job](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31018) and bypasses [Funhouse](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30054) or [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066), do the non-subroutine abilities on those cards resolve?",
    "answer": "No. An ability that meets its trigger condition due to an encounter beginning can only resolve if the encounter is still taking place. [Inside Job](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31018)’s bypass ability meets its trigger condition at the same time as [Funhouse](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30054) or [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066)’s ability, and as it’s the Runner’s turn, they will resolve the ability they control first. Bypassing a piece of ice immediately ends the encounter, stopping the Corp from resolving their ability before they can tag the Runner or charge a toll.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "inside_job",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a player charge cards that have 2 or more power counters?",
    "answer": "Yes, a card that has 2 power counters qualifies as having at least 1 power counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "into_the_depths",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner passes an unrezzed piece of ice, does it count toward how many modes they can use for [Into the Depths](/en/card/33023)?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner does not encounter unrezzed ice, but they still pass it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "into_the_depths",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if a piece of ice is uninstalled during a run made with [Into the Depths](/en/card/33023)?",
    "answer": "If the Runner already passed the uninstalled piece of ice, [Into the Depths](/en/card/33023) will remember that it was passed and count that toward the number of modes the Runner can resolve when the run is declared successful. If the ice is uninstalled while it is being encountered, the encounter immediately ends. The Runner passes that ice's former position, but since the ice is no longer there it does not count as the Runner passing a piece of ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "into_the_depths",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner passes the same ice more than once during a single [Into the Depths](/en/card/33023) run, does that ice count multiple times for the payout?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "into_the_depths",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 15](https://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Earth's_Scion_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Inversificator to swap the passed piece of ice with an ice in Archives?",
    "answer": "No. Unless specified otherwise, only installed cards can be chosen by effects.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "inversificator",
    "update_date": "2018-08-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner has exactly 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> and plays Isolation, trashing Dadiana Chacon, do they suffer meat damage?",
    "answer": "No. Both the credit cost and the additional cost are paid at the same time. Dadiana is inactive by the time her last ability meets its trigger condition, so it never becomes pending or resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "isolation",
    "update_date": "2019-04-26",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Once triggered, IT Department results in a constant ability that\ncontinually tracks how many power counters are on the card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "it_department",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "IT Department always gives a piece of ice +1 strength due to the\ntoken spent to activate the card ability, even if there are no other\ncounters left on the card or IT Department is no longer installed.\n\n*Example: There are 5 tokens on IT Department. If the Corp\nspends 1 token, the ice has +5 strength (1 for the initial token\n+ 4 for the token still on IT Department). If the Corp spends\nanother token, now the ice has +8 strength (2 for the initial\ntokens + 3 for each of the two instances of the ability). If the\nCorp spent a third token, now the ice has only +9 strength (3\nfor the initial tokens + 2 for each of the three instances of the\nability).* [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "it_department",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp does not lose the game if they have a negative hand\nsize. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "itinerant_protesters",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Tinkering](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/25047) on an unrezzed [Ivik](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33045), then runs the server it is protecting, does it reduce its own cost when the Corp rezzes it?",
    "answer": "No. [Ivik](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33045) only counts rezzed code gates, and it is not rezzed until after the Corp pays its rez cost. However, if an ability checks [Ivik](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33045)’s rez cost afterward, it will count itself then.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ivik",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Jackpot! trigger with cards that are added to the Runner's score area without being stolen, such as [Notoriety](/en/card/20041) or [Director Haas](/en/card/03010)?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nIf both Jackpot! and [Another Day, Another Paycheck](/en/card/11007) are active, which card meets its trigger condition first?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jackpot",
    "update_date": "2021-10-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When does the Runner draw 1 card with [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028)?",
    "answer": "When the run is declared successful at step 5a.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jailbreak",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028) to run a server with a rezzed [Crisium Grid](/en/card/31079), will they access an additional card?",
    "answer": "No. [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028)’s ability that gives an additional access is a delayed conditional ability created by its “If successful” ability. Since [Crisium Grid](/en/card/31079) stops the run from being declared successful, that ability is never resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jailbreak",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Jailbreak](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30028) or another run event to make a successful run on HQ, can they choose that event as one of the cards for [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001)’s ability?",
    "answer": "No. An event that initiates a run is not fully resolved until that run is complete, and thus is in the play area, not the heap, at the time [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001)’s ability resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jailbreak",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has zero tags when they install Jarogniew Mercs, how many power counters are placed on it?",
    "answer": "Four power counters are placed on Jarogniew Mercs: 3 + 1 for the tag taken from its ability.\n\nIf the Corp plays [The All-Seeing I](/en/card/09022) while Jarogniew Mercs and another resource are installed, what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jarogniew_mercs",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "####Official FAQ\n* Playing a double operation and then playing a regular operation, spending three clicks for [Melange Mining Corp.](/en/card/01108), as well as clicking for three credits are each considered spending three clicks on the same action. Additional <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> costs are still costs to trigger an ability.\n* Jeeves must be rezzed while all 3 clicks are being spent. Installed cards must be active while meeting their trigger condition, and Jeeves trigger condition is the spending of 3 clicks on the same action, not the third click.",
    "card_codename": "jeeves_model_bioroids",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nAmong other things, the following series of actions can all trigger Jeeves Model Bioroids:",
    "answer": "* Advance three different cards\n* Install a piece of ice, an asset, and an upgrade\n* Use a copy of [Marked Accounts](/en/card/02055) three times\n* Purge virus counters\n* Use [Mumbad City Hall](/en/card/10055) to find [Mumba Temple](/en/card/10018), [Museum of History](/en/card/10019), then [Heritage Committee](/en/card/10013)\n\nAmong other things, the following series of actions do **not** trigger Jeeves Model Bioroids:",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jeeves_model_bioroids",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp place the advancement tokens from the ability on Jemison Astronautics onto multiple cards?",
    "answer": "No, all the advancement tokens must be placed on the same card.\n\nIf the Corp, playing as Jemison Astronautics, forfeits [Hostile Takeover](/en/card/01094) hosting [Political Graffiti](/en/card/10039), how many advancement tokens do they place on a card?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jemison_astronautics_sacrifice_audacity_success",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner avoids a tag from [Data Raven](/en/card/01088) with a card other than Jesminder Sareen (e.g. [New Angeles City Hall](/en/card/02109)), does Jesminder Sareen avoid the tag from a second Data Raven?",
    "answer": "No. Jesminder can only avoid the first tag that is given during any single run.\n\nCan Jesminder Sareen avoid the tag from [John Masanori](/en/card/04009)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jesminder_sareen_girl_behind_the_curtain",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Runner has a mandatory ability that would prevent the tag from [Funhouse](30054), such as the ability on [Jesminder Sareen: Girl Behind the Curtain](10006)?",
    "answer": "Players cannot attempt to pay a cost that would be prevented. If Jesminder Sareen’s ability is applicable, the Runner must choose to end the run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jesminder_sareen_girl_behind_the_curtain",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp plays [Anonymous Tip](/en/card/20118), do they draw all the cards at once and then decide which ice to install with Jinja City Grid, or do they draw the cards one at a time and decide as ice is drawn whether or not to install any of those ice?",
    "answer": "Drawing multiple cards at once is a batch effect. The Corp draws all three cards, then Jinja City Grid meets its trigger condition simultaneously for each drawn piece of ice. The Corp decides the order in which to trigger the instances of Jinja City Grid's ability, and thus the order in which to install the drawn ice.\n\nIf the Runner initiates a run on a server with Jinja City Grid and the Corp has a scored [Advanced Concept Hopper](/en/card/10011), will the Runner approach an ice drawn with Advanced Concept Hopper and installed with Jinja City Grid?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jinja_city_grid",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner accesses an agenda that would earn them 7 agenda points with 0 cards in their grip, who wins the game?",
    "answer": "The Runner wins the game in the checkpoint following the steal. The [Jinteki: Personal Evolution](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31050) ability has become pending, but would only resolve in the reaction window following this checkpoint. Since the Runner has won the game in this checkpoint, the game has ended and that reaction window never happens.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jinteki_personal_evolution",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner suffers net damage and one of the cards trashed is [I've Had Worse](/en/card/07032), which goes first: trashing the top card of the stack or drawing three cards?",
    "answer": "Both Potential Unleashed and I’ve Had Worse meet their trigger conditions at the same time. If it is currently the Runner’s turn, they draw three cards then trash a card from the top of the stack. If it is the Corp’s turn, the top card of the stack is trashed then the Runner draws three cards.\n\nIf the Runner takes more than 1 net damage at once (e.g. with [Project Junebug](/en/card/01069)), how many cards do they trash from the top of the stack?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jinteki_potential_unleashed",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp trigger [Jinteki: Restoring Humanity](/en/card/30043) if they have no facedown cards in Archives for most of their turn, but they discard cards to their maximum hand size?",
    "answer": "Yes!",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jinteki_restoring_humanity",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What’s the difference between \"when your discard phase ends\" and \"when your turn ends\"?",
    "answer": "We sometimes write abilities with “when your discard phase ends” to emphasize that they resolve after your hand size is checked. There is no difference in timing or functionality between this wording and “when your turn ends”.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jinteki_restoring_humanity",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens if Jua's subroutine resolves while the RUnner only has one installed card?",
    "answer": "The Corp cannot choose 2 installed cards, so nothing is added to the top of the stack.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "jua",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner plays [Scavenge](/en/card/03034) to trash and reinstall the program installed with Kabonesa Wu, do they still have to remove that program from the game at the end of the turn?",
    "answer": "No. After the program is uninstalled, it is considered a new copy of that card.\n\nIf the Runner uses Kabonesa Wu to find and install a [Chameleon](/en/card/08069), what happens at the end of the turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "kabonesa_wu_netspace_thrillseeker",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Kakugo trigger if it is trashed during an encounter?",
    "answer": "No. The encounter ends immediately when Kakugo is trashed, but then it is no longer active and thus its ability cannot trigger.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "kakugo",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Corp shuffle or rearrange the cards in Archives after turning them facedown?",
    "answer": "Yes. Cards in Archives do not have an order, and the Corp is not required to distinguish facedown cards in Archives from each other for the Runner.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "kakurenbo",
    "update_date": "2020-04-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Karunā](/en/card/30047)’s first subroutine resolves while the Runner is already breaching the attacked server (perhaps because of [Ganked!](/en/card/26119)), can the Runner still jack out? Does that stop them from accessing any more cards?",
    "answer": "Yes and yes. Nothing stops the Runner from jacking out at unusual times if given the opportunity by a card ability. Jacking out ends the run, which ends any breach in progress as well.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "karuna",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf there is a Kasi String in a score area, what happens when the Runner installs another Kasi String?",
    "answer": "Nothing.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "kasi_string",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner installs Keiko, and hasn't installed or used any other companions this turn, do they gain a credit?",
    "answer": "Yes. Keiko's trigger condition is met when installing a companion is complete, at step 8.3.6 in the rules for installing a card. Keiko becomes active before that, at step 8.3.5, so the ability is able to see that its trigger condition is met, and the Runner can trigger it and gain a credit.\n\nIf the Runner spends a credit from Paladin Poemu to install Keiko, can they trigger Keiko's ability?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "keiko",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Keros Mcintyre gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> if the Corp derezzes a piece of ice? How do the players know if the Runner or the Corp is responsible for the derez?",
    "answer": "Unless otherwise stated in the card text, the player who owns the card is always assumed to be the owner of any abilities on that card. Keros Mcintyre's ability only triggers if the Runner is responsible for the ice being derezzed. If a Corp card derezzes a piece of ice (e.g. [Test Ground](/en/card/08071)), or if a Runner card tells the Corp to derez a piece of ice (e.g. [Muertos Gang Member](/en/card/08068)), then Keros Mcintyre does not trigger.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "keros_mcintyre",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The card trashed by Keyhole is trashed faceup. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "keyhole",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Keyhole is trashed during a run it initiated, the replacement effect\nis still resolved. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "keyhole",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Khan’s ability trigger if an encountered ice is trashed?",
    "answer": "Yes. Ice that is uninstalled while it is being approached or encountered is immediately passed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "khan_savvy_skiptracer",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if the trace on Ash 2X3ZB9CY is successful during a Khusyuk run?",
    "answer": "Khushyuk replaces the Runner’s access step with its own ability, but Ash still prohibits the Runner from accessing any card other than itself. The Runner reveals cards from the top of R&D, but does not access any of them, nor do they access Ash.\n\nWhat happens if the trace from the second subroutine on SYNC BRE is successful during a Khusyuk run?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "khusyuk",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIs the Runner required to reveal agendas accessed from R&D while Kill Switch is active?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "kill_switch",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Knight cannot move to a piece of ice that is vertically adjacent to the\nice that it is hosted on. Knight can move to a piece of ice protecting\nany other server without restriction. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "knight",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Knight can be hosted on any piece of ice if it is already hosted on\nanother non-ice card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "knight",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat actually happens when the runner encounters Konjin?",
    "answer": "If the Corp wins the Psi game, they choose another rezzed piece of ice and create a forced encounter with it. This means that an Encounter Ice Phase resolves for the chosen ice, but the Runner's position does not change: they are still in Konjin's position throughout, and they will not pass the other piece of ice. When that encounter ends, Konjin's ability is finished resolving and the game proceeds with the rest of the encounter with Konjin itself. So if Konjin has acquired any subroutines of its own, the Runner's opportunity to break those subroutines is after the forced encounter. See section 6.5.2 for more details.\n\nWhat happens if an \"end the run\" effect resolves during an encounter created by Konjin?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "konjin",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes La Costa Grid's \"Remote server only.\" restriction apply even while it is unrezzed?",
    "answer": "Yes. It cannot even be installed into the root of a central server.\n\nCan La Costa Grid be swapped to a central server?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "la_costa_grid",
    "update_date": "2020-04-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Laamb have to match the strength of an encountered piece of ice to give it barrier?",
    "answer": "No. Just like bypassing a piece of ice with [Femme Fatale](/en/card/20029), Laamb has a \"when encountered\" ability that is usable regardless of strength.\n\nCan the Runner install [Paperclip](/en/card/11024) from their heap after giving  apiece of ice barrier with Laamb?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "laamb",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nHow does Lady Liberty Work? Can the Corp use Lady Liberty to turn an agenda into a different number of agenda points?",
    "answer": "The phrase \"worth agenda points equal to the exact number of hosted power counters\" is a qualifier to \"an agenda\". The Corp can only use Lady Liberty on an agenda in HQ that is already worth as many agenda points as there are power counters hosted on Lady Liberty. The ability cannot change the number of points on an agenda because it is not a conversion effect using the word \"as\".\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.05).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "lady_liberty",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes Lakshmi Smartfabrics get a power counter when it is rezzed?",
    "answer": "Yes. \"When you rez\" abilities meet their trigger condition at the end of the rez action, so Lakshmi Smartfabrics is active and can see its own rez action trigger.\n\nIf the Runner trashes Lakshmi Smartfabrics after the Corp uses its ability, can the Runner steal copies of the revealed agenda?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "lakshmi_smartfabrics",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhich comes first, Lat’s ability or discarding to hand size?",
    "answer": "The Runner discards to hand size first, then checks whether to draw a card from Lat’s ability. They don’t check hand size again that turn.\n\nIf Lat has Safety First installed, which comes first?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "lat_ethical_freelancer",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has four programs installed when they play Lean and Mean, then one of them is trashed during that run, do icebreakers then gain +2 strength?",
    "answer": "No. Lean and Mean checks the number of programs installed as the run is initiated, and if there are 3 or fewer programs installed at that time applies a constant effect during the run.\n\nIf the Runner has three programs installed when they play Lean and Mean, then they use [Clone Chip](/en/card/03038) to install a fourth program, do icebreakers then lose the +2 strength?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "lean_and_mean",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Is [Leech](/en/card/30008) a functional reprint of [Datasucker](/en/card/01008)?",
    "answer": "Not quite. Because [Datasucker](/en/card/01008) says that the ice you are encountering must be rezzed, there are some rare encounters where it cannot be used, such as an encounter with an [Archangel](/en/card/09013) being accessed from the Corp’s hand or deck. [Leech](/en/card/30008) can be used even during these encounters.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "leech",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Leela steals an agenda while accessing multiple cards from HQ,\nshe adds a card to HQ before continuing to access more cards. [Official FAQ] [Typically, the Corp player would shuffle this card into their HQ before continuing with accesses.]",
    "card_codename": "leela_patel_trained_pragmatist",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat does Letheia Nisei actually do?",
    "answer": "If the Corp wins the Psi game, the Corp may choose to trash Letheia and force the Runner to go back to the top of the server and progress through all the ice protecting the server again. Since her trigger condition is “the first time each run the Runner approaches this server”, once the Runner gets through the ice a second time, another copy of Letheia Nisei cannot trigger.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "letheia_nisei",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf Levy Advanced Research Lab reveals a program, can the Runner add a non-program from among the revealed cards to the grip?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nIf Levy Advanced Research Lab does not reveal any programs, or if the Runner chooses not to take any revealed programs, do the revealed cards still get added to the bottom of the stack?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "levy_advanced_research_lab",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nAt the start of the Runner's turn, can they choose to trash Lewi Guilherme and use [Fall Guy](/en/card/04106) to prevent Lewi from being trashed?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "lewi_guilherme",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner has 5 agenda points and a [Fan Site](/en/card/08085) in their score area, can they use Liberated Chela to win the game before the Corp can forfeit an agenda?",
    "answer": "No, if adding Liberated Chela to the score area is prevented, then it never becomes an agenda at all.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "liberated_chela",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens to agendas during a run made with [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009)?",
    "answer": "Any agenda in the root of the attacked server is trashed along with any other cards in that root. There will be no cards of any type left in the root to access when the Runner breaches the attacked server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "light_the_fire",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Aumakua](/en/card/12104) gain a virus counter when successfully running a server with [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009)?",
    "answer": "As long as the server is protected by ice, yes. You still breach the server when using [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009), unless the server itself ceases to exist. Usually, there will be no cards to access during that breach, but [Aumakua](/en/card/12104)’s trigger condition is still met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "light_the_fire",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009) to run a server that has a [Full Immersion RecStudio](/en/card/10108) in the root, hosting two cards, do the hosted cards lose their abilities? What happens to the hosted cards once [Full Immersion RecStudio](/en/card/10108) is trashed?",
    "answer": "Cards hosted on [Full Immersion RecStudio](/en/card/10108) are in the root of the server, and lose their abilities.  All cards in the root of the attacked server, including the hosted cards, will be trashed by [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "light_the_fire",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the attacked server changes to a central server during a run made with [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009), what happens?",
    "answer": "When the run is declared successful, the Runner will trash all upgrades in the root of the new attacked server. They will breach and access cards in the server’s corresponding zone normally.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "light_the_fire",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "How does [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009) affect a remote server with an advanced [NGO Front](/en/card/21039)?",
    "answer": "Once the Runner triggers [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009)’s ability, there is no opportunity for the Corp to use [NGO Front](/en/card/21039) before the ability begins to resolve. If the run is made against the server with [NGO Front](/en/card/21039) in its root, the Corp will not be able to use that [NGO Front](/en/card/21039) until after the run ends, and then only if it is still installed. However, the Corp does have the opportunity to use [NGO Front](/en/card/21039) in the paid ability window before the Runner takes the action on [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009). The Runner cannot use [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009) immediately after installing it without giving the Corp an opportunity to trigger paid abilities.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "light_the_fire",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner gain credits from [Security Testing](/en/card/31024) and trash the cards due to [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009)?",
    "answer": "Yes, you still breach the server when using [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009). You can combine the breach replacement effect and the [Light the Fire!](/en/card/33009) trash effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "light_the_fire",
    "update_date": "2022-09-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp play Liquidation while there are no rezzed cards?",
    "answer": "No, you cannot trigger an ability that has no potential to change the game state.\n\nCan the Corp play Liquidation while there are rezzed cards, but then choose not to trash any cards?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "liquidation",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner avoid the tag and still draw the 2 cards?",
    "answer": "Yes. The cards and the tag are not dependent on each other, they are two separate effects combined into one composite ability.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.06).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "liza_talking_thunder_prominent_legislator",
    "update_date": "2022-06-09",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses Logic Bomb to bypass a piece of ice on which they have already broken all subroutines, are those subroutines still considered broken for the purposes of card abilities (such as [Inversificator](/en/card/12048))?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "logic_bomb",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Logic Bomb when they have no remaining <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span>?",
    "answer": "Yes. Losing remaining <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> is part of the ability's effect, not part of its cost.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "logic_bomb",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has zero cards in grip, can they still choose to shuffle their grip into the stack in order to keep Loki from ending the run?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as there are at least 2 cards in the stack that can be shuffled.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "loki",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf Loki gains a subroutine with a self-reference from another piece of ice, such as a trap like [Kitsune](/en/card/06043), what happens?",
    "answer": "Everything in the subroutine resolves as normal, except for any effect with a self-reference in it. The reference does not refer to Loki, so it cannot resolve.\n\nIf Loki gains a subroutine from a [Mausolus](/en/card/11097) with 3 advancement tokens on it, does the regular text resolve or does the parenthetical text resolve?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "loki",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has [Spoilers](/en/card/08082) installed and the Corp scores [Longevity Serum](/en/card/30044), can the Corp choose to add the card trashed by Spoilers to R&D?",
    "answer": "No. The abilities on both [Spoilers](/en/card/08082) and [Longevity Serum](/en/card/30044) have the same trigger condition. Since agendas are always scored on the Corp’s turn, the Corp is the active player and must fully resolve their abilities before the Runner resolves any of theirs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "longevity_serum",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if Loki gains Loot Box’s subroutines and they resolve?",
    "answer": "With the recent changes to self-reference templating, “this ice” refers to Loki and Loki will trash itself when the subroutines resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "loot_box",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Lucky Charm to prevent the “when encountered” ability on Data Raven from ending the run without having to take a tag?",
    "answer": "Yes. Just like with avoiding the tag from Data Raven, the ability only requires the Runner to make a choice. Once the choice is made, whether or not the effect is prevented does not undo or invalidate the choice.\n\nCan the Runner use Lucky Charm to prevent the first subroutine on Fairchild from ending the run if they decline to pay the credits?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "lucky_charm",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner access a card and then trashes that card later in the turn (e.g. with [Apocalypse](/en/card/09030) or [Political Operative](/en/card/10043)), does Mâché gain power counters?",
    "answer": "No. Mâché triggers when the Runner trashes a card at the time of access.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.06).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mache",
    "update_date": "2022-06-21",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the first subroutine on Macrophage resolves and the trace is successful, but there are no virus counters hosted on cards and no cards that will be trashed from the purge effect, does the Corp still lose 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> from [Fester](/en/card/06075)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Subroutines that are not broken must resolve, even if they will not have any direct effect on the game state.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "macrophage",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If a [Parasite](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/01012) with 3 hosted virus counters is moved to a [Magnet](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31044) when it is rezzed, is [Magnet](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31044) trashed?",
    "answer": "No, the static ability on [Magnet](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31044) is already active before the conditional ability on [Parasite](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/01012) can meet its trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "magnet",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner host a Caïssa program on a [Magnet](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31044) that is already hosting another Caïssa program?",
    "answer": "No. Subtypes are not abilities and are not lost because of [Magnet](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31044). All the Caïssa programs require themselves to move to ice not already hosting Caïssa, so the Runner cannot move them to [Magnet](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31044) if one is already hosted.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "magnet",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the Runner still gain credits from Makler if another card (like Datasucker) is used during the encounter where all subroutines are broken by Makler?",
    "answer": "Yes. All that matters for Makler's trigger condition is that all subroutines were broken using only Makler and no other cards.\n\nWhat happens if the encountered ice gains additional subroutines after the Runner uses Makler to break all of the other subroutines?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "makler",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What does it mean to “score an agenda from this server”?",
    "answer": "This ability meets its trigger condition when the Corp scores an agenda that was in or in the root of the same server as [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "malapert_data_vault",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens if Malia is derezzed and then rezzed again?",
    "answer": "Once Malia is derezzed, its ability is no longer active. When it is rezzed again, only the resource chosen for the most recent trigger is blank.\n\nIf the Corp chooses a resource for Malia that is hosting cards or tokens, what happens to the hosted objects?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "malia_z0l0k4",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses [Dr. Lovegood](/en/card/09042) to blank the text of Mammon for the remainder of the turn, does Mammon still lose all of its power counters?",
    "answer": "No. When the Runner’s turn begins, they can trigger Mammon’s ability first to put power counters on it, then trigger Dr. Lovegood’s ability to blank Mammon’s text box. It is still the Runner’s turn when “turn ends” abilities meet their trigger condition, so Mammon’s text box will still be blank, and the ability that removes the counters won’t meet its trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mammon",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Corp scores Mandatory Seed Replacement, can they change the number of ice protecting  a server or create new servers with the available ice?",
    "answer": "No. The same amount of ice must be protecting each server after the rearrangement as before, and thus no new servers can be created through the rearrangement.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mandatory_seed_replacement",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Mandatory Upgrades is forfeited, the Corp loses the additional\nclick immediately. The Corp cannot choose to spend the additional\nclick before the forfeit, except as part of his last action (at which\npoint it has already been spent, and there is nothing left for the Corp\nto lose). Each player spends clicks from a pool of available clicks,\nand does not spend each click individually. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "mandatory_upgrades",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the Corp’s last chance to rez [Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042) for its ability to apply to a run?",
    "answer": "The Runner has an opportunity to jack out after passing the last piece of ice protecting the server. The “last chance” you are looking for is the paid ability window just after this (step 4e).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "manegarm_skunkworks",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Runner uses [Omar Keung](/en/card/11043)’s ability to run R&D with [Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042) rezzed?",
    "answer": "[Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042) will not affect this run unless it is rezzed in the root of Archives. [Omar Keung](/en/card/11043)’s ability moves the attacked server just before step 5a, which is after the step that can meet [Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042)’s trigger condition, step 4g.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "manegarm_skunkworks",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner would gain enough credits to have more than 6<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when the run ends (e.g. through a run initiated by [Dirty Laundry](/en/card/03052) or [High-Stakes Job](/en/card/10004)), does Manta Grid still trigger?",
    "answer": "The credit amount requirement for Manta Grid’s ability is a part of the trigger condition, so the number of credits the Runner has when the run ends is the amount that is checked. Any changes in credit amount due to other triggered abilities will not stop Manta Grid from triggering.\n\nIf the Runner trashes Manta Grid after the run in which it triggers (e.g. with [Political Operative](/en/card/10043) or on another run), does the Corp still get an additional click on their next turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "manta_grid",
    "update_date": "2017-04-18",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the run initiated with Marathon is unsuccessful, is the Runner still prohibited from running that server again?",
    "answer": "Yes. The restriction on running the server again is independent of the \"if successful\" ability.\n\nIf the Runner is redirected to a different remote server during a Marathon run, do they still gain <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> and add Marathon to their grip if the run is successful against the new server? Which server are they prohibited from running again during that turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "marathon",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Marilyn Campaign](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31042) is installed but unrezzed, can the Corp still shuffle it into R&D when it is trashed?",
    "answer": "No. The interrupt ability on [Marilyn Campaign](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31042) is not active while the source card is unrezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "marilyn_campaign",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Corp spends an agenda counter for Mark Yale’s paid ability, they also gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> from his conditional ability. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "mark_yale",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf [Tennin Institute](/en/card/05003) has placed an advancement token on a Runner card, does that increase the credits gained from Mass Commercialization?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mass_commercialization",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner breaks all the subroutines on a piece of ice with Mass-Driver, can they still break the subroutines on the next piece of ice that would not normally resolve?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nIf the Runner breaks all the subroutines on a piece of ice with Mass-Driver, then breaks one of the first three subroutines on the next ice encountered, does the fourth subroutine on that ice resolve or not?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mass_driver",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Masterwork (v37) with Az McCaffrey to install a 0 cost piece of hardware when they have no credits?",
    "answer": "Yes. The two cost modifiers are combined into a net of 0.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "masterwork_v37",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhat is the additional cost to rez Masvingo incurred by [Hernando Cortez](/en/card/11004)?",
    "answer": "No matter how many advancement tokens are on Masvingo, Hernando Cortez does not add any additional cost to rez it. Masvingo's ability is not active until rezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "masvingo",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the Runner place credits on Māui when they install it if there are pieces of ice currently protecting HQ?",
    "answer": "Yes. The value of X is already greater than 0 when Māui is installed, so credits up to that X value are immediately placed on it.\n\nIf the Corp installs another piece of ice protecting HQ during a run on HQ, does Māui gain an additional credit for use immediately?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "maui",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 19](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Sovereign_Sight_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\n**Updated** Does Maw trigger if the Runner uses [Salsette Slums](/en/card/10059) to remove an accessed card from the game?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner accessed a card but did not steal or trash it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "maw",
    "update_date": "2018-02-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 13](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Daedalus_Complex_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the first card the Runner accesses not in Archives that they do not steal or trash is an agenda that they host on [Film Critic](/en/card/08086), does Maw trigger?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner accessed a card and did not steal or trash it. Maw's trigger condition can only ever be met after an access ends, so it isn't a condition met by entering the \"accessing a card\" timing structure. Ending the access prematurely with Film Critic won't invalidate its trigger condition.\n\nIf the Runner does not steal or trash the first card they access in HQ, and that card is then randomly selected for Maw's trigger, is the card trashed to Archives faceup or facedown?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "maw",
    "update_date": "2018-02-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen can the Runner use the ability on Maxwell James?",
    "answer": "Maxwell James can be used in any paid ability window during the same turn in which the Runner has made a successful run on HQ. Interpret the card as if it said \"Use this ability only if you made a successful run on HQ during this turn.\"",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "maxwell_james",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Runner use Maya to add an accessed card to the bottom of R&D even after trashing it or stealing it?",
    "answer": "Yes. Maya triggers after the access has ended, so the state of the accessed card does not matter for the resolution of Maya's effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "maya",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Mayfly](/en/card/30032) to break more than one subroutine in a run?",
    "answer": "Yes. Each time [Mayfly](/en/card/30032)’s interface ability resolves, it creates a delayed conditional ability that will wait until the end of the run to trash [Mayfly](/en/card/30032), but extra copies of this ability that try to resolve after [Mayfly](/en/card/30032) is already trashed will simply do nothing.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mayfly",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use the second ability on MCA Austerity Policy on the same turn the third power counter is placed on it?",
    "answer": "Yes. Only the first ability is limited to once per turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mca_austerity_policy",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like MCA Informant work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays MCA Informant as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mca_informant",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhile MCA Informant is installed as a condition counter, can the tag be removed if the Runner has no tag tokens?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner is considered to have an additional tag, but it cannot be manipulated by card abilities.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mca_informant",
    "update_date": "2023-01-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Before accessing cards from R&D at step 4.5 of a run, the Runner chooses how many cards they want to access when using Medium. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "medium",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf a copy of Megaprix Qualifier in the Runner's score area has a hosted agenda counter, is it worth an extra agenda point?",
    "answer": "No. Megaprix Qualifier's ability is only active in the Corp's score area, so it keeps its printed agenda point value in the Runner's score area.\n\nIf the Corp scores Bifrost Array while there is a copy of Megaprix Qualifier in their score area, can they trigger Megaprix Qualifier's ability and put an agenda counter on it?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "megaprix_qualifier",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf both players have 6 agenda points, what happens when the Corp plays [Exchange of Information](/en/card/10092) and swaps a scored Merger with a stolen [Global Food Initiative](/en/card/09026)?",
    "answer": "The game ends in a tie.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "merger",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner takes Meridian as a -1 point agenda, does the Corp still gain 4<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nIf Meridian is hosting a [Sub Boost](/en/card/07025) when the Runner chooses to add Meridian to their score area, does the run still end?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "meridian",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [NISEI Rules Team Update]\nWhat happens if the Corp uses [Loki](/en/card/12069) to copy Meridian's subroutine?",
    "answer": "Because of the text update to Meridian to remove the self-reference, the subroutine resolves as normal. The Runner can add Loki to their score area; if they don't the run ends and the Corp gains 4<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>.\n\nUpdated (2022.07).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "meridian",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner encounters [Mestnichestvo](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33053) with 1 hosted advancement counter, which is spent to make the Runner lose 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>, will [Weyland Consortium: Builder of Nations](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/11038) trigger at the end of the encounter?",
    "answer": "No. The ability on [Weyland Consortium: Builder of Nations](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/11038) triggers when an encounter with an advanced piece of ice ends. The game checks if the ice is advanced at the end of the encounter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mestnichestvo",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use Metamorph to swap a card with an installation restriction like [Bamboo Dome](/en/card/12053) (install only in the root of R&D) to a different server?",
    "answer": "Yes. These restriction apply at the time they are installed and do not affect the card once installed.\n\nCan the Corp use Metamorph to swap an extra **region**, asset, or agenda into a server?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "metamorph",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIs Mganga trashed when the Corp and the Runner spend the same number of credits or a different number of credits?",
    "answer": "Both.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mganga",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “skip your discard step this turn” mean?",
    "answer": "You will not discard cards due to exceeding your maximum hand size this turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "midnight_3_arcology",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Midori can only be used at timing structure of a run 2. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "midori",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Ice that is swapped is installed, but the install cost of the ice being\nswapped does not have to be paid. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "midori",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner exposes an ice with [Snitch](/en/card/02045), Midori can still swap the\nice unless the Runner jacks out with Snitch. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "midori",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Midori must already be rezzed before the run in order to use her on\nthe first piece of ice protecting the server. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "midori",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Ice installed with Midori can be rezzed with the [Amazon Industrial Zone](/en/card/02038). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "midori",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf there is ice protecting the server chosen for Mind Game, can the Runner jack out before encountering the outermost piece of ice on that server, or must they encounter it first?",
    "answer": "The Runner can jack out before encountering ice on the new server, as long as they add 1 installed card to the bottom of the stack. The choice to jack out from a run is during the approach to a piece of ice, and the restriction from jacking out on a run only applies to the first piece of ice approached during a run, not the outermost ice of any server.\n\nWhat happens if the subroutine on [Wormhole](/en/card/07013) resolves the one on Mind Game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mind_game",
    "update_date": "2017-04-18",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [NISEI Rules Team Update]\nCan the access from Mind's Eye be augmented with additional accesses from cards like [Akiko Nisei](/en/card/22015), [Nyashia](/en/card/21067), and [eXer](/en/card/21041)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Mind's Eye resolves the steps of the Timing Structure of Breaching a Server (section 11.4) as if the Runner had just made a successful run on R&D, including applying effects that modify accessing cards from R&D and setting the number of cards to access. However, you cannot access upgrades installed in the root of R&D with Mind's Eye, nor can you apply effects like The Turning Wheel that depend on a run being in progress.\n\nUpdated (2022.06).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "minds_eye",
    "update_date": "2022-06-21",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp has less than 5<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when the Runner plays Mining Accident, must they take the bad publicity?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mining_accident",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen does Mirāju's effect resolve? Does the Runner start running on Archives immediately upon breaking Mirāju's subroutine?",
    "answer": "When the Runner reaches step 4 of the run and would pass Mirāju, if they broke the printed subroutine they instead run on Archives and the Corp derezzes Mirāju.\n\nWhen the subroutine on Mirāju resolves, does the Corp have to draw a card in order to shuffle a card from HQ into R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "miraju",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the number of recurring credits available on [Pheromones](/en/card/02086) has decreased (e.g. from the Corp using [Cyberdex Virus Suite](/en/card/07027) during the run on R&D), can the Runner still use Mirror to replace a recurring credit if the number of credits still hosted on Pheromones is greater than or equal the number of virus counters?",
    "answer": "No. Recurring credits can only be replaced up to the value shown on the card, never over it.\n\nCan the Runner use Mirror's ability to replace a spent recurring credit on [Whizzard: Master Gamer](/en/card/02001)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mirror",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp is playing Mirrormorph and the third action they take on their turn is to play a Terminal operation, do they get a bonus action?",
    "answer": "Yes. Playing an operation is not normally considered complete until step 8.6.11, after the “after you resolve” ability from the Terminal ends the action phase. If Mirrormorph were already pending at that time, it would be cancelled as per rule 5.4.3b, but it only meets its trigger condition at the next checkpoint after that (5.4.3d). Therefore Mirrormorph’s ability is the very next thing to happen after the action phase is ended.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mirrormorph_endless_iteration",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp play [Mitosis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33046) but install 0 cards?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Corp must have at least 1 card in HQ that could be installed in order to play [Mitosis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33046), but once they are resolving the operation, they can choose not to install any cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mitosis",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Can the Corp rez cards installed with [Mitosis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33046) on the Runner’s immediately following turn?\nYes.",
    "card_codename": "mitosis",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “creating a new remote server each time” mean?",
    "answer": "Each card installed with [Mitosis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33046) must create a new server. The two cards cannot be installed to the same server as each other or to any other server that already exists.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mitosis",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner has fewer cards in their stack than required to trash by a subroutine on Mlinzi, can they still choose to trash the top cards of the stack to not suffer the net damage?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner must be able to pay the full cost in cards trashed in order to not suffer the net damage. (This reverses a previous ruling, which did not consider Mlinzi’s effects using the rules for costs. Since rule 1.15.1c now makes clear that trashing cards from the stack in Mlinzi’s subroutines is a cost, those rules should be applied.)",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mlinzi",
    "update_date": "2019-04-26",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen does the Runner gain credits from Möbius?",
    "answer": "The Runner gains 4<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> from Möbius as soon as the second run is considered to be successful.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mobius",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner uses Mongoose to break subroutines on a piece of ice, and then that ice is encountered a second time during the run (through [Cell Portal](/en/card/01074) or The [The Twins](/en/card/07024), for example) can the Runner still break its subroutines with Mongoose?",
    "answer": "Yes. It is the same copy of the ice, so the Runner can break subroutines on it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mongoose",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "> Can the Corp use [Regensis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040)’s ability after using [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042)?\nIf the Corp uses [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042) on their turn and does not trash any cards from HQ with its ability, they can still meet the condition on [Regenesis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040). [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042) itself is removed from the game by its ability, so it never enters Archives.",
    "card_codename": "moon_pool",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp shuffles 0 cards into R&D with [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042), do they shuffle R&D?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "moon_pool",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner trash Moshing itself as one of the 3 cards trashed for its additional cost?",
    "answer": "No. An event is placed into the play area before its play cost is paid, so it is not a card in the grip at the time 3 cards need to be trashed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "moshing",
    "update_date": "2020-02-19",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Mother Goddess only gains the subtypes of other ice while it is\nrezzed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "mother_goddess",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Corp installs a piece of ice with Mti Mwekundu, can they trash other ice protecting the server?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nDoes installing a piece of ice with Mti Mwekundu cause [K. P. Lynn](/en/card/13052) to trigger twice during a single run?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mti_mwekundu_life_improved",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner spend 2[c] from stealth cards to access 2 additional cards from HQ with Mu Safecracker?",
    "answer": "No. Only one instance of a conditional ability becomes pending for each time the trigger condition is met. The Runner will only have 1 opportunity each run to trigger the pending ability and pay 1[c] to access 1 additional card from HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mu_safecracker",
    "update_date": "2021-10-05",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "mumba_temple",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "answer": "No. It is assumed that the Corp's deck is legal, and the influence value on the card is irrelevant for the purposes of gameplay.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp no longer has enough cards in their deck to satisfy the Alliance requirement for a card due to cards being removed from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mumba_temple",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Runner passes a [Wall of Static](/en/card/01113) and uses [Copycat](/en/card/04025) to bounce to another Wall of Static on a different server. Can the Corp still use Mumbad City Grid to swap the original Wall of Static with another piece of ice protecting the original server?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner is no longer passing that Wall of Static, so Mumbad City Grid's trigger condition has expired.\n\nIf a passed piece of ice protecting a server with Mumbad City Grid is uninstalled (e.g. [Paper Wall](/en/card/04059), or via a card effect like [False Echo](/en/card/04007)), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mumbad_city_grid",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "####MWL [Update v1.2]\nNAPD Most Wanted List - **Level 1**: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction.",
    "card_codename": "mumbad_city_hall",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp use Mumbad City Hall when there is only one card in R&D? Does it matter if that card is an alliance card?",
    "answer": "Yes, whether the last card is an alliance card or not. Since R&D is a hidden zone, the game doesn’t check whether the last card in R&D might meet the criteria for the search when determining if Mumbad City Hall’s ability has the potential to change the game state.\n\nCan the Corp use Mumbad City Hall when R&D is empty?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mumbad_city_hall",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes moving an advancement token from Mumbad Construction Co. to a public agenda trigger its ability?",
    "answer": "No. Neither placing nor moving advancement tokens is considered the same as advancing a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mumbad_construction_co",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner does not have 5<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> but has an installed [Imp](/en/card/02003) that they haven’t used yet, is the Runner forced to use the Imp to trash Mumbad Virtual Tour?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner is able to trash Mumbad Virtual Tour, so they must do so.\n\nIf the Runner has only 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> but a full [Ghost Runner](/en/card/06040) installed, is the Runner forced to spend the credits from Ghost Runner to trash Mumbad Virtual Tour?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mumbad_virtual_tour",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "answer": "No. It is assumed that the Corp's deck is legal, and the influence value on the card is irrelevant for the purposes of gameplay.\n\nWhat happens if the Corp no longer has enough cards in their deck to satisfy the Alliance requirement for a card due to cards being removed from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "museum_of_history",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner trashes any of the accessed cards, does the Corp still gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for each of the trashed cards?",
    "answer": "Yes. The trashed cards were still accessed, even though they are no longer in the server.\n\nCan Mwanza City Grid count as one of the additional cards I need to access from R&D because of its ability?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mwanza_city_grid",
    "update_date": "2019-01-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf Mystic Maemi's last ability trashes a program or hardware from the Runner's grip, does District 99 get a counter?",
    "answer": "Yes. District 99's trigger condition looks for cards trashed from any location.\n\nCan the Runner play Isolation by spending credits from Mystic Maemi to pay the play cost and trashing Mystic Maemi to pay the additional cost?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mystic_maemi",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp scores an agenda, and the Runner uses [Pantograph](/en/card/30023) to install [Mystic Maemi](/en/card/26072), does the Runner put a credit on [Mystic Maemi](/en/card/26072)?",
    "answer": "No. Conditional abilities must be active at the time their trigger condition is met in order to resolve. [Mystic Maemi](/en/card/26072) was not installed until after the agenda was stolen, so the Runner cannot trigger its ability at that time.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "mystic_maemi",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes Nanoetching Matrix’s last ability trigger when it’s unrezzed or not installed?",
    "answer": "No.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nanoetching_matrix",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner accesses NAPD Contract from R&D and does not pay\nthe additional cost to steal it, the NAPD Contract is not revealed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "napd_contract",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "napd_contract",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner steals Bellona with 2 advancement counters on it while NAPD Cordon is active, how many different costs do they pay? How many times can the Corp trigger GameNET?",
    "answer": "The Corp can trigger GameNET only once. The Runner pays an additional cost of 8[c] due to NAPD Cordon and an additional cost of 5[c] due to Bellona, but the Runner pays both costs simultaneously for a total of 13[c]. Since the total cost to steal Bellona is paid all at once, Corp card abilities caused the Runner to spend credits only 1 time.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "napd_cordon",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Nasir loses any bad publicity credits he has when his ability resolves. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "nasir_meidan_cyber_explorer",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "An ice is considered “just rezzed” for Nasir’s ability if it is rezzed at\nany time during timing structure 2 of a run. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "nasir_meidan_cyber_explorer",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Abilities which increase the rez cost of ice give Nasir more credits\nwhen his ability resolves. Likewise, abilities which reduce the rez\ncost of ice give Nasir fewer credits. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "nasir_meidan_cyber_explorer",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Abilities which require the Corp to pay an additional cost to rez ice\ndo not give Nasir more credits when his ability resolves. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "nasir_meidan_cyber_explorer",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp spends 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> after playing [Hedge Fund](/en/card/01110), do they place 1 power counter on NASX or 9?",
    "answer": "The Corp places 1 power counter on NASX. \"That many power counters\" refers to the number of credits \"up to 2\" that the Corp spends using the ability.\n\nDoes NASX trigger before or after the credits are gained? For example, if the Corp plays [Beanstalk Royalties](/en/card/01098) with an empty credit pool, can they use NASX at all?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nasx",
    "update_date": "2019-08-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes Navi Mumbai City Grid prohibit the Runner from using conditional abilities with costs, such as the subroutine breaking of [e3 Feedback Implants](/en/card/02024) or the derez of [Councilman](/en/card/10047)? What about the <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> to break ability provided on many bioroid pieces of ice?",
    "answer": "No, the Runner can still use all of those abilities. Even though those abilities involve paying a cost, paid abilities are always specifically written in the form “**cost**: effect”. Only those abilities are prohibited.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "navi_mumbai_city_grid",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner trashes more than one Corp card at the same time, such as with [Apocalypse](/en/card/09030), how many traces does Controlling the Message initiate?",
    "answer": "One.\n\nIf the Runner plays [Apocalypse](/en/card/09030) and [Aryabhata Tech](/en/card/10070) Tech trigger?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nbn_controlling_the_message",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses [Public Trail](/en/card/30057) or another card to give the Runner a tag, can they trigger [NBN: Reality Plus](/en/card/30051)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Giving the Runner 1 or more tags results in the Runner taking tags.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nbn_reality_plus",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner prevents taking a tag, can the Corp still trigger [NBN: Reality Plus](/en/card/30051)?",
    "answer": "No. If a tag is prevented, then the Runner does not take the tag.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nbn_reality_plus",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner prevents taking a tag and then takes a tag later in the turn, can the Corp trigger [NBN: Reality Plus](/en/card/30051)?",
    "answer": "Yes. [NBN: Reality Plus](/en/card/30051)’s ability looks for the first time a tag is actually taken. It doesn’t care whether it’s the first time an ability tried to give the Runner a tag.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nbn_reality_plus",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner accesses [Snare!](/en/card/31054) from R&D and takes a tag, can they still trash the [Snare!](/en/card/31054) if the Corp draws it with [NBN: Reality Plus](/en/card/30051)?",
    "answer": "No. Once a card being accessed moves to another zone, the access ends immediately.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nbn_reality_plus",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Before accessing cards from HQ at step 4.5 of a run, the Runner\nchooses how many cards they want to access when using\nNerve Agent. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "nerve_agent",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhat does \"for anything\" on Net Mercur mean?",
    "answer": "For the purposes of spending credits, credits on Net Mercur act like credits in your credit pool. However, if an effect makes the Runner lose all credits in their credit pool, credits on Net Mercur are not lost.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "net_mercur",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Micahel Boggs]\nDoes the base link strength reduction include any link from installed cards?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nWhen the first trace on a turn occurs with Net Quarantine scored, do cloud breakers then cost MU (and subsequently must be trashed if the Runner is over their memory limit)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "net_quarantine",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Net Shield can prevent a single point of net damage each turn. It\ndoes not prevent all net damage from a single source. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "net_shield",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Multiple Net Shields cannot prevent more damage. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "net_shield",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThere are four NetChips installed, and one of them is hosting an [Endless Hunger](/en/card/09033). A different NetChip is trashed. Is the Endless Hunger trashed as a result?",
    "answer": "Yes, as the hosting restriction applies at all times. Cards can host any other game object by default, but abilities can define limitations on the capability to host.\n\nThere are four NetChips installed, and one of them is hosting an Endless Hunger. At the start of the Runner’s turn, [Dr. Lovegood](/en/card/09042) blanks the text of that NetChip. Is the Endless Hunger trashed as a result?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "netchip",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If you play [Networking](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31020) and choose to add it to your grip, do you draw 1 card with [Aniccam](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/26084)?",
    "answer": "No, [Networking](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31020) adding itself to HQ prevents the default trashing of a resolved event.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "networking",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp scores an agenda, but then forfeits that agenda later in the turn, how much damage does [Neurospike](/en/card/30049) do?",
    "answer": "[Neurospike](/en/card/30049) doesn’t look for agendas in any particular location. Rather, it looks back at the history of the Corp’s turn for each time that they scored an agenda, then checks the printed point value of each of those scored agendas at the time when they were scored. Forfeiting an agenda has no effect on the amount of damage it adds to [Neurospike](/en/card/30049)’s total.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "neurospike",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp install ice with New Construction's ability?",
    "answer": "No, ice is installed protecting a server not in a server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "new_construction",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan Quetzal break a barrier subroutine when NEXT Activation Command is active?",
    "answer": "No. Quetzal is a non-icebreaker card.\n\nCan the Runner click through bioroids if NEXT Activation Command is active?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "next_activation_command",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use [Bifrost Array](/en/card/06081) or [24/7 News Cycle](/en/card/09019) to trigger the ability on NEXT Wave 2?",
    "answer": "No, NEXT Wave 2 does not have an explicit “when scored” ability on it because its ability has an additional condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "next_wave_2",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp has [The Twins](/en/card/07024) installed, which goes first, Nfr or The Twins? If The Twins is used first, does Nfr still gain a counter after the second encounter?",
    "answer": "The encounter with the piece of ice ending is a result of the Runner passing the ice. For simultaneous effects, first all of the active player’s abilities trigger, then all of the inactive player’s abilities trigger. Thus, if it is the Runner’s turn, Nfr will gain a counter before the second encounter occurs. If it is the Corp’s turn, The Twins triggers first; after the second encounter with the piece of ice, Nfr will resolve twice to place two counters on itself.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nfr",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Pravdivost Consulting](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33048) to put a counter on [NGO Front](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21039) and then use [NGO Front](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21039)’s ability before the Runner breaches the attacked server?",
    "answer": "No. Once the run is declared successful, there are no more windows to use paid abilities like the ones on [NGO Front](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21039).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ngo_front",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner trashes [Nico Campaign](/en/card/30037), does the Corp draw a card?",
    "answer": "No. The Corp only draws a card if [Nico Campaign](/en/card/30037) is trashed by its own ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nico_campaign",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf a subroutine on Nightdancer resolves while the Runner has no <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> to lose, does the Corp still gain an additional <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> on their next turn?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nightdancer",
    "update_date": "2018-02-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner trash [No Free Lunch](/en/card/33020) to gain credits while another ability is resolving, such as when they are installing a card with [Gachapon](/en/card/26069) or contesting a trace from [Punitive Counterstrike](/en/card/31078)?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner can only use [No Free Lunch](/en/card/33020) when they have priority in a paid ability window.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "no_free_lunch",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 21](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Council_of_the_Crest_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the trace on No One Home is unsuccessful, can the Runner choose to avoid/prevent fewer than the total incoming tags/damage?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nWhen a [Snare!](/en/card/20098) resolves, when does the Runner have to choose between preventing the net damage or avoiding the tag with No One Home?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "no_one_home",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Cards trashed by Noise’s ability are placed facedown in Archives. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "noise_hacker_extraordinaire",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use all three power counters from Nyashia on a single run?",
    "answer": "No. The ability only triggers once per trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nyashia",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner’s mark stay if all mark cards leave play, or does it leave and return when a new mark card comes into play?",
    "answer": "When you identify your mark, that server becomes your mark for the turn, even if the card that instructed you to identify your mark leaves play. If an event instructs you to identify your mark, that server continues to be your mark for the remainder of the turn after that event resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nyusha_sable_sintashta_symphonic_prodigy",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner does not have a mark, and they install a card that says “When your turn begins, identify your mark.”, do they get a mark for the current turn?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner only identifies a mark when an ability instructs them to.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nyusha_sable_sintashta_symphonic_prodigy",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has multiple “mark” cards, how do they identify their mark?",
    "answer": "The first time each turn the Runner resolves an instruction to identify their mark, they will randomly choose a central server. That server becomes their mark for the entire turn. Resolving another instruction to identify their mark will have no effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nyusha_sable_sintashta_symphonic_prodigy",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner gain a click with [Nyusha “Sable” Sintashta](/en/card/33011) if they are somehow able to make a successful run on the Corp’s turn?",
    "answer": "No. The mark only lasts for the Runner’s turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "nyusha_sable_sintashta_symphonic_prodigy",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does placing advancement counters with [Seamless Launch](/en/card/30040) meet the trigger condition for “when you advance” abilities like the one on [Oaktown Renovation](/en/card/31072)?",
    "answer": "No. Advancing a card results in placing an advancement counter on it, but placing advancement counters does not by itself count as advancing a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "oaktown_renovation",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes a [Border Control](/en/card/23054) to end the run and then uses [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to search for an [Anemone](/en/card/33043), can they also trigger [Anemone](/en/card/33043)'s rez ability?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as the [Anemone](/en/card/33043) is installed protecting the attacked server. The search effect from [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) and any resulting chain reactions are resolved immediately after paying the cost of [Border Control](/en/card/23054)'s ability, before the \"End the run.\" instruction resolves, so the condition on [Anemone](/en/card/33043)'s ability can still be met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to search R&D for a card when they trash a card with rez cost 0?",
    "answer": "Yes, but since there are no cards with a printed rez cost less than 0, they will fail to find any cards and simply shuffle R&D. Note that the ability was still used, even if no card was installed, so it cannot be used again that turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080) and triggers [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to shuffle R&D, does the shuffle happen before or after they draw 3 cards?",
    "answer": "The shuffle happens before drawing cards. Trashing [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080) is a nested cost, which requires a checkpoint to occur after it is paid. [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) triggers at this checkpoint and resolves before the rest of [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080)’s ability resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to search for [Daily Quest](/en/card/26048) when not in their action phase? What happens if the Corp tries to install and rez a card that cannot be rezzed?",
    "answer": "The Corp can search for and install [Daily Quest](/en/card/26048), but if it is not their action phase, it will remain unrezzed. The Corp must reveal the card to show that it cannot be rezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes a card with a printed rez cost of 2 to pay the additional cost to score [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), can they use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066) into the root of the same server as the [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058)? Can they then resolve [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066)’s ability?",
    "answer": "Yes and yes. When the Corp pays the additional cost to score [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), a checkpoint occurs before the score effect itself is resolved.  [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) triggers at this checkpoint and resolves in time for [Malapert Data Vault](/en/card/30066) to be active when its trigger condition is met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install a piece of ice, do they pay the install cost of that ice?",
    "answer": "No. [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) directs the Corp to ignore credit costs, and this includes install costs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does rezzing a piece of ice with [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) ignore effects like [Tread Lightly](/en/card/30012) and [Hernando Cortez](/en/card/11004)?",
    "answer": "Yes. “Ignoring credit costs” includes both increases to rez costs like the one imposed by [Tread Lightly](/en/card/30012) and additional costs consisting of credits like the one imposed by [Hernando Cortez](/en/card/11004).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “except during installation” mean?",
    "answer": "The Corp has the opportunity to trash other cards as part of the process of installing a new card. This clause excludes this type of trashing from the trigger condition of [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057). You cannot use its ability while in the process of installing a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install an agenda?",
    "answer": "No. Since agendas do not have rez costs, they can never meet the requirements of the search.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp has two rezzed copies of a unique (♦) card, the older copy will be trashed. Can the Corp use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) due to this trashing?",
    "answer": "No. The trigger condition on [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) only looks for cards trashed by the Corp, and cards trashed because of uniqueness are trashed by the game rules, not by a player.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install a card that has an additional cost to rez, can they decline to pay the additional cost?",
    "answer": "If the additional cost is paying credits, that cost is already being ignored, so the Corp cannot decline to pay it. If the additional cost is anything other than credits, such as the additional cost on [Archer](/en/card/31075), the Corp can decline to pay it. If they decline, the card will not be rezzed, but they must reveal the card to show why it was not rezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes a piece of ice (such as [Envelopment](/en/card/33060)) while the Runner is encountering it, then installs a new piece of ice protecting the same server with [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057), where is the Runner’s position relative to the newly installed ice?",
    "answer": "The Runner is inward from the new ice, so they will not approach it. When ice is uninstalled during a run, the Runner and all ice protecting the server immediately “collapse” their positions toward the root of the server. Ice cannot “jump in front of ” the Runner by trashing and installing midrun.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp trashes [Alexa Belsky](/en/card/11055) with her ability, can they use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install a card shuffled from HQ into R&D by that ability?",
    "answer": "No. The Corp’s opportunity to use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) is immediately after the cost of [Alexa Belsky](/en/card/11055)’s ability is paid, before the ability resolves. No cards will have been shuffled from HQ into R&D yet.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp trash [Daruma](/en/card/22041) to use its ability, install a card with [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057), and then choose the newly installed card to swap when resolving [Daruma](/en/card/22041)’s ability?",
    "answer": "Yes. Trashing [Daruma](/en/card/22041) is paying a nested cost, so it is immediately followed by a checkpoint. The ability on [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) resolves in full before the game continues to the instruction to swap cards in [Daruma](/en/card/22041)’s ability, so the newly installed card is available as a possible target for that instruction.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) while resolving the additional cost on [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) to install an asset in the root of the same server as [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058)?",
    "answer": "It is not possible to do this and still score the [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058). When the Corp pays the additional cost to score [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), a checkpoint occurs before the score effect itself is resolved.  [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) triggers at this checkpoint and resolves fully before the game continues attempting to resolve scoring. If the Corp chooses to install an asset in the root of the server that currently contains [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058), they must trash [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) as part of installing the asset. This is legal, but when the reaction window closes and the game proceeds, the score effect won't be able to find [Azef Protocol](/en/card/33058) because it is no longer installed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp trash [Reconstruction Contract](/en/card/21020) to use its paid ability, install a card with [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057), and then resolve the ability to place an advancement counter on the card that was just installed?",
    "answer": "Yes, but there must be a card the Corp can advance installed before they begin this process. If there are no installed cards the Corp can advance, the game does not consider [Reconstruction Contract](/en/card/21020)’s ability to have the potential to change the game state.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp trash [Calibration Testing](/en/card/21017) to use its ability, install a card with [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057), and then resolve the ability to place an advancement counter on the card that was just installed? Does it matter what other cards are in the root of the server with [Calibration Testing](/en/card/21017) when they begin this process?",
    "answer": "Yes, the Corp can do this, as long as the new card is installed in the root of the same server from which [Calibration Testing](/en/card/21017) is trashed. It is not relevant whether other cards are installed in the root of the server. The game checks if [Calibration Testing](/en/card/21017)’s ability has the potential to change the game state before the card is trashed, so it sees [Calibration Testing](/en/card/21017) itself as a potential target and allows the Corp to use the ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "During a run, if the attacked server has [Reconstruction Contract](/en/card/21020) and no other cards in its root and no ice protecting it, can the Corp trash [Reconstruction Contract](/en/card/21020) to use its ability and then use [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install a new card in the root of the same server?",
    "answer": "No. The attacked server ceases to exist in the checkpoint immediately after [Reconstruction Contract](/en/card/21020) is trashed, before the ability on [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) resolves. The non-existent server is not a valid destination for installing a card after this point.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The Corp trashes a card with [Svyatogor Excavator](/en/card/33059) and uses [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080). Can the Corp immediately use [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080)’s ability?",
    "answer": "No, [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080) has the same trigger condition as [Svyatogor Excavator](/en/card/33059), and was not active when that trigger condition was met. Once a reaction window opens to handle pending conditional abilities for a particular trigger condition, new abilities cannot become pending for that trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "How big is *[Endurance](/en/card/33025)* compared to the ships depicted on [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057)?",
    "answer": "There are two tanker ships in the foreground of [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) with large white cylindrical tanks. *[Endurance](/en/card/33025)* is about one-twelfth the length of those ships, smaller than the radius of one of the tanks.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to search for [Spin Doctor](/en/card/30053), do they shuffle R&D before or after drawing cards with [Spin Doctor](/en/card/30053)’s first ability?",
    "answer": "The shuffle happens before drawing cards. When searching their deck, players set aside any cards found by the search and shuffle immediately, before resolving further instructions that act on the found cards. In particular, in this case the Corp shuffles before [Spin Doctor](/en/card/30053) is installed and rezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ob_superheavy_logistics_extract_export_excel",
    "update_date": "2022-11-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner accesses a single card twice during a run on HQ with Obelus, how many cards do they draw?",
    "answer": "Two cards. The Runner is considered to have accessed two cards even if they end up being the same card.\n\nIf the Runner accesses cards from another server during a run on HQ or R&D, such as through the ability on [Hades Shard](/en/card/06059), does the Runner draw cards for those accesses as well?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "obelus",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Runner accesses Obokata Protocol, can the Corp use [Tori Hanzō](/en/card/05022) to replace the net damage with brain damage? Does this prevent the Runner from stealing the agenda?",
    "answer": "The Corp cannot use Tori Hanzō's ability on the net damage from Obokata Protocol because Tori only works on net damage that is dealt by the Corp.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "obokata_protocol",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan Observe and Destroy trash a Corp card?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "observe_and_destroy",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Runner encounters Oduduwa, is the value of X determined before or after placing 1 advancement token on it?",
    "answer": "After.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "oduduwa",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the Runner have to choose a server for Omar’s ability when it is used or when the run on Archives is successful?",
    "answer": "The choice is not made until the relevant part of the ability resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "omar_keung_conspiracy_theorist",
    "update_date": "2019-07-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Runner uses [Omar Keung](/en/card/11043)’s ability to run R&D with [Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042) rezzed?",
    "answer": "[Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042) will not affect this run unless it is rezzed in the root of Archives. [Omar Keung](/en/card/11043)’s ability moves the attacked server just before step 5a, which is after the step that can meet [Manegarm Skunkworks](/en/card/30042)’s trigger condition, step 4g.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "omar_keung_conspiracy_theorist",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes using On the Lam's ability trigger [Wasteland](/en/card/09036)?",
    "answer": "No. On the Lam is a condition counter and no longer considered a card while hosted on the resource.\n\nCan the Runner install On the Lam from a [Street Peddler](/en/card/08062)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "on_the_lam",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner gains 1 credit even during the resolution of another\nability (e.g., paying the cost to play a [Sure Gamble](/en/card/01050) with 5 credits in\ntheir credit pool). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "order_of_sol",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIs the Corp allowed to place 0 advancement tokens on a card and still force the Runner to either access that card or pay 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "otoroshi",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner runs HQ or R&D, accesses a card during the run due to [Otoroshi](/en/card/22038), and then the run ends unsuccessfully, can they still claim 1[c] from [Zahya Sadeghi](/en/card/30010)'s ability?",
    "answer": "Yes, the card accessed would still count. *Zahya*’s ability does not require a successful run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "otoroshi",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Runner use more than one copy of Out of the Ashes when their turn begins?",
    "answer": "Yes, each Out of the Ashes triggers separately from each other. Each copy is finished resolving only after the run has ended, at which time the Runner can resolve another copy (or any other “when your turn begins” abilities).\n\nIs using the “When your turn begins” ability on Out of the Ashes considered to be playing the event?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "out_of_the_ashes",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the first subroutine on [Whitespace](/en/card/30074) resolves, can the Runner lose credits from [Overclock](/en/card/30029)?",
    "answer": "No. Credits are always lost from the credit pool.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "overclock",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Overmind is installed, and its MU counts against the Runner’s\nmemory limit, when it gains power counters. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "overmind",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Playing Oversight AI does not give [Haas-Bioroid: Engineering the Future](/en/card/01054) 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for an install. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "oversight_ai",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Oversight AI is treated as a condition counter, and is no longer an\noperation, while it is active. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "oversight_ai",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Oversight AI is trashed to the Archives if the host ice is uninstalled. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "oversight_ai",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan PAD Factory place tokens on non-installed cards?",
    "answer": "No. The Corp cannot choose a card that is not installed to place the advancement token on.\n\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pad_factory",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes PAD Tap trigger when the Corp takes credits from a card like [Adonis Campaign](/en/card/20064)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Whenever the Corp \"takes\" credits from a card and moves them to their credit pool, they are considered to have “gained” those credits.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pad_tap",
    "update_date": "2019-05-03",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner does not make a run during the turn they use\nPaintbrush, then the condition no longer applies and the ice loses\nany subtypes gained from Paintbrush. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "paintbrush",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner spends a credit from Paladin Poemu to install Keiko, can they trigger Keiko's ability?",
    "answer": "No. Since Paladin Poemu is a companion, the first time the Runner spends credits from or installs a companion this turn is paying Keiko's install cost, which happens at step 8.3.4. Keiko's abilities only become active at step 8.3.5, so the ability is not active when the trigger condition is met, and it cannot be triggered.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "paladin_poemu",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Runner has [Safety First](/en/card/09044) and [Drug Dealer](/en/card/08083) installed. What is the exact timing of the two draw effects, and how many times does Pālanā Foods gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "Conditional abilities that trigger when the Runner’s turn ends do so at Runner 2.4, and abilities that trigger when the Corp’s turn begins do so at Corp 1.2. Pālanā Foods will gain a credit for both Safety First and for Drug Dealer, assuming each was the first time the Runner drew a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "palana_foods_sustainable_growth",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which subtypes are valid for Panchatantra to give to ice? Does the Runner have to choose a subtype on a rezzed piece of ice?",
    "answer": "Comprehensive Rules 1.3, 2.15.6:",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "panchatantra",
    "update_date": "2019-11-26",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner steals an agenda with their first R&D access and uses [Pantograph](/en/card/30023) to install [eXer](/en/card/21041), can they access another card?",
    "answer": "No. The limit to how many cards the Runner can access from R&D is determined at the beginning of breaching R&D. If an ability that would modify a breach, such as [eXer](/en/card/21041)’s ability, becomes active after the Runner has accessed a card, then it is too late to affect that breach.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pantograph",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp scores an agenda, and the Runner uses [Pantograph](/en/card/30023) to install [Mystic Maemi](/en/card/26072), does the Runner put a credit on [Mystic Maemi](/en/card/26072)?",
    "answer": "No. Conditional abilities must be active at the time their trigger condition is met in order to resolve. [Mystic Maemi](/en/card/26072) was not installed until after the agenda was stolen, so the Runner cannot trigger its ability at that time.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pantograph",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner spend credits on [Cloak](/en/card/03041) to install Paperclip from the heap?",
    "answer": "No. While triggering Paperclip’s ability from the heap is considered using Paperclip, paying the install cost is part of the install action and not a cost of using the ability.\n\nCan the Runner use Paperclip’s paid ability even if its strength doesn’t match a piece of ice?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "paperclip",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If a piece of ice hosting Parasite is derezzed, the Parasite continues to collect virus tokens, but the hosting ice has no strength while derezzed and therefore cannot be trashed by Parasite unless it is rezzed again. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "parasite",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Parasite cannot be hosted on [Djinn](/en/card/01009) [or any other Daemon program]. A card or counter can only be hosted in one place at a time, and Parasite has the restriction that it must be installed on a piece of ice. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "parasite",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "parasite",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the credit symbol with the arrow on [Paricia](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31034) and what does it do?",
    "answer": "That symbol means “recurring credits”, and it means that after a player installs (or rezzes, for Corp cards) the card it appears on, they should place the indicated number of credits on it (in [Paricia](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31034)’s case, 2 of them). Then, for as long as the card remains active, the player “refills” the card up to the indicated number of credits just before their turn begins. If there are already as many credits as the number indicated (or more), then no more credits will be added.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "paricia",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The wording on [Paricia](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31034) looks a little different. Has anything changed about how the Runner can spend its credits?",
    "answer": "Only the interaction with [Salsette Slums](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10059) has changed, and it is restored to the original state of that interaction before [Salsette Slums](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10059) received its first errata. The new wording for [Paricia](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31034) allows the Runner to spend its hosted credits when paying any cost that refers to an asset’s trash cost, including the basic trash ability and the current wording of [Salsette Slums](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10059). While [Political Operative](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10043) previously used a wording that would be compatible with this requirement, it has never previously been able to work with [Paricia](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31034), and so has received otherwise-nonfunctional errata to maintain this non-interaction.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "paricia",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Patchwork to play [Sure Gamble](/en/card/20056) with only 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> in their credit pool?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.05).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "patchwork",
    "update_date": "2022-05-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhat happens if the Runner's stack is empty by the time they make a successful run on the server chosen with Patron?",
    "answer": "Patron's replacement effect is not optional. Patron still replaces the access, but the Runner does not draw any cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "patron",
    "update_date": "2023-02-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat does \"each unique connection” mean?",
    "answer": "Paule's Café counts each installed connection that has the ◆ symbol, which indicates unique cards. It does not count connections without that symbol, even if they are the only installed copy of that card or have one-of-a-kind alternate art.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "paules_cafe",
    "update_date": "2020-03-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Pawn can move onto a piece of ice hosting another **caïssa**, but other\n**caïssa** programs cannot move onto a piece of ice hosting Pawn. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "pawn",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner cannot choose the Pawn that is being trashed as the\nprogram to install with Pawn because the trash and install are part\nof the same effect. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "pawn",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner play Peace in Our Time if they’ve already made any runs before spending any clicks, such as with [Out of the Ashes](/en/card/10080) or [Jak Sinclair](/en/card/09052)?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "peace_in_our_time",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nHow long does Peeping Tom gain subroutines from its ability?",
    "answer": "*Designer's Note: Technically, as Peeping Tom is written the ice gains the subroutines until the end of the game, but treat it as if the card reads \"... has the named type for the remainder of this run.\" Errata for this card will be issued in the next official FAQ.*",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "peeping_tom",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner use Pelangi to give an encountered Wraparound “fracter” or a made up subtype?",
    "answer": "No. Whenever a player must choose a subtype, they must choose one that exists, and if applicable they must choose one that is applicable to the card type in question. For a complete list of all subtypes by card type, see rule 2.15.7.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pelangi",
    "update_date": "2019-04-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "After the turn when Penrose is installed ends, does Wraparound get +7 strength?",
    "answer": "No. Penrose always has the fracter subtype, even after it loses its ability to break barrier subroutines.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "penrose",
    "update_date": "2020-03-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner lose credits hosted on [Overclock](/en/card/30029) or [Penumbral Toolkit](/en/card/26081) for the first subroutine on [Whitespace](/en/card/30074)?",
    "answer": "No. Those credits are only available to be spent. “Losing” credits always drains the Runner’s credit pool.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "penumbral_toolkit",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf two subroutines resolve during an encounter with a sentry and the Runner has Persephone installed, how many cards does each player trash from the top of their decks?",
    "answer": "If the Runner wishes to use Persephone, they must trash 1 card from the top of their stack. This will trash the top 2 cards of R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "persephone",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner may use the first ability on Personal Workshop to host a\nprogram or a piece of hardware on it. Cards hosted by this ability are\nnot installed, and therefore are inactive. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "personal_workshop",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can pay to remove a power counter from a card hosted\non Personal Workshop as a paid ability. A program installed from\nPersonal Workshop follows all the normal install rules; the Runner\nmust trash already installed programs to make room for the new\none, if necessary. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "personal_workshop",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "When there are no power counters on a program or a piece of\nhardware that has a play restriction on it that cannot be met (such as\na [Parasite](/en/card/01012) with no rezzed ice to be hosted on or a console when there\nis already a console installed), that program or piece of hardware is\ntrashed instead of being installed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "personal_workshop",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If Personal Workshop is uninstalled, all cards hosted on it are\ntrashed and all counters on those cards are removed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "personal_workshop",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes Personality Profiles trigger when the search for [Hostage](/en/card/04004) begins or after a connection is found and added to the Runner’s grip?",
    "answer": "When the search initiates, before the Runner looks at the stack.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "personality_profiles",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp advance [Pharos](/en/card/30063) if it’s unrezzed?",
    "answer": "Yes. Abilities that allow the Corp to advance a card are active even if the card is unrezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pharos",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses a card ability to rez [Ping](/en/card/30055) at a time other than while the Runner is approaching it, will its ability give the Runner a tag?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as there is a run in progress and [Ping](/en/card/30055) is protecting the attacked server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ping",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner trigger [Aumakua](/en/card/12104)’s ability with the access from [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013)?",
    "answer": "No. [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) replaces breaching the attacked server, and the access it grants is not a breach, so it does not meet [Aumakua](/en/card/12104)’s trigger condition regardless of whether the accessed card is trashed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pinhole_threading",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner trigger [Kasi String](/en/card/21111) with the access from [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) by running Archives?",
    "answer": "No. [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) replaces breaching the attacked server, and the access it grants is not a breach, so it does not meet [Kasi String](/en/card/21111)’s trigger condition regardless of whether the accessed card is stolen.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pinhole_threading",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The Runner uses [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) to access [Ganked!](/en/card/26119) and is forced to encounter ice. Both the attacked server and the accessed server are protected by [Border Control](/en/card/28005). Which paid ability among the [Border Control](/en/card/28005)s can the Corp use to end the run?",
    "answer": "The access from [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) doesn't change the attacked server, so the Corp can only use the [Border Control](/en/card/28005) protecting the server where the run was made, not the server where [Ganked!](/en/card/26119) was accessed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pinhole_threading",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The Runner uses [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) to access [Ganked!](/en/card/26119) and is forced to encounter ice. If the Runner is tagged, can the Corp gain credits from [Henry Phillips](/en/card/12056) during that encounter? Where would [Henry Phillips](/en/card/12056) need to be installed for this to work?",
    "answer": "The access from [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) doesn't change the attacked server, so abilities like [Henry Phillips](/en/card/12056) that apply “during a run on this server” only apply for cards in the root of or protecting the server where the run was made. The ability would be able to resolve successfully even though the subroutines being broken are on ice protecting a different server. Conversely, a copy of [Henry Phillips](/en/card/12056) in the root of the server where [Ganked!](/en/card/26119) was accessed would not be able to meet its trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pinhole_threading",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Pinhole Threading](/en/card/33013) to run a central server, can they use credits hosted on [Cezve](/en/card/33017) to trash an asset in the root of a remote server?",
    "answer": "Yes. The run is still on a central server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pinhole_threading",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Corp draws an agenda and a non-agenda with [Daily Business Show](/en/card/06086) and uses Political Dealings to install the agenda, is the Corp forced to return the non-agenda card to the bottom of R&D?",
    "answer": "No, the Corp can return the installed agenda to the bottom of R&D if desired, as the game still knows that it was drawn by Daily Business Show.\n\nIf the Corp draws two agendas with Daily Business Show and uses Political Dealings to install both agendas, is the Corp forced to return one of the installed agendas to the bottom of R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "political_dealings",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner adds Political Graffiti to an [AstroScript Pilot Program](/en/card/01081), is the AstroScript worth negative 1 agenda point or 1 agenda point?",
    "answer": "It would be worth 1 agenda point.\n\nIf the Runner adds Political Graffiti to a [Project Beale](/en/card/02115) with an agenda counter on it, how many agenda points is the Beale worth?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "political_graffiti",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan recurring credits from cards like [Whizzard](/en/card/02001) and [Scrubber](/en/card/02063) be used to pay the cost for Political Operative's ability?",
    "answer": "No. Those cards specify to use their credits for trashing cards, so they cannot be spent on using Political Operative.\n\nIs the cost of Political Operative's ability affected by cards such as [Industrial Genomics](/en/card/06105) and [Skulljack](/en/card/08042)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "political_operative",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan Populist Rally be played if the Corp has 0 clicks to spend on their next turn?",
    "answer": "No. As the Corp cannot have fewer than 0 clicks to spend on their next turn, playing Populist Rally would not cause a change in game state and thus cannot be played.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "populist_rally",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp must choose X before trashing cards from R&D. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "power_shutdown",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp cannot choose a number that is greater than the number\nof cards in R&D. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "power_shutdown",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp can play Power Shutdown even if the Runner has no\ninstalled cards. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "power_shutdown",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if both players want to prevent the same instance of net damage?",
    "answer": "The active player has the first opportunity to trigger interrupts and prevent the damage. Once the expected amount of damage is 0 or less, any further interrupt abilities preventing damage are not relevant and can no longer be triggered.\n\nIf the Corp plays Neural EMP and prevents the damage with Prāna Condenser, then they use Prāna Condenser's other ability to do net damage, can the Runner use No One Home?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "prana_condenser",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Pravdivost Consulting](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33048)’s ability to place an advancement counter on a card the Runner is about to access, like a [Chekist Scion](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33050)?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pravdivost_consulting_political_solutions",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner jack out after the Corp places an advancement counter with [Pravdivost Consulting](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33048)?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner’s final chance to jack out is before the run is declared successful.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pravdivost_consulting_political_solutions",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Pravdivost Consulting](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33048) to put a counter on [NGO Front](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21039) and then use [NGO Front](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21039)’s ability before the Runner breaches the attacked server?",
    "answer": "No. Once the run is declared successful, there are no more windows to use paid abilities like the ones on [NGO Front](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/21039).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pravdivost_consulting_political_solutions",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp plays [Predictive Planogram](/en/card/30056) while the Runner is tagged, can they choose the order to resolve its effects?",
    "answer": "Yes, but the Corp must decide before resolving either effect whether they will be resolving both of them or only 1.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "predictive_planogram",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like Preemptive Action work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays Preemptive Action as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "preemptive_action",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDo the credits gained from Product Recall include modifications to the trash cost, such as that from [Industrial Genomics](/en/card/06105)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Modifiers are always taken into account whenever a value is queried from the game state.\n\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "product_recall",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes Prognostic Q-Loop require the Runner to pay the install cost when they use it to install a program or piece of hardware?",
    "answer": "Yes. Effects that allow players to install cards require them to pay their normal costs unless specifically stated.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "prognostic_q_loop",
    "update_date": "2020-02-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp choose an unrezzed piece of ice for Project Kusanagi's ability?",
    "answer": "Yes, but it won’t do anything because unrezzed ice cannot have subroutines. Note that the Corp can only activate Project Kusagani’s ability if there is a rezzed piece of ice somewhere: to activate the ability, it must have the potential to change the game state, but once the ability resolves the Corp is not required to make a choice that actually changes the game state.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "project_kusanagi",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner has 4 or more agenda points and then steals Project Vacheron from a server other than Archives, do they win the game?",
    "answer": "No. When the Runner steals Project Vacheron, it will already have hosted agenda counters, and the ability changing its agenda point value will already be active, as it enters their score area. There is no point at which the Runner has agenda points from Project Vacheron until all the counters are removed.\n\nIf the Runner steals Project Vacheron during their turn, can the Corp play Game Over or Punitive Counterstrike on their next turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "project_vacheron",
    "update_date": "2020-08-04",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp swaps a rezzed piece of ice with an unrezzed one, does the Runner still approach the swapped in ice? If so, is the Runner still allowed to jack out?",
    "answer": "Project Yagi-Uda explicitly allows the Runner to jack out right after the swap occurs, regardless of when the ability is used. If a piece of ice is swapped while it is being approached, the Runner is still approaching that position and the Corp can rez the new piece of ice. If a piece of ice is swapped to HQ while being encountered, the encounter will end and the Runner will proceed to pass the position now occupied by the ice swapped from HQ.\n\nCan the Corp swap a card in HQ with a card in R&D or Archives?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "project_yagi_uda",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner accesses the same card twice (e.g. running R&D and a [Shiro](/en/card/05019) fires), do they gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> or 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "The Runner gains 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>. Psych Mike counts the number of times the Runner accesses a card from R&D, not specific cards accessed from R&D.\n\nDoes the Runner gain credits from Psych Mike for accessing upgrades installed in the root of R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "psych_mike",
    "update_date": "2022-06-21",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like Psychokinesis work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays Psychokinesis as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "psychokinesis",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses [Public Trail](/en/card/30057) or another card to give the Runner a tag, can they trigger [NBN: Reality Plus](/en/card/30051)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Giving the Runner 1 or more tags results in the Runner taking tags.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "public_trail",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens if the Runner uses Puffer's click ability while it is hosted on an [Omni-drive](/en/card/03039)?",
    "answer": "Puffer is trashed as it no longer can be hosted on the Omni-drive.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "puffer",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner draws cards so they have 3 or more in grip during the run initiated by Pushing the Envelope, do installed icebreakers lose the +2 strength?",
    "answer": "No. The ability of Pushing the Envelope takes effect when the event is played.\n\nIf the Runner installs another icebreaker during a run initiated by Pushing the Envelope (e.g. [Paperclip](/en/card/11024) from heap), does it have +2 strength?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "pushing_the_envelope",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nThe Corp, playing [Jemison Astronautics](/en/card/12016), uses Quarantine System to forfeit a [Hostile Takeover](/en/card/01094). What is the exact order of operations, and how much discount does the Corp receive for rezzing an [Asteroid Belt](/en/card/07012)?",
    "answer": "The trigger for Jemison Astronautics is the forfeiting of the agenda. As this is a chain reaction, Jemison must resolve before Quarantine System, so the Corp places 2 advancement tokens on a card, which can be placed on Asteroid Belt. Then, Quarantine System resolves and rezzes one piece of ice at a time. If the Asteroid Belt receives the advancement tokens from Jemison, then the total rez cost of the Asteroid Belt is 1: 9 printed rez cost, 6 discounted for having 2 advancement tokens, and 2 discounted for the printed agenda point on the forfeited Hostile Takeover.\n\nIf the Corp forfeits a card that becomes an agenda for Quarantine System, such as [\"Clones are not People\"](/en/card/10052), how much is the discount for rezzing the ice?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "quarantine_system",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is [Quetzal](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31001)’s ability written differently than in previous printings?",
    "answer": "The old wording of [Quetzal](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31001)’s ability did not fit into any of the modern ability types that the CR supports. In practice, it always worked like a paid ability, but now it’s written as one so that it’s clear what timing and other rules apply to it.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "quetzal_free_spirit",
    "update_date": "2022-04-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes the card swapped into Archives with Raman Rai enter faceup, facedown, or in the same state as the card swapped out of Archives?",
    "answer": "Facedown.\n\nThe Corp has Raman Rai and [Political Dealings](/en/card/10051) rezzed for the mandatory draw. If the Corp uses Raman Rai first to swap a drawn agenda with one in Archives, can the Corp then use Political Dealings to install the agenda swapped into Archives? What about the other way around?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "raman_rai",
    "update_date": "2021-09-13",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Corp has a scored [Sentinel Defense Program](/en/card/03007) when the Runner encounters a [Viktor 1.0](/en/card/01063) and cannot break the subroutines. How many copies of Ramujan-Reliant 550 BMI must be installed to prevent all the damage?",
    "answer": "The Runner only needs 1 copy of Ramujan-Reliant 550 BMI, which can be used to prevent the 1 brain damage from Viktor 1.0. Since Sentinel Defense Program requires the Runner to ‘’suffer’’ damage and not just be dealt damage, it does not trigger if the damage is prevented.\n\nDoes \"Limit 6 per deck.\" apply during a draft?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ramujan_reliant_550_bmi",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the only rezzed bioroid ice are multiple copies of [Ravana 1.0](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31045), what happens if one of their subs resolves?",
    "answer": "A mandatory loop is created. The general rule is that the Corp chooses a number X and the loop continues X iterations and then stops. In this case the end result is that the subroutine does not have any effect for whatever number the Corp chooses.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "ravana_1_0",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan [Andromeda](/en/card/02083) play Rebirth and change into [Boris \"Syfr\" Kovac](/en/card/00008)?",
    "answer": "No, the factioned identities from the Hardwired draft are for \"draft format only\" as indicated on the cards.\n\nCan [Apex](/en/card/09029), [Adam](/en/card/09037), and [Sunny Lebeau](/en/card/09045) play Rebirth?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rebirth",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can jack out the first time they encounter a piece\nof ice with Recon, even if it was not the outermost piece of ice\nprotecting the server. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "recon",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner accesses an agenda from R&D and does not pay the\nadditional cost to steal it, they do not reveal it to the Corp. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "red_herrings",
    "update_date": "2017-04-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Sneakdoor Beta](/en/card/31023) to run Archives and then switch to HQ, does [Red Team](/en/card/30018) count that as a run on Archives or HQ?",
    "answer": "[Red Team](/en/card/30018) cares about the server the Runner declared to be the attacked server at the beginning of the run. Therefore, it will always count a run made with [Sneakdoor Beta](/en/card/31023) as a run against Archives. The Runner will not be able to use [Red Team](/en/card/30018) to run Archives later in the turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "red_team",
    "update_date": "2021-10-12",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp uses Reeducation to add more cards from HQ to the bottom of R&D than the Runner has in their grip, does the Runner still have to randomly add cards to the bottom of their stack?",
    "answer": "No. If the Runner does not have enough cards with which to resolve the effect, then they are not \"able\" to do so.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "reeducation",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp play [Seamless Launch](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30040) to put the last required advancement counters on [Regenesis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040), and then score [Regenesis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040) before [Seamless Launch](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30040) is added to Archives?",
    "answer": "No. [Seamless Launch](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30040) will resolve and be trashed before a paid ability window occurs in which the Corp could score [Regenesis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "regenesis",
    "update_date": "2022-11-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Regensis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040)’s ability after using [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042)?",
    "answer": "If the Corp uses [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042) on their turn and does not trash any cards from HQ with its ability, they can still meet the condition on [Regenesis](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33040). [Moon Pool](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33042) itself is removed from the game by its ability, so it never enters Archives.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "regenesis",
    "update_date": "2022-11-27",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner is playing [Reina Roja](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31002) and the first piece of ice the Corp rezzes in a given turn is [Tithonium](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/12098), does the Corp have to pay 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> if they forfeit an agenda rather than pay [Tithonium](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/12098)’s rez cost?",
    "answer": "No. [Reina](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31002) increases the rez cost temporarily of the first ice being rezzed by the Corp. This increase in rez cost is not an additional cost, so by using [Tithonium](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/12098)’s first ability you do not need to pay 1 extra credit.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "reina_roja_freedom_fighter",
    "update_date": "2022-04-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nThe Runner has an Astrolabe installed and has installed programs with a total memory cost meeting their memory limit. If they Rejig their Astrolabe into another console with +1<span class=\"icon icon-mu\"></span>, do they have to trash programs?",
    "answer": "Yes. After the Runner adds the Astrolabe to their grip, their installed programs exceed their memory limit, so they must trash programs down to their new memory limit before continuing to resolve Rejig.\n\nWhich uninstalled card does Rejig refer to?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rejig",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan Remote Enforcement rez an Archer without forfeiting an agenda?",
    "answer": "No. If you install Archer with Remote Enforcement and do not forfeit an agenda, it will remain unrezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "remote_enforcement",
    "update_date": "2023-02-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner chooses to use [Carnivore](/en/card/30003), can they draw with [René “Loup” Arcemont](/en/card/30001) before trashing cards from their grip?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner must fully resolve [Carnivore](/en/card/30003)’s ability before the trigger condition on *Loup*’s ability is met.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rene_loup_arcemont_party_animal",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has 3 Respirocytes installed, how many cards do they draw when they have 0 cards in their grip?",
    "answer": "When the trigger condition is met, the Runner draws one card for each installed Respirocytes, so they will draw 3 cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "respirocytes",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use Restore to install an agenda from Archives and remove any other copies of that agenda from the game?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nCan the Corp use Restore to install an asset, upgrade, or ice from Archives that they don't have enough credits to rez?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "restore",
    "update_date": "2017-10-17",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp can trash a facedown card, but must reveal it to the\nRunner. The card is still trashed facedown. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "restoring_face",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When using the interface ability on [Revolver](/en/card/33018) by spending a power counter, does the Runner gain a credit from [Tech Trader](/en/card/10023)?",
    "answer": "No.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "revolver",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Rigging Up](/en/card/33024) to put an extra counter on [Hyperbaric](/en/card/33026)?",
    "answer": "Yes. [Hyperbaric](/en/card/33026)’s “when you install” ability resolves in between the instruction from [Rigging Up](/en/card/33024) that installs it and the instruction that gives the option to charge it. By the time the latter instruction resolves, [Hyperbaric](/en/card/33026) has a hosted power counter and is legal to charge.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rigging_up",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does [Rigging Up](/en/card/33024) say “if able”?",
    "answer": "This text is included to clarify that the “you may charge that card” effect is still subject to the requirement that a card can only be charged if it has a hosted power counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rigging_up",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a player charge cards that have 2 or more power counters?",
    "answer": "Yes, a card that has 2 power counters qualifies as having at least 1 power counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rigging_up",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhen can Rime be rezzed?",
    "answer": "Rime’s ability means that it can be rezzed in paid ability windows that allow the Corp to rez assets and upgrades, not just the special paid ability window while it is being approached. It cannot be rezzed during paid ability windows that don’t allow rezzing non-ice cards, most notably the paid ability window during an encounter.\n\nCan the Corp rez Rime with the ability on Architects of Tomorrow?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rime",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nHow does Rip Deal interact with upgrades installed in the root of HQ?",
    "answer": "If the Runner chooses to use Rip Deal's ability, they still access cards from the root of HQ, but those cards do not add to the number of cards that the Runner adds from the heap to the grip.\n\nIf the Runner has an installed [Nerve Agent](/en/card/02041), does it gain an additional virus counter before or after the Runner decides to use Rip Deal's effect?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rip_deal",
    "update_date": "2017-07-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 20](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Down_the_White_Nile_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes RNG Key trigger once for the first successful run on each of HQ and R&D, or does it trigger once the first time the Runner makes a successful run on either HQ or R&D?",
    "answer": "RNG Key triggers a maximum of once per turn, when the Runner makes a successful run on either HQ or R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rng_key",
    "update_date": "2018-03-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Rook can only move to another server if there is another piece of ice\nin the same “row” as the ice Rook is hosted on, counting up from\nthe innermost piece of ice protecting each server. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "rook",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Rook can be hosted on any piece of ice if it is already hosted on\nanother non-ice card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "rook",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner removes a program hosted on [Dhegdheer](/en/card/13020) from the game as the cost for using Rosetta 2.0, by how much is the install cost of the new program lowered?",
    "answer": "Dhegdheer’s cost reduction only applies at the time the program hosted on it is installed. The install cost of the new program will be lowered by the printed cost of the trashed program.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rosetta_2_0",
    "update_date": "2017-05-25",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the ice hosting Rover Algorithm is derezzed, does Rover Algorithm still gain power counters when the Runner passes that ice?",
    "answer": "Yes. The ability is on the condition counter, which remains active even while the ice is inactive.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rover_algorithm",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can spend zero credits after the subroutine on RSVP\nresolves to trash cards or trigger paid abilities. [Official FAQ] [eg to trash [Project Junebug](/en/card/01069), or use [Yog.0](/en/card/01014)]",
    "card_codename": "rsvp",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the Corp have to forfeit an agenda to rez [Ibrahim Salem](/en/card/10109) while Rumor Mill is active?",
    "answer": "No, Ibrahim Salem’s text box is considered blank while Rumor Mill is active, even if Ibrahim Salem is inactive.\n\nDoes the Runner add [Director Haas](/en/card/03010) to their score area if they trash it when accessing it from R&D while Rumor Mill is active?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "rumor_mill",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "#### UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen does Run Amok trigger?",
    "answer": "Run Amok triggers as soon as the run ends, similar to [Dirty Laundry](/en/card/03052) or [Doppelgänger](/en/card/02064).\n\nCan the Runner use Run Amok to trash a piece of ice the Corp rezzes during the run but then uses [Test Ground](/en/card/08071) to derez before the run ends?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "run_amok",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner pay the core damage cost before or after removing [Running Hot](/en/card/33003) from the grip when playing it?",
    "answer": "[Running Hot](/en/card/33003) is placed into the play area and then the cost for playing the event is paid, including the additional cost of suffering a core damage. The core damage cannot trash the copy of [Running Hot](/en/card/33003) that was played.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "running_hot",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the core damage cost be prevented?",
    "answer": "No. Costs cannot be prevented.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "running_hot",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [Running Hot](/en/card/33003) if it is the only card in their hand?",
    "answer": "They can, but they will flatline from doing so.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "running_hot",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [Running Hot](/en/card/33003) if the core damage will flatline them at the end of their turn?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "running_hot",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp forfeits a [Project Beale](/en/card/02115) with an agenda counter on it when they play Sacrifice, how much bad publicity can they remove?",
    "answer": "The Corp removes three bad publicity as the Project Beale was worth three agenda points. If the Corp has less than three bad publicity, they remove all the bad publicity they have and gain that many credits.\n\nCan the Corp play Sacrifice if they have no bad publicity?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sacrifice",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the second subroutine on Sadaka resolves, does the Corp still have to trash Sadaka if they do not trash a card in HQ to trash a resource?",
    "answer": "Yes. \"Trash Sadaka\" is independent of the other parts of the subroutine.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sadaka",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the first piece of ice [Rielle \"Kit\" Peddler](/en/card/03028) encounters is a [NEXT Bronze](/en/card/04011), giving it the code gate subtype, is it considered to have 3 subtypes for the purpose of breaking with Sadyojata?",
    "answer": "No. Changes in subtypes are tracked cumulatively, but the state of having a subtype is binary.\n\nCan the Runner use Sadyojata to swap in another copy of Sadyojata from the grip?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sadyojata",
    "update_date": "2022-01-04",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Corp’s trace strength is 5 or greater, Sagittarius trashes a program even if the trace was unsuccessful. [Official FAQ, listed under Taurus' ruling]",
    "card_codename": "sagittarius",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the extra damage from Saisentan’s “when encountered” ability trigger itself?",
    "answer": "No. The damage from trashing a card of the chosen type is not dealt by a subroutine, so it cannot meet the trigger condition of the ability again.\n\nHow does Marcus Batty interact with Saisentan?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "saisentan",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp play Salem's Hospitality while the Runner has an empty grip?",
    "answer": "No. Salem's Hospitality has no potential to change the game state, so the Corp cannot choose to take that action.\n\nIf the Runner accesses an Alliance card from HQ, is the Corp required to tell the Runner how much influence that card is worth in their deck? What about if the Runner accesses an Alliance card from R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "salems_hospitality",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner access a card and then later in the turn uses [Political Operative](/en/card/10043) to trash it, can they use Salsette Slums to remove that card from the game?",
    "answer": "No, Salsette Slums can only be used while accessing the card.\n\nCan the Runner choose not to use Salsette Slums the first time they trash an accessed card and then use it later to remove the second card trashed that turn from the game?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "salsette_slums",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner cannot use Same Old Thing to play priority events. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "same_old_thing",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Corp has 10<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> while Sandburg is installed. A [Parasite](/en/card/01012) with 1 hosted virus counter is installed on an [Ice Wall](/en/card/01103) without advancement counters. Is the Ice Wall trashed if the Corp plays [Hedge Fund](/en/card/01110)?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Corp's credit pool dips below 10<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> after paying the cost of Hedge Fund, so Ice Wall's strength is reduced to zero momentarily.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sandburg",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner spend virus counters from Sandstone for Yusuf, Freedom, etc.?",
    "answer": "No. Players can only pay costs with items they control, and the Corp controls the virus counters on Sandstone as per rule 1.13.2f.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sandstone",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "sansan_city_grid",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nAfter installing a card with Saraswati Mnemonics, when is the earliest that the Corp can rez or score that card?",
    "answer": "The restriction from Saraswati expires at step 1.4 of the Corp's turn. The Corp's first opportunity to rez or score the card after that point is step 2.1 before taking actions.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "saraswati_mnemonics_endless_exploration",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use Savant to break 1 code gate subroutine?",
    "answer": "Yes. Because the ability does not say \"if able\", it will resolve as much as possible when used.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "savant",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can trash a program as [the] additional cost, and then\nreinstall that same program. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "scavenge",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "As part of the install action, the Runner can trash installed\nprograms. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "scavenge",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the credit symbol with the arrow on [Scrubber](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31011) and what does it do?",
    "answer": "That symbol means “recurring credits”, and it means that after a player installs (or rezzes, for Corp cards) the card it appears on, they should place the indicated number of credits on it (in [Scrubber](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31011)’s case, 2 of them). Then, for as long as the card remains active, the player “refills” the card up to the indicated number of credits just before their turn begins. If there are already as many credits as the number indicated (or more), then no more credits will be added.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "scrubber",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The wording on [Scrubber](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31011) looks a little different. Has anything changed about how the Runner can spend its credits?",
    "answer": "Only the interaction with [Salsette Slums](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10059) has changed, and it is restored to the original state of that interaction before [Salsette Slums](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10059) received its first errata. The new wording for [Scrubber](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31011) allows the Runner to spend its hosted credits when paying any cost that refers to a card’s trash cost, including the basic trash ability and the current wording of [Salsette Slums](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10059). While [Political Operative](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/10043) previously used a wording that would be compatible with this requirement, it has never previously been able to work with [Scrubber](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31011), and so has received otherwise-nonfunctional errata to maintain this non-interaction.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "scrubber",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Seamless Launch](/en/card/30040) to place advancement counters on 1 of their cards that they could not normally advance?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "seamless_launch",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Seamless Launch](/en/card/30040) to place advancement counters on 1 of the Runner’s installed cards?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "seamless_launch",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does placing advancement counters with [Seamless Launch](/en/card/30040) meet the trigger condition for “when you advance” abilities like the one on [Oaktown Renovation](/en/card/31072)?",
    "answer": "No. Advancing a card results in placing an advancement counter on it, but placing advancement counters does not by itself count as advancing a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "seamless_launch",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Security Testing](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31024) is trashed while running the chosen server, does the Runner still apply its replacement effect (gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> instead of breaching)?",
    "answer": "No. The second ability on [Security Testing](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31024) is a separate ability, not a lingering effect. If [Security Testing](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31024) is trashed during the run, it is not active at the time it would meet its trigger condition, so the Runner does not apply the replacement effect to gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "security_testing",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If breaching HQ is replaced with another effect, such as gaining 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> with [Security Testing](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31024), will the Runner get the additional access with [Docklands Pass](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30013) if they make a successful run on HQ again later in the turn?",
    "answer": "Yes. “The first time you breach HQ” refers to a breach actually taking place, not just reaching the “Breach the attacked server.” step of the run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "security_testing",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Seidr Adaptive Barrier have +1 strength from itself?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "seidr_adaptive_barrier",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Self-Destruct does not count itself as one of the cards trashed in\norder to establish the trace value. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "self_destruct",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nThis card is a reprint. Has anything changed about how Self-modifying Code works?",
    "answer": "No. We cleaned up this card's wording by removing the redundant directions to pay the install cost and to shuffle after the search, but those are still required parts of the ability. We felt that players would enjoy having a version of this iconic card with clean and concise text, so we opted not to include the frequently-used \"(Shuffle your stack after searching it)\" reminder text in this case.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "self_modifying_code",
    "update_date": "2020-03-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Send a Message](/en/card/30069)’s ability to rez an [Archer](/en/card/31075) without forfeiting an agenda?",
    "answer": "Yes. “Ignoring all costs” in [Send a Message](/en/card/30069)’s ability refers to both the rez cost of the ice and any additional costs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "send_a_message",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Sensei only adds a single “End the run.” subroutine after all of the\nother subroutines on the next piece of ice, not a subroutine after\neach subroutine on the ice. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "sensei",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "#### MWL [update v1.2]\nNAPD Most Wanted List - **Level 3**: Each copy of this card costs 3 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities' influence limits, even those in the same faction.",
    "card_codename": "sensie_actors_union",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Corp has Sensie Actors Union and [Daily Business Show](/en/card/06086) rezzed, how is the Sensie Actors Union’s ability resolved?",
    "answer": "The Corp draws four cards, adds one of the drawn cards to the bottom of R&D due to Daily Business Show’s ability, then adds any card from HQ to the bottom of R&D due to Sensie Actors Union’s ability.\n\nIf the only piece of ice protecting Sensie Actors Union  is returned to hand by [Blue Sun](/en/card/06068) at the start of the Corp's turn, does the ability of the political asset still trigger?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sensie_actors_union",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner initiate an effect that makes a run while Service Outage is active, then decline to pay the additional cost? If so, does that count as the “first run” on their turn?",
    "answer": "Yes, the additional cost can be declined (and the run does not initiate). This does not count as the first run, as no run was initiated.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "service_outage",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen does the Runner trash cards to use Severnius Stim Implant?",
    "answer": "The cards are trashed as the run is initiated.\n\nAfter using Severnius Stim Implant, does the Runner access additional cards from that server in later runs or card abilities?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "severnius_stim_implant",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp play Shipment from Tennin on their first turn?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner does not have a last turn to reference.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "shipment_from_tennin",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan Şifr be used on [Lotus Field](/en/card/06003)?",
    "answer": "No. Lotus Field cannot have its strength lowered.\n\nWhat is the strength of [Wraparound](/en/card/04096) if there is no fracter installed and the Runner uses Şifr? What if the Runner then installs [Paperclip](/en/card/11024) from the heap?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sifr",
    "update_date": "2017-04-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 3: Each copy of this card costs 3 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "sifr",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Runner uses Aesop's Pawnshop to trash Harbinger, turning it facedown, do they have to pay the additional cost to use Simulchip that turn?",
    "answer": "No. Harbinger still counts as having been trashed, even though its ability replaces moving it to the heap with turning it facedown.\n\nIf the Runner uses Aesop's Pawnshop to trash a Harbinger that is already facedown, do they have to pay the additional cost to use Simulchip that turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "simulchip",
    "update_date": "2020-03-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf [Employee Strike](/en/card/09053) is active when either an agenda is scored or another current is played, can Skorpios Defense Systems remove it from the game?",
    "answer": "No. Employee Strike is active until it is trashed, so Skorpios doesn’t have its ability in time to see the trigger condition being met.\n\nIf the Runner trashes multiple cards at once, such as through damage from [Scorched Earth](/en/card/01099) or through [MaxX's](/en/card/07029) ability, does the Corp have to choose one at a time which card to remove from the game as damage is picked?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "skorpios_defense_systems_persuasive_power",
    "update_date": "2018-09-22",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Slipstream work if the ice is uninstalled during the encounter?",
    "answer": "No. Though ice is immediately passed if it is derezzed or uninstalled while being encountered, it then is no longer a rezzed piece of ice, so it does not meet Slipstream's trigger condition.\n\nHow is ice position determined for Sipstream?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "slipstream",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use the action to place credits on [Smartware Distributor](/en/card/30033) if there are already credits on it?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "smartware_distributor",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) is active in the root of HQ and the Runner uses [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023), is the run successful on either Archives or HQ?",
    "answer": "No, [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023) changes the attacked server while step 6.9.5a of the run is imminent, because the expected effects of that step include the trigger condition of [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023)’s delayed conditional ability, which is that the run on Archives would be declared successful. However, once the attacked server is changed to HQ, the imminent step cannot declare the run successful after all because of [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079)’s ability. The Runner will still breach HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sneakdoor_beta",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079) is active in the root of Archives and the Runner uses [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023), what server does the Runner breach and is the run successful?",
    "answer": "The Runner breaches Archives and the run is not declared successful. Since [Crisium Grid](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31079)’s ability is a static ability and applies immediately, declaring the run successful is never part of the expected effects of step 6.9.5a of the run, so the trigger condition of [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023)’s delayed conditional ability is never met and the ability never resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sneakdoor_beta",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Sneakdoor Beta](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31023) is trashed during a run it initiated, is the attacked server still changed to HQ?",
    "answer": "Yes, once the ability is initiated, resolving its effects becomes independent from the source card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sneakdoor_beta",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner uses [Sneakdoor Beta](/en/card/31023) to run Archives and then switch to HQ, does [Red Team](/en/card/30018) count that as a run on Archives or HQ?",
    "answer": "Archives. [Red Team](/en/card/30018) cares about the server the Runner declared to be the attacked server at the beginning of the run. Therefore, it will always count a run made with [Sneakdoor Beta](/en/card/31023) as a run against Archives.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sneakdoor_beta",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the outermost piece of ice on a server is unrezzed, the Runner\ncan use Snitch to look at it and then decide to jack out before\nencountering it. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "snitch",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the expose effect is prevented, the Runner can still jack out. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "snitch",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner encounters the innermost piece of ice multiple times during a Spear Phishing run (e.g. through [Cell Portal](/en/card/01074) or [The Twins](/en/card/07024)), do they bypass it each time?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "spear_phishing",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp play Special Report and choose to shuffle 0 cards into R&D?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nCan the Corp play Special Report when it is the only card in HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "special_report",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp use [Spin Doctor](/en/card/30053)’s ability to remove it from the game without choosing any cards in Archives? Does this cause R&D to be shuffled?",
    "answer": "Yes and yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "spin_doctor",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If there are no cards in Archives, can the corp activate [Spin Doctor](/en/card/30053)’s ability to remove it from the game in order to shuffle the deck?",
    "answer": "Yes. Shuffling the deck is a change in game state, so you could activate this ability without any targets to shuffle back.  Note that you must have at least 2 cards in R&D to do this, because if you only have 1 card, you aren’t actually shuffling the deck.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "spin_doctor",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "When rezzing or using [Spin Doctor](/en/card/30053), can the Corp quote Malcolm Tucker from the BBC series *The Thick of It*?",
    "answer": "Maybe! Please be mindful of what is appropriate language for your play environment. NISEI encourages players to be respectful and welcoming to each other, and some players may find strong expletives to be off-putting. Refer to the NISEI [Code of Conduct](https://nisei.net/about/code-of-conduct/) and [Organized Play Policies](https://nisei.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Organized_Play_Policies.pdf) for more information.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "spin_doctor",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has [Spoilers](/en/card/08082) installed and the Corp scores [Longevity Serum](/en/card/30044), can the Corp choose to add the card trashed by Spoilers to R&D?",
    "answer": "No. The abilities on both [Spoilers](/en/card/08082) and [Longevity Serum](/en/card/30044) have the same trigger condition. Since agendas are always scored on the Corp’s turn, the Corp is the active player and must fully resolve their abilities before the Runner resolves any of theirs.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "spoilers",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner has no cards in their stack but a [Tech Trader](/en/card/10023) installed, can the Runner use Sports Hopper?",
    "answer": "No. Sports Hopper's effect cannot change the game state, so its ability cannot be triggered.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sports_hopper",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens if the Runner steals an agenda in the middle of accessing cards from R&D and the Corp uses Sportsmetal to draw cards?",
    "answer": "The Runner continues accessing from the topmost card of R&D that the Runner has not already accessed. If Sportsmetal drew past the point the Runner already accessed, the new top of R&D is the next card accessed. If Sportsmetal drew 2 cards the Runner has already accessed and there are other cards the Runner has already accessed, the Runner simply continues accessing from the point in R&D at which they are already accessing.\n\nAudited by NISEI Rules (2022.07).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sportsmetal_go_big_or_go_home",
    "update_date": "2022-07-08",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nDoes \"Limit 6 per deck.\" apply during a draft?",
    "answer": "Yes. As it is part of the card text, this limit applies even during a draft.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "spy_camera",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp name a made up card type for Standard Procedure?",
    "answer": "No, but they can name a Corp card type.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "standard_procedure",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens to the other two cards revealed by Stargate?",
    "answer": "The cards not trashed are returned to R&D in the same order they were originally in.\n\nIf the Runner uses Stargate and the run is unsuccessful, can they try again the same turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "stargate",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses a card ability to rez [Stavka](/en/card/33062) at a time other than while the Runner is approaching it, will they be able to use its ability?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as there is a run in progress and [Stavka](/en/card/33062) is protecting the attacked server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "stavka",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Runner plays [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004), is it trashed from their grip?",
    "answer": "No, it is trashed from the play area. When the Runner plays [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004), they will only resolve its first ability, drawing 3 cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steelskin_scarring",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner draw cards from [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004) when it is discarded to meet their maximum hand size?",
    "answer": "No, discarded cards are not considered trashed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steelskin_scarring",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "How does [Buffer Drive](/en/card/26093) interact with [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004)?",
    "answer": "Both cards' conditional abilities meet their trigger conditions at the same time, and the Runner can choose to resolve either one first. If they choose to resolve [Buffer Drive](/en/card/26093)'s ability first and put [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004) on the bottom of the stack, they will not be able to resolve [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004)’s ability because that ability is no longer active once its source leaves the heap. If they choose to resolve [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004)’s ability first, they will still be able to use [Buffer Drive](/en/card/26093)’s ability after drawing 2 cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steelskin_scarring",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What exactly happens if [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004) is on top of the Runner's stack and they play [Labor Rights](/en/card/28001)?",
    "answer": "Each sentence on Labor Rights is an instruction, and other abilities that meet their trigger conditions have the opportunity to resolve between instructions. So [Labor Rights](/en/card/28001) will trash 3 cards including [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004), then [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004)'s ability will trigger and the Runner may draw 2 cards. Then, the Runner shuffles cards (which could include the same copy of [Steelskin Scarring](/en/card/33004)) from their heap into their stack, and finally, they draw 1 more card and remove [Labor Rights](/en/card/28001) from the game.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steelskin_scarring",
    "update_date": "2022-09-28",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31014)’s ability do anything if there are fewer than 2 cards in the heap?",
    "answer": "No. Choosing 2 cards in the heap is a nested cost because it is followed by “If you do”. If the Runner cannot pay the cost in full, the rest of the ability does not resolve.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steve_cambridge_master_grifter",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Jailbreak](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30028) or another run event to make a successful run on HQ, can they choose that event as one of the cards for [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001)’s ability?",
    "answer": "No. An event that initiates a run is not fully resolved until that run is complete, and thus is in the play area, not the heap, at the time [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001)’s ability resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steve_cambridge_master_grifter",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner choose to look at the top card of R&D with [Find the Truth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/11047) before using [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001)?",
    "answer": "Yes. Both abilities meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner chooses the order to resolve them.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steve_cambridge_master_grifter",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner returns [Utopia Shard](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06100) to their grip with [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001), can they then install [Utopia Shard](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06100)?",
    "answer": "No. In order for [Utopia Shard](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06100) to install itself with its ability, it must already be in the Runner’s grip at the time the ability would meet its trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "steve_cambridge_master_grifter",
    "update_date": "2022-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nHow much net damage does Sting! do?",
    "answer": "The first copy of Sting! Scored or stolen just does 1 net damage. Assuming no agendas are swapped or forfeited, the second copy does 1 net damage if the same player scores or steals it, or 2 if the other player does. The third copy does between 1 and 3 net damage: 3 if that player just scored or stole their only copy of Sting!, 2 if they already had one and their opponent had one, and 1 if the same player has all three.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sting",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like Stock Buyback work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays Stock Buyback as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "stock_buy_back",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a player charge cards that have 2 or more power counters?",
    "answer": "Yes, a card that has 2 power counters qualifies as having at least 1 power counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "stoneship_chart_room",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Stoneship Chart Room](/en/card/33030) after their discard step to draw additional cards before [Lat: Ethical Freelancer](/en/card/26019)’s ability meets its trigger condition?",
    "answer": "Yes, there is a paid ability window after the discard step but before the end of the discard phase.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "stoneship_chart_room",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes Storgotic Resonator get a counter when the Corp clears a Runner current matching the Runner’s identity faction?",
    "answer": "No. Currents are trashed by the game rules, not by a player.\n\nDoes Storgotic Resonator get a counter when the Corp trashes a daemon hosting a card matching the Runner’s identity faction?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "storgotic_resonator",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen the Runner encounters a piece of ice with Street Magic installed, when is the order of resolution for the subroutines determined? Is the order determined before any subroutines resolve, or does the Runner choose one subroutine to resolve at a time?",
    "answer": "Instead of the subroutines resolving in the order printed on the ice, the Runner chooses the order they will resolve in, and then they resolve one at a time in that order.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "street_magic",
    "update_date": "2017-05-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp spend credits gained from the first operation played with Subcontract to pay for the second operation?",
    "answer": "Yes. The entire process of paying for the first operation’s cost and resolving its effects is carried out before playing the second operation.\n\nWhile resolving Subcontract, can the Corp play a [Hedge Fund](/en/card/01110) as the second operation if it was drawn from playing [Anonymous Tip](/en/card/01083) as the first operation?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "subcontract",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When [Subliminal Messaging](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31082) is faceup in Archives and the Corp uses its ability to add it to HQ, does Hyoubu Institute gain 1 credit?",
    "answer": "Yes, [Subliminal Messaging](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31082) is revealed even if it is faceup.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "subliminal_messaging",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhen the Corp plays Success, can they split the advancements among more than one card?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nIf [Jemison Astronautics](/en/card/12016) plays Success, which goes first? Jemison or Success?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "success",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp is playing [Weyland Consortium: Built to Last](30059) and uses [Success](12078) to advance a card multiple times at once, how many credits do they gain?",
    "answer": "Success advances its target multiple times in sequence, not simultaneously. Only the first advancement can meet [Weyland Consortium: Built to Last](30059)'s trigger condition, so the Corp can gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "success",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The credits are gained when the Runner spends a click to initiate an\naction that does not make a run on the server Sundew is installed in,\nbefore the click is resolved. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "sundew",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Runner plays a run event to initiate a run on the server\nSundew is installed in, the Corp does not gain 2 credits. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "sundew",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "When resolving Sunset, the ice must be rearranged in such a way\nthat the Runner knows which pieces of ice moved where. The Corp\ncannot conceal the rearrangement of the ice. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "sunset",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhen does Supercorridor check the number of credits the players have? If they have a different number of credits at the end of the Runner’s turn, but resolving another ability (such as Citadel Sanctuary) causes them to have the same number of credits, does the Runner gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "Supercorridor checks the number of credits the players have when its ability resolves. Even if the players have a different number of credits when the Runner’s turn ends, it will still trigger, and other abilities can cause Supercorridor to end up paying out.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "supercorridor",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The Corp trashes a card with [Svyatogor Excavator](/en/card/33059) and uses [Ob Superheavy Logistics](/en/card/33057) to install [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080). Can the Corp immediately use [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080)’s ability?",
    "answer": "No, [Rashida Jaheem](/en/card/21080) has the same trigger condition as [Svyatogor Excavator](/en/card/33059), and was not active when that trigger condition was met. Once a reaction window opens to handle pending conditional abilities for a particular trigger condition, new abilities cannot become pending for that trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "svyatogor_excavator",
    "update_date": "2022-11-20",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the Runner gain [click] from Swift before or after making a run?",
    "answer": "Before making a run. Swift's ability meets its trigger condition at step 8.6.4 of playing an event, and resolves in step 8.6.5, before the play abilities of the event itself are resolved.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "swift",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp choose to discard 2 cards if they have 1 or fewer cards in HQ?",
    "answer": "No, in that case they must choose to draw 4 cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "syn_attack",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nHow long does the effect of the second trace on SYNC BRE last?",
    "answer": "*Designer's Note: Technically, as SYNC BRE is written this effect lasts until the end of the game, but it should read: \"**Trace2** - if successful, the Runner accesses 1 fewer card whenever he or she accesses cards **for the remainder of the run**.\"*\n\nIf SYNC BRE’s second trace resolves during a run on Archives, how will the access step be affected?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sync_bre",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhile SYNC Rerouting is active, can the Runner choose to take a tag rather than pay credits and then avoid the tag?",
    "answer": "Yes. SYNC Rerouting does not create a cost to initiate the run, so its effects can be prevented or avoided normally. Furthermore, when an ability directs that a player \"must\" resolve one of two effects, they are required to choose an effect they could potentially resolve, but this potential does not take into account interrupts that could apply after the choice is made.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "sync_rerouting",
    "update_date": "2020-04-15",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes the icebreaker affected by System Seizure hold its strength only during the run when System Seizure is triggered, or during every run that turn?",
    "answer": "The icebreaker only holds its strength until the end of the run System Seizure was triggered.\n\nWhile System Seizure is active, how long does the strength boost of an icebreaker last if the Runner boosts its strength outside of a run?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "system_seizure",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner is playing as [Tāo Salonga](/en/card/30019) and manages to steal an agenda during an encounter, can they use his ability to change the attacked server by moving the currently encountered ice to another server?",
    "answer": "Yes. If a piece of ice moves while the Runner is encountering it, the Runner moves with the ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tao_salonga_telepresence_magician",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner use [Tāo Salonga](/en/card/30019) to swap a piece of ice protecting a server with ice hosted on ​[Awakening Center​](/en/card/03021)?",
    "answer": "Yes, but only if that piece of ice is a rezzed ​**bioroid​**, because [Awakening Center​](/en/card/03021) is only a legal location for ​**bioroid​** ice. If the ice is unrezzed, the Runner cannot demonstrate that the swap is legal. It does not matter if the ice was exposed earlier in the game or is otherwise known by the Runner; it only matters whether the Runner is allowed to see the **​bioroid​** subtype at the time Tāo’s ability resolves. If a rezzed **bioroid​** is swapped this way, the Corp will not be able to pay the cost to force the Runner to encounter it with [Awakening Center​](/en/card/03021)​’s second ability unless another effect derezzes the ​**bioroid​**.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tao_salonga_telepresence_magician",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp cannot gain 10 credits when the Runner plays a current\nthat trashes Targeted Marketing (if the current was named when\nTargeted Marketing was played). Targeted Marketing is trashed\nbefore its ability resolves. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "targeted_marketing",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Corp’s trace strength is 5 or greater, Taurus trashes a piece\nof hardware even if the trace was unsuccessful. This also applies to\n[Gemini](/en/card/06084), [Sagittarius](/en/card/06082), and [Virgo](/en/card/06109). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "taurus",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Runner uses a power counter from Temple of the Liberated Mind in turn step 1.1 (before \"Turn begins\") or step 2.3 (before \"End of turn\"). Can the gained <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> be spent on actions at either of these times?",
    "answer": "The Runner cannot spend clicks on taking actions until \"Take actions\" during step 1.4 of their turn. Before that step of the turn, clicks can still be lost or spent through card effects, such as [Wyldside](/en/card/01016) or Bioroid ice during a run initiated by a card effect. A click gained during step 2.3 after the action phase does not return the runner to the action phase, and it will not be available to spend until the Runner’s next action phase because clicks can only be gained or spent during a player’s own turn. However, it can still be lost by card effects (for example, if the Corp plays [An Offer You Can't Refuse](/en/card/08091) and resolves the first subroutine on an [Enigma](/en/card/01111)).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "temple_of_the_liberated_mind",
    "update_date": "2017-04-11",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 22](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Devil_and_the_Dragon_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner has only 1 <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> left when the trace from Tempus is successful, can they choose to lose <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> instead of taking the brain damage? What if the Runner has no <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span> remaining?",
    "answer": "The Runner must choose an option that can be fully resolved if there is an option that can be fully resolved. Suffering 1 brain damage is always possible, so if the Runner has fewer than 2 clicks remaining, they must choose to suffer the brain damage. Note that once the choice is made, prevent/avoid abilities can still be used to modify the results of that choice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tempus",
    "update_date": "2018-04-06",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nWhat happens if the remote server chosen for Temujin Contract is destroyed?",
    "answer": "Any credits still on Temujin Contract remain on it, but the card does not have any abilities that let you take them.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "temujin_contract",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "temujin_contract",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Tennin Institute cannot place advancement tokens on itself,\nsince ID cards are not installed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "tennin_institute_the_secrets_within",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Tennin Institute can place advancement tokens on Runner\ncards. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "tennin_institute_the_secrets_within",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does [Test Run](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31028) now say \"has not been uninstalled\"?",
    "answer": "The lingering effect to place the program on top of the stack only affects the object installed with this event, not the program as a whole. If the Runner reinstalls that program, for example with [Rejig](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/26029), then the lingering effect does not apply to the newly installed object anymore. This wording was chosen to clarify this interaction; this is not a change in the functionality of the card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "test_run",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp does not have to have a bad publicity in order to play The\nAll-Seeing I. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "the_all_seeing_i",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat is \"using\" a hardware for the purposes of The Back?",
    "answer": "A card is \"used\" if its controller makes a choice to trigger or resolve any optional ability or part of an ability with that card as its source, or if its controller spends or moves counters to pay costs because of an ability from that card. See section 9.1.6 in CR 1.4.\n\nOK, that was a confusing answer. Can we talk about the kinds of \"using\" one at a time?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_back",
    "update_date": "2020-03-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf both players have at least 7 agenda points while The Black File is installed, does the game end in a tie or the Runner winning?",
    "answer": "The Runner wins and the Corp loses.\n\nIf a tournament game ends due to time while The Black File is installed and the Corp has at least 7 agenda points, what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_black_file",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf The Class Act is uninstalled during the turn the Runner installed it, do they still draw 4 cards?",
    "answer": "No.\n\nWhich comes first, The Class Act’s first ability or discarding to hand size?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_class_act",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How does [Verbal Plasticity](en/card/30034) interact with [The Class Act](/en/card/26018)?",
    "answer": "[Verbal Plasticity](en/card/30034)’s ability resolves immediately after the Runner pays the cost to take the basic action to draw 1 card, before the actual draw becomes imminent. [The Class Act](/en/card/26018)’s second ability resolves later, during the interrupt window that occurs while the draw effect is imminent. If both abilities are applicable, the Runner will look at 3 cards and put 1 of those cards on the bottom of their stack, then draw the other 2.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_class_act",
    "update_date": "2022-06-20",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Cleaners adds an additional point of damage to the source of\nthe damage before any damage is prevented. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "the_cleaners",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Cleaners can add unpreventable meat damage if the source is\nalso unpreventable. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "the_cleaners",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Corp must find a piece of ice searched for, if able. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "the_foundry_refining_the_process",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes The Gauntlet count broken pieces of ice that have since been derezzed or trashed?",
    "answer": "The Gauntlet can count derezzed pieces of ice on which all subroutines were broken, but it cannot count trashed pieces of ice because they are no longer protecting HQ.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_gauntlet",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Corp choose to trash the top card of R&D if R&D is empty to keep the Runner from drawing with The Nihilist?",
    "answer": "No. Since “unless” designates that trashing the top card of R&D is a nested cost (rule 1.15.10b), the Corp must trash a card to stop the Runner from drawing. If they do not trash a card, the Runner draws.\n\nIf the Runner’s stack is empty, does The Nihilist force the Corp to trash the top card of R&D?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_nihilist",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Runner play The Noble Path if it is the only card in their grip?",
    "answer": "Yes. There is no stipulation on the card that requires at least one card to be trashed.\n\nDoes The Noble Path prevent the damage dealt by [Dedicated Response Team](/en/card/02118)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_noble_path",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf The Outfit is playing against [Valencia Estevez](/en/card/07030), does the Corp start the game with 1 bad publicity and 8<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "No. The Corp does not \"take\" a bad publicity from Valencia, they simply start the game with the bad publicity.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_outfit_family_owned_and_operated",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp still place advancement counters on cards through card abilities while suffering the effects of The Price of Freedom?",
    "answer": "Yes, only the action of advancing cards is forbidden.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_price_of_freedom",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Runner use The Shadow Net to play a priority event?",
    "answer": "No. The first click would have been spent to use The Shadow Net instead of on playing the priority event.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_shadow_net",
    "update_date": "2017-08-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner cannot use any “when your turn begins” abilities on\ncards that are installed by The Supplier until their next turn. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "the_supplier",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nDoes The Turning Wheel allow the Runner to increase their accesses for both R&D and HQ or only one at a time?",
    "answer": "Each time the Runner uses The Turning Wheel's ability, they must declare the server from which they wish to access additional cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_turning_wheel",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 5](https://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/The_Liberated_Mind_UFAQ) [Damon Stone]\nAfter using The Turning Wheel, when does the Runner access an additional card?",
    "answer": "Each time the Runner accesses cards from HQ or R&D for the remainder of the run.\n\nAfter using The Turning Wheel, can the Runner choose to access a card from R&D when they access a card from HQ and vice versa?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_turning_wheel",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) gain a power counter when spending credits from [Prepaid VoicePAD](/en/card/31038)?",
    "answer": "Yes, recurring credits are hosted credits and are spent from their host card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Does [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) gain a power counter when spending credits from [Overclock](/en/card/30029)?\nNo. Credits can be spent from [Overclock](/en/card/30029), but it is not an installed card.",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) gain a power counter when spending credits from [Ele \"Smoke\" Scovak](/en/card/11066)?",
    "answer": "No. A player’s identity is not installed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) gain a power counter when spending credits from [DJ Fenris](/en/card/22025) hosting [Ele \"Smoke\" Scovak](/en/card/11066)?",
    "answer": "Yes. The recurring credit is hosted on [DJ Fenris](/en/card/22025), which is an installed card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015) is installed and the Runner’s mark is R&D, how many additional cards can they access with [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) when they make a successful run on R&D?",
    "answer": "The Runner resolves a separate instance of [The Twinning](/en/card/33010)’s second ability for each breach: the normal breach of R&D as part of the Success Phase of the run, and the breach of HQ at the end of the run from [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015)’s ability. If [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) has enough hosted power counters, the Runner can spend 2 counters each time and access a total of 4 additional cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you spend hosted credits to use an icebreaker’s paid ability to increase its strength outside of a run, in order to place a power counter on [The Twinning](/en/card/33010)?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner spends credits hosted on [Paladin Poemu](/en/card/26073) to install [The Twinning](/en/card/33010), does the Runner place a power counter on [The Twinning](/en/card/33010)?",
    "answer": "No. [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) is not yet active when you are paying its install cost.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "the_twinning",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner cannot jack out before encountering the ice again. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "the_twins",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Runner uses Inversificator to swap Thimblerig in for another piece of ice, can the Corp then swap Thimblerig away with another piece of ice?",
    "answer": "No. Thimblerig was not the ice installed in the position the Runner is passing at the time that the pass occurred.\n\nIf the Runner passes Thimblerig, then Corp swaps it with a [Kakugo](/en/card/12013), does the Runner suffer 1 net damage?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "thimblerig",
    "update_date": "2020-06-18",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [NISEI Rules Team Update]\nThe Runner has [Citadel Sanctuary](/en/card/11070), Thunder Art Gallery, and [Autoscripter](/en/card/06076) installed. At the end of the Runner’s turn, they use Citadel Sanctuary to remove a tag, triggering Thunder Art Gallery. Does the Runner gain a click from Autoscripter if they install a program with the Gallery?",
    "answer": "Yes. But, players cannot spend clicks outside of the Action Phase and any of the Runner's unspent clicks are lost during the discard phase (5.7.2c).\n\nThe Runner has [Forger](/en/card/08065) and Thunder Art Gallery installed when they access a [Snare!](/en/card/20098). If they avoid the tag with Forger and install a [Sports Hopper](/en/card/10064) with the Gallery, can they use the Sports Hopper to draw more cards to survive the incoming net damage? Can the Runner install and use [Bio-Modeled Network](/en/card/12006) to prevent the incoming net damage?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "thunder_art_gallery",
    "update_date": "2022-06-09",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nIf Tithonium is already hosting a [Pawn](/en/card/04002) when it is rezzed, what happens to the Pawn?",
    "answer": "The Pawn is immediately and unpreventably trashed because Tithonium cannot host it.\n\nCan the Corp use [Oversight AI](/en/card/02079) to rez Tithonium? If so, does the Corp still install Oversight AI onto Tithonium?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tithonium",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "TMI can be rezzed multiple times while the Runner approaches\nit. Timing structure of a run 2.3 is a window that allows the\napproached piece of ice to be rezzed. There is no limit to the number\nof times a Corp can rez an approached piece of ice if it is derezzed\nduring this window. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "tmi",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Runner cannot pay 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when encountering [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066)?",
    "answer": "If the Runner cannot pay 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> when encountering [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066), then the run ends without the Runner paying any credits.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tollbooth",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner choose not to pay 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> and let the run end when encountering [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066)?",
    "answer": "No, the encounter ability from [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066) says that the Runner must pay 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> if they are able.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tollbooth",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Inside Job](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31018) and bypasses [Funhouse](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30054) or [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066), do the non-subroutine abilities on those cards resolve?",
    "answer": "No. An ability that meets its trigger condition due to an encounter beginning can only resolve if the encounter is still taking place. [Inside Job](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31018)’s bypass ability meets its trigger condition at the same time as [Funhouse](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/30054) or [Tollbooth](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/31066)’s ability, and as it’s the Runner’s turn, they will resolve the ability they control first. Bypassing a piece of ice immediately ends the encounter, stopping the Corp from resolving their ability before they can tag the Runner or charge a toll.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tollbooth",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Top Hat allow the Runner to see the top cards of R&D before choosing which to access?",
    "answer": "No.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "top_hat",
    "update_date": "2017-04-14",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The first net damage can be prevented/avoided before Tori Hanzō’s\nreplacement ability resolves. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "tori_hanzo",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the first instance of net damage is prevented by another effect or\nreplaced with Tori Hanzō’s own effect, Tori Hanzō cannot trigger for\nthe remainder of the run. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "tori_hanzo",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The card that is swapped with Toshiyuki Sakai is installed. This halts\nthe resolution of the accessing step, taking the Runner back to the\nbeginning of accessing the newly installed card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "toshiyuki_sakai",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes Tranquility Home Grid's \"Remote server only.\" restriction apply even while it is unrezzed?",
    "answer": "Yes. It cannot even be installed into the root of a central server.\n\nCan Tranquility Home Grid be swapped to a central server?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tranquility_home_grid",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens to [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) after it derezzes its host ice?",
    "answer": "[Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) remains installed and hosted on the derezzed ice and keeps its virus counters. If that ice is later rezzed again, [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) could potentially derez it again.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tranquilizer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) gets to 3 virus counters in the middle of the turn, does the ice derez?",
    "answer": "No. [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) can only derez ice when its ability resolves: when it is installed and when the Runner’s turn begins.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tranquilizer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose the Runner has [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) and [Hivemind](/en/card/07042) installed, with 1 virus counter on [Hivemind](/en/card/07042). If they then install [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017), is the host ice derezzed immediately? Or does it wait for the next check at the beginning of the Runner's next turn?",
    "answer": "By managing their abilities carefully, the Runner can choose whether to derez the ice right away or not. [Hivemind](/en/card/07042)’s second ability is a static ability, so it always applies as soon as [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) is installed. But the conditional abilities on [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) and [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) meet their trigger conditions at the same time, so the Runner can choose the order to resolve them. If they resolve [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) first, it will only have 2 hosted virus counters (including the one shared from [Hivemind](/en/card/07042)) at the time that the number of counters is checked. If they resolve [Cookbook](/en/card/30009) first, then by the time [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) resolves, it will have 3 hosted virus counters and will derez the ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tranquilizer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the Corp rezzes ice that is hosting a [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) with 3 virus counters?",
    "answer": "The ice remains rezzed. If [Tranquilizer](/en/card/30017) still has 3 or more virus counters at the start of the Runner’s turn, then it will become derezzed again.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tranquilizer",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp install Transparency Initiative on an already faceup installed **public** agenda?",
    "answer": "No. If no agenda is turned faceup, then Transparency Initiative can't find \"that agenda\" to install itself as a hosted condition counter.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "transparency_initiative",
    "update_date": "2017-07-21",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens at the time a run is supposed to become successful if the run \"cannot be declared successful\"?",
    "answer": "Step 6.9.5e of the run will do nothing, and abilities that look for a successful run will never see this run. The run proceeds through the remaining steps of the Approach Server Phase and the Run Ends Phase normally, including the Runner accessing cards from the attacked server. The run will not be declared unsuccessful either.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "transport_monopoly",
    "update_date": "2020-04-16",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If an [Asteroid Belt](/en/card/07012) has 4 hosted advancement counters, how much does it cost to rez it during a run made with [Tread Lightly](/en/card/30012)?",
    "answer": "It would cost 0<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>. To determine what a cost is when effects are modifying its value, start with the default value for that cost ([Asteroid Belt](/en/card/07012)’s printed rez cost is 9<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>), apply each effect that increases the cost ([Tread Lightly](/en/card/30012) adds 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>), and then apply each effect that lowers the cost ([Asteroid Belt](/en/card/07012)’s ability subtracts 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> for each hosted advancement counter).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tread_lightly",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Trick of Light can only be used to move advancement tokens from\nan installed card to another installed card. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "trick_of_light",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nCan the Runner avoid the tag from Trickster Taka’s last ability?",
    "answer": "Yes. Just like with avoiding the tag from Data Raven, the ability only requires the Runner to make a choice. Once the choice is made, whether or not the effect is prevented does not undo or invalidate the choice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "trickster_taka",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ice chosen for [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) is derezzed, what happens?",
    "answer": "The choice made when [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) was rezzed is still maintained, because the ice is still the same object, and [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) is still active. If the Corp rezzes that ice again, Trieste’s ability will still apply.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "trieste_model_bioroids",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) is derezzed, what happens?",
    "answer": "The effect prohibiting Runner card abilities from breaking subroutines ends immediately, and the lingering effect remembering which ice was chosen expires. If the Corp rezzes [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) again, they will make a new choice of a rezzed piece of bioroid ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "trieste_model_bioroids",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Is the ability on [Quetzal: Free Spirit](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06052) affected by [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034)?",
    "answer": "Yes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "trieste_model_bioroids",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ice chosen with [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) loses the **bioroid** subtype, what happens?",
    "answer": "That ice is still affected by the ability. The bioroid subtype is only required at the time [Trieste Model Bioroids](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33034) is rezzed and the choice of ice is made.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "trieste_model_bioroids",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Agendas switched with Turntable keep any hosted counters or cards\non them, but their text is not active. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "turntable",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat happens if Týr is trashed after increasing the Corp's allotted [click]?",
    "answer": "The Corp still gets the extra allotted [click] next turn.\n\nWhen exactly does Týr's ability apply? If the Corp uses Tyr's Hand to prevent a subroutine from being broken after a click is spent, do they still get the extra allotted [click] next turn? What if the Runner breaks the last subroutine using Týr's ability and then immediately uses Hippo to trash it (so that Týr is not active for a conditional ability to resolve)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "tyr",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Unity](/en/card/30026)'s boost ability give +1 strength to each installed icebreaker?",
    "answer": "No, [Unity](/en/card/30026)'s boost ability increases the strength of [Unity](/en/card/30026) by an amount equal to the number of installed icebreakers.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "unity",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nIf the Runner only has 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> after losing the Psi game on Upayoga, do they lose that credit?",
    "answer": "Yes. Upayoga’s subroutine lacks an “if able” clause, so as much of the effect as can be resolved must resolve.\n\nIf the Runner has no credits in their credit pool after losing the Psi game on Upayoga, can they be forced to lose credits on other cards, such as [Ghost Runner](/en/card/06040) or [Net Celebrity](/en/card/06038)?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "upayoga",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Corp advance [Urtica Cipher](/en/card/30044) if it’s unrezzed?",
    "answer": "Yes. Abilities that allow the Corp to advance a card are active even if the card is unrezzed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "urtica_cipher",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Urtica Cipher](/en/card/30044) do damage even if it has no advancement counters on it?",
    "answer": "Yes, as long as it is installed. The 2 damage indicated in the card text is not contingent on adding more damage for advancement counters.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "urtica_cipher",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Urtica Cipher](/en/card/30044) do its damage all at once, or in increments?",
    "answer": "[Urtica Cipher](/en/card/30044)’s ability causes a single occurrence of damage, whether or not [Urtica Cipher](/en/card/30044) is advanced.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "urtica_cipher",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner returns [Utopia Shard](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06100) to their grip with [Steve Cambridge](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/13001), can they then install [Utopia Shard](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06100)?",
    "answer": "No. In order for [Utopia Shard](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/06100) to install itself with its ability, it must already be in the Runner’s grip at the time the ability would meet its trigger condition.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "utopia_shard",
    "update_date": "2022-04-24",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Runner encounters a [Tyrant](/en/card/02078) with a single advancement token on it and breaks the subroutine with Vamadeva. If the Corp then uses [Firmware Updates](/en/card/07004) to add another advancement token to Tyrant, can the Runner break the new subroutine with Vamadeva?",
    "answer": "No. Broken subroutines still exist on the ice.\n\nCan the Runner use Vamadeva to swap in another copy of Vamadeva from the grip?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "vamadeva",
    "update_date": "2022-01-04",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nDoes the restriction \"You cannot use this ability to install a card in this server.\" apply to Vaporframe Fabricator's click ability?",
    "answer": "No, it only applies to the install from the second ability.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "vaporframe_fabricator",
    "update_date": "2020-04-10",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How does [Verbal Plasticity](/en/card/30034) interact with [The Class Act](/en/card/26018)?",
    "answer": "[Verbal Plasticity](/en/card/30034)’s ability resolves immediately after the Runner pays the cost to take the basic action to draw 1 card, before the actual draw becomes imminent. [The Class Act](/en/card/26018)’s second ability resolves later, during the interrupt window that occurs while the draw effect is imminent. If both abilities are applicable, the Runner will draw 3 cards and put 1 of those cards on the bottom of their stack.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "verbal_plasticity",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nHow does \"After you resolve this operation, end your action phase.\" on terminal operations like Violet Level Clearance work?",
    "answer": "Immediately after the operation resolves and is trashed from playing it, \"after you resolve this operation\" triggers meet their trigger condition. Ending the action phase then advances the game to the discard phase. This skips the paid ability window that would normally follow the end of an action, ceases the resolution of any other pending abilities or effects, and invalidates any conditional abilities. If the operation was played as part of a card ability, any remaining effects from that card ability immediately stop resolving as well.\n\nIf the Corp plays Violet Level Clearance as the first operation for [Subcontract](/en/card/10113), what happens?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "violet_level_clearance",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf the Corp has a rezzed [Genetics Pavilion](/en/card/08113) when they score a Viral Weaponization, does the Runer draw 2 or 3 cards if [I've Had Worse](/en/card/07032) is trashed?",
    "answer": "The Runner will draw the full 3 cards. Viral Weaponization triggers at step 3.4 of the Corp's discard phase, which is still part of the Corp's turn.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "viral_weaponization",
    "update_date": "2018-05-07",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "If the Corp’s trace strength is 5 or greater, Virgo gives the Runner 1 tag even if the trace was unsuccessful. [Official FAQ, listed under Taurus' ruling]",
    "card_codename": "virgo",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Runner’s mark stay if all mark cards leave play, or does it leave and return when a new mark card comes into play?",
    "answer": "When you identify your mark, that server becomes your mark for the turn, even if the card that instructed you to identify your mark leaves play. If an event instructs you to identify your mark, that server continues to be your mark for the remainder of the turn after that event resolves.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner does not have a mark, and they install a card that says “When your turn begins, identify your mark.”, do they get a mark for the current turn?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner only identifies a mark when an ability instructs them to.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner has multiple “mark” cards, how do they identify their mark?",
    "answer": "The first time each turn the Runner resolves an instruction to identify their mark, they will randomly choose a central server. That server becomes their mark for the entire turn. Resolving another instruction to identify their mark will have no effect.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If R&D is identified as the Runner's mark, and they run R&D with [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028), can the Runner access 1 additional card in HQ when they breach it with [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015)’s ability?",
    "answer": "No. When you make a run on R&D with [Jailbreak](/en/card/30028) and breach HQ afterwards due to [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015), HQ is not the attacked server. You will only access an additional card in R&D.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does breaching HQ with [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015) after breaching a non-HQ mark allow [Zahya Sadeghi: Versatile Smuggler](/en/card/30010) to gain credits from the additional breach?",
    "answer": "No. The additional breach occurs after the run ends.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the \"otherwise\" in [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015)’s ability mean it triggers if the run is unsuccessful?",
    "answer": "No. “Otherwise” in [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015)’s ability means “If that server is not HQ”.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner over-install [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015) and trigger the “first time you make a successful run on your mark” ability a second time?",
    "answer": "No. The next successful run on the Runner’s mark is not the first run, even if different cards are installed.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "How does [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015) interact with [Security Testing](/en/card/31024) if the Runner’s mark is not HQ?",
    "answer": "If the same server was identified as the Runner’s mark and chosen with [Security Testing](/en/card/31024), the Runner will gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> instead of breaching that server. They will then breach HQ after the run ends.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose the Corp has a copy of [Ganked!](/en/card/26119) in HQ. What happens if an “End the run.” subroutine resolves during a breach made with [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015)?",
    "answer": "Since this breach is not happening during a run, an “End the run.” instruction ends the forced encounter that was in progress, but otherwise does not affect the breach. If the Runner still has cards to access, they continue doing so.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015) is installed and the Runner’s mark is R&D, how many additional cards can they access with [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) when they make a successful run on R&D?",
    "answer": "The Runner resolves a separate instance of [The Twinning](/en/card/33010)’s second ability for each breach: the normal breach of R&D as part of the Success Phase of the run, and the breach of HQ at the end of the run from [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015)’s ability. If [The Twinning](/en/card/33010) has enough hosted power counters, the Runner can spend 2 counters each time and access a total of 4 additional cards.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015) work with [Docklands Pass](/en/card/30013)?",
    "answer": "Yes. If the Runner has not previously breached HQ this turn, they will access 1 additional card during the breach from [Virtuoso](/en/card/33015).",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "virtuoso",
    "update_date": "2022-09-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nThe Runner has a copy of [Fan Site](/en/card/08085) in their score area. Can the Corp play Voter Intimidation?",
    "answer": "Yes. Cards that move to a zone as agendas are considered to be agendas for all purposes.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "voter_intimidation",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner play [VRcation](/en/card/30021) if they only have 1 click left?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner only needs to spend the 1 click required for the basic action to play an event. The second sentence on [VRcation](/en/card/30021) is part of its effect, not a cost to play the card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "vrcation",
    "update_date": "2021-10-10",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nWhen resolving the trace on Waiver, by how much does the Corp’s trace strength need to exceed the Runner’s link strength in order to trash cards with cost X, such as [Angel Arena](/en/card/06080) and [Bribery](/en/card/06118)?",
    "answer": "The Corp’s trace strength only needs to exceed the Runner’s link strength by 1 to be considered successful and trash cards with cost X. A printed cost of X is considered to be 0 when referenced outside of paying that cost to play/install the card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "waiver",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use Wake Up Call to trash [Jarogniew Mercs](/en/card/12062) while other resources are installed?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Runner is the player specified to trash the chosen card, so Jarogniew Mercs's second ability does not apply.\n\nCan the Corp play Wake Up Call if the Runner does not have an installed hardware or non-virtual resource, and if so is the Runner forced to suffer the meat damage?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "wake_up_call",
    "update_date": "2017-12-29",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](https://nisei.net) [Uprising Release Notes](https://nisei.net/files/Uprising_Release_Notes.pdf) [NISEI Rules Team]\nIf the Corp is able to resolve 3 choices on Wall to Wall, do they have to choose all 3 before resolving them? Do they have to resolve them in the order they appear on the card?",
    "answer": "No and no. The Corp chooses the next instruction to resolve after the previous one is finished resolving. They do not have to choose instructions that are written after those they have already chosen.\n\nCan the Corp resolve the same instruction on Wall to Wall more than once on the same turn?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "wall_to_wall",
    "update_date": "2020-04-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIn what order does a piece of ice gain subroutines while hosting [Wetwork Refit](/en/card/11071) with Warden Fatuma active?",
    "answer": "The subroutines are gained in \"timestamp order\". Whichever card became active first gives its subroutine first, then the other card gives its subroutine second. Thus, the most recently active card's subroutine will be the first subroutine, followed by the subroutine from the older card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "warden_fatuma",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 23](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Whispers_in_Nalubaale_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nIf [Loki](/en/card/12069) copies the subroutines from another bioroid while Warden Fatuma is rezzed, how many \"<span class=\"icon icon-subroutine\"></span> The Runner loses <span class=\"icon icon-click\"></span>, if able.\" subroutines does Loki have?",
    "answer": "Loki will have two copies of the subroutine: one from Warden Fatuma, and one copied from the other bioroid ice.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "warden_fatuma",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes a Warroid Tracker installed in the root of R&D trigger when the Runner uses [Keyhole](/en/card/04061) to trash a card?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nIf Warroid Tracker and [Adonis Campaign](/en/card/01056) are installed in the same server and the Runner makes a run and trashes both cards while accessing them, how many times does Warroid Tracker trigger?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "warroid_tracker",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp uses a card ability to rez [Wave](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33037) at a time other than while the Runner is approaching it, will they be able to use its ability?",
    "answer": "Yes. The Corp can use the ability as long as there is a run in progress and [Wave](https://netrunnerdb.com/en/card/33037) is protecting the attacked server.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "wave",
    "update_date": "2022-10-22",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nDoes Builder of Nations trigger when a piece of ice with advancement tokens on it is trashed?",
    "answer": "Yes. When an encountered piece of ice is uninstalled, the encounter immediately ends.\n\nDoes Builder of Nations trigger for a piece of ice without any advancement tokens on it that is protecting a server in which [Satellite Grid](/en/card/07023) is installed and rezzed?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "weyland_consortium_builder_of_nations",
    "update_date": "2017-04-12",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “if it had no advancement counters” mean?",
    "answer": "Usually, it simply refers to the first time you advance a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "weyland_consortium_built_to_last",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp is playing [Weyland Consortium: Built to Last](/en/card/30059) and uses [Seamless Launch](/en/card/30040) to place 2 advancement counters at the same time, how many credits do they gain?",
    "answer": "None. Placing or moving advancement counters directly does not count as advancing a card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "weyland_consortium_built_to_last",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Corp is playing [Weyland Consortium: Built to Last](/en/card/30059) and uses [Success](/en/card/12078) to advance a card multiple times at once, how many credits do they gain?",
    "answer": "Success advances its target multiple times in sequence, not simultaneously. Only the first advancement can meet [Weyland Consortium: Built to Last](/en/card/30059)'s trigger condition, so the Corp can gain 2<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "weyland_consortium_built_to_last",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) UFAQ [Michael Boggs]\nCan the Corp use the ability on Whampoa Reclamation to add the card used to pay for the ability to the bottom of R&D?",
    "answer": "Yes.\n\nCan the Corp use Whampoa Reclamation while there are no cards in Archives?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "whampoa_reclamation",
    "update_date": "2017-06-23",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[NISEI](http://nisei.net) [Downfall Release Notes](http://nisei.net/products/Downfall/DFReleaseNotes#QandAforDownfall) [NISEI Rules Team]\nWhat does Whistleblower do? Won’t the Runner steal the agenda anyway?",
    "answer": "Whistleblower skips the usual sequence of steps for accessing a card, and lets the Runner steal it before any “when accessed” abilities resolve. Once the agenda is stolen, it is no longer being accessed, which stops other “when accessed” abilities from resolving. It also lets the Runner ignore additional costs to steal agendas like the one imposed by Red Herrings or the one on Obokata Protocol.\n\nSo if the Runner names Fetal AI with Whistleblower and accesses a Fetal AI, do they still suffer the net damage?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "whistleblower",
    "update_date": "2019-04-27",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Does [Whitespace](/en/card/30074) check for the Runner having 6<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> or less before or after the Runner loses 3<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "After. Resolve each subroutine 1 at a time, in the order they appear on the card.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "whitespace",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the Runner lose credits hosted on [Overclock](/en/card/30029) or [Penumbral Toolkit](/en/card/26081) for the first subroutine on [Whitespace](/en/card/30074)?",
    "answer": "No. Those credits are only available to be spent. “Losing” credits always drains the Runner’s credit pool.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "whitespace",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Do credits hosted on cards like [Overclock](/en/card/30029) and [Penumbral Toolkit](/en/card/26081) count toward whether the Runner has more than 6<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span>?",
    "answer": "No. The Runner only “has” credits in their credit pool. The abilities on these cards only allow players to spend their hosted credits.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "whitespace",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner plays [Wildcat Strike](/en/card/30002) with fewer than 4 cards left in their stack, can the Corp choose the draw option? What if the Runner cannot draw cards due to some other effect?",
    "answer": "The Corp can choose either option regardless of the Runner’s stack or abilities affecting the Runner’s ability to draw cards. Making the choice for [Wildcat Strike](/en/card/30002) is not taking an action or using an ability, so it does not need to have the potential to change the game state.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "wildcat_strike",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "Worlds Plaza may be accessed and trashed, thereby trashing all of its\nhosted cards, before the cards hosted on it are accessed. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "worlds_plaza",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The subroutine that resolves is not considered to be on Wormhole\n(e.g. when the Corp uses Wormhole with cards like [Data Raven](/en/card/01088) or\n[Viktor 2.0](/en/card/03019), the power counters are placed on those cards and not\nWormhole). [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "wormhole",
    "update_date": "2017-04-09",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "wyldside",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "The Runner can only use Wyrm to lower the strength of a currently\nencountered piece of ice, and only if Wyrm is of equal or higher\nstrength than that ice. [Official FAQ]",
    "card_codename": "wyrm",
    "update_date": "2017-04-08",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "text": "NAPD Most Wanted List - Level 1: Each copy of this card costs 1 universal influence, which is separate & in addition to the normal printed influence, and counts against all Identities influence limits, even those in the same faction. [MWL v1.2]",
    "card_codename": "yog_0",
    "update_date": "2017-04-28",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does [Zahya Sadeghi](/en/card/30010) say “for each time you accessed a card” instead of “for each card you accessed”?",
    "answer": "Although the Runner is not usually allowed to access any given card more than once during a single breach, some cards, such as [Bacterial Programming](/en/card/21033), have abilities that can move cards around in the middle of a breach, potentially resulting in the Runner having to access 1 or more cards for a second time. *Zahya*’s wording emphasizes that these repeat accesses still count toward the number of credits the Runner can gain.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "zahya_sadeghi_versatile_smuggler",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Runner runs HQ or R&D, accesses a card during the run due to [Otoroshi](/en/card/22038), and then the run ends unsuccessfully, can they still claim 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> from [Zahya Sadeghi](/en/card/30010)'s ability?",
    "answer": "Yes, the card accessed would still count. *Zahya*’s ability does not require a successful run.",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "zahya_sadeghi_versatile_smuggler",
    "update_date": "2021-10-11",
    "nsg_verified": true
  },
  {
    "question": "####UFAQ [Damon Stone]\nCan the Corp use [Worlds Plaza](/en/card/08116) to install Zealous Judge if the runner is not tagged?",
    "answer": "No. Worlds Plaza uses the phrase “if able”, which applies to the entire effect of installing and rezzing a card. Since Zealous Judge cannot be rezzed in this circumstance, Worlds Plaza’s ability cannot be used to install it.\n\nThe Corp scores [License Acquisition](/en/card/06085) and the Runner is not tagged. Can the Corp install Zealous Judge with Licence Acquisition’s ability?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "zealous_judge",
    "update_date": "2017-05-02",
    "nsg_verified": false
  },
  {
    "question": "####[ANCUR](https://twitter.com/anr_ruleswiki) [UFAQ 24](http://ancur.wikia.com/wiki/Reign_and_Reverie_UFAQ) [Michael Boggs]\nCan the damage from Zer0 be prevented?",
    "answer": "The Runner can prevent the damage from Zer0, but they will not gain 1<span class=\"icon icon-credit\"></span> or draw 2 cards as the cost will not have fully been paid.\n\nIf the Runner prevents the damage from Zer0, can they attempt to use the ability again?",
    "text": "",
    "card_codename": "zer0",
    "update_date": "2018-08-01",
    "nsg_verified": false
  }
]